<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA3099</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Harvey A. Bordner papers, <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1901/1955" era="ce">1901-1955</date> <num>C90</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Papers at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Ryan K. Lee</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2006</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:57:11 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 23, 2006</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>March 30, 2006</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>May 6, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>April 16, 2018</date><item>Updated folder list and extent and fixed broken IUCAT links. MRM</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Harvey A. Bordner papers</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Bordner, Harvey Albert, 1872-1938.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C90</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3.1 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">5 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1901/1955" type="inclusive">1901-1955</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1936" type="bulk">1902-1936</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_84a88df598b1799f429288ba5766b424">Harvey A. Bordner was an educator and public school administrator in the Philippines, 1902-1936. Bordner received his bachelor's in chemistry at Indiana University in 1896, served as a laboratory assistant in the department from 1894-1900, and instructor from 1900-1901. Collection consists of Bordner's articles and essays about education in the Philippines; books and pamphlets about the Philippines in general and about its educational system; school yearbooks and some student work; about 400 black and white photographs of the Philippines; Bordner's correspondence to relatives in the United States; certificates of award or appointment give to Bordner; and Indiana University Alumni Office files containing biographical information and some correspondence from Bordner.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4ebbbb204c29cab4ddb9cad7739ee9fc">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ca908d32eb94671d774846af2a7e4f1c">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b67b9e4fc36e73aa01d89d1bd5b8d5e0">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Harvey Bordner was born in Mt. Aetna, Pennsylvannia, 9 April 1872, the son of Tilon J. and Rebecca Schreffler Bordner. He graduated from Indiana University in 1896 with an AB in Chemistry. He worked as a laboratory assistant in the Chemistry Department from 1894 1900 and as an instructor in Chemistry from 1900 1901.</p><p> In January 1902, Bordner married Maude Ethel Martin, and in February 1902 the couple went to the Philippines where Bordner had accepted a job as an administrator at the Manila High School. He later served as an administrator at the Philippine Normal School. His wife Maude taught English at both of these schools. Together the Bordners spent the next 34 years in the Philippines as public school teachers.</p><p> Harvey was also a member of the Rotary Club at Manila and a 32nd degree Mason. In Manila he worked with the Y.M.C.A. and the Boy's Club. Harvey spent most of his career as a school administrator, retiring as superintendent of the Manila schools in 1936 due to ill health. He died in Indianapolis in 1938.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_cc2b3a9638bf9876b387804006330ef3">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Organized into ten series: Correspondence; Articles and reports; Speeches; General Philippines infromation; Photographs; Clippings; Diary; Yearbooks; Certificates and awards; and Memorial materials.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_696b98d3d6a71dfc318eee3fe9421ff9">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The IU gift file indicates that this collection was received in 1964 from Mrs. Harvey Bordner. Since the acknowledgment address was "Mr. J. B. Howe Martin, 3139 Sharon Avenue, Indianapolis" the collection was probably given to IU after her death. The material received from the Bordner family has been augmented with some material from files already in the IU Archives.</p><p> The Harvey Bordner papers span 1901-1955 although the bulk of the material dates between 1902 and 1936. The collection relates primarily to Bordner's life and career in the Philippines and is organized into ten series: Correspondence; Articles and reports; Speeches; General Philippines information; Photographs; Clippings; Diary; Yearbooks; Certificates and awards; and Memorial materials.</p><p> The Correspondence series spans 1902-1938 and is further organized into two subseries, Personal, 1902-1918, and Professional, 1910-1938. Harvey Bordner's Personal correspondence includes letters to his brother and sister-in-law, Mr. and Mrs. Tilon D. Bordner, parents, Mr. and Mrs. Tilon J. Bordner, and other family members which Harvey called "home folks," written during his time in the Philippines. The Professional correspondence includes letters written by both Harvey and Maude. There is quite a bit of correspondence with the Indiana University Alumni Office, mostly in regards to the Alumni newsletter. There are also letters between the Bordners and other School administrators in the Philippines. A few of the letters are correspondence with American politicians, such as Louis Ludlow and Frank Crone of Virginia. The letters that date after Harvey's death are by Maude and others concerning Harvey.</p><p> The Articles and reports series, 1902-1940, consists of Bordner's reports and published articles, most of which were written by Harvey while he was in the Philippines. There are reports on traveling through the Pacific, the Philippine Islands, the Philippine Normal School, and other education-related topics. There is also an article on the role of the church in daily life after the First World War and one on the meaning of the American Flag.</p><p> The Speeches series, 1902-1935, consists primarily of welcome and graduation addresses, most likely for the students of the Philippine Normal School. Other speeches include addresses to teachers and other school administrators. Topics featured are discipline, teaching techniques, and suggested courses of study for high schools.</p><p> The General Philippines information series spans 1904-1940 and is further organized into four subseries: Books, 1916-1927; Education, 1904-1913; Souvenirs, 1904-1909; and Travel and history, 1905-1940. The subseries are arranged chronologically. The series includes books on the Philippine Islands' history, geography, and culture; education publications; travel pamphlets; and American publications on the Philippines. The Education sub-series includes student artwork and a diary kept by a student as an English assignment. The Souvenirs sub-series includes post cards and a cruise ship dinner menu.</p><p> The Clippings series, 1901-1955, includes articles from Philippine and American newspapers. Articles are mostly about the Bordner's teaching influence in the Philippines.</p><p> The Diary dates to 1914-1915 and appears to have been written by Maude's father, P.B. Martin, as his name is written on the front of the volume. It details a trip taken from San Francisco with Maude. The weather during the voyage is described in great detail, as in the travel schedule, including arrival and departure times and the names of the ships taken on the journey. The rest of the diary is a day-to-day record of the visit to the Philippines. There is a small account of a visit to a Catholic Church that does not recognize the authority of the Pope. The scenery of the islands is a topic of interest in the diary. There are notes about packages arriving from America as well as visits with other Americans on the islands. In the back of the diary is a brief paragraph written by Maude that gives an account of her family history in Kentucky and Virginia. The loose papers tucked into the diary include lists of groceries and a sample of Asian language characters.</p><p> The Yearbooks series, 1916-1921, consists of books from two schools where the Bordners worked while in the Philippines. The <title render="doublequote">Souvenir</title> (1921) is the yearbook of the Manila High School and was produced during the time Harvey served as the Superintendent of the Manila City Schools. <title render="doublequote">The Torch</title> (1917-1919) is the yearbook of the Philippine Normal School where Harvey served as superintendent.</p><p> The Certificates and awards series, 1915-1929, is a set of three official documents given to Bordner from his various places of study and employment.</p><p> The Memorial materials, 1936, consist of Harvey's obituary and letters of consolation to Maude. Related to this series is a scrapbook called "Necrological Services Held in Memory of Harvey A. Bordner." The service was held at the Philippine Normal School. The book includes photographs of the service, newspaper clippings, a speech, and letters. It is housed with the photographs of this collection because of the large number of photographs in the scrapbook. But due to the nature of the book – a memorial service for Bordner – it should be described in the memorial materials.</p><p> The Photographs span 1902-1936 and are a very interesting group of about 400 mostly black &amp; white prints taken in the Philippines. There are also some post cards and photos clipped from publications. These photos include images of the Bordners' home, family, schools in the Philippines, such as Manila High School and the Philippine Normal School, school groups, and scenery and sights around the Philippines (including a Russian ship damaged in the Russo Japanese war). One album contains manuscript testimonials written on the occasion of Bordner's retirement in 1936. There are also scrapbooks that include photos of Manila, Bordner family and friend photos, scenes from the Philippine Normal School, and other schools. Most of photos are pasted onto album pages. There is an inventory of the photos in the Archives processing file for this collection. The photos are stored with the archives photograph collection. Consult staff for details.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_c2678a48f338bfda7a99dbf78b5f1c1d">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Dunn family legal documents which appear to have been boxed with these papers in error.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_77b5c4b60693d5d87f37a8d1e476c5f1">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accessions 0678, 0968, and 7016.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c232a24018f6653efabcd199a956a50e">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_960b083db753a7a180be97b01b73382c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Harvey A. Bordner papers, Collection C90, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2ca5e7e2dc1d49f10cd57046c4c8f622">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Bill Baus; reprocessed by Alex Kelner.</p><p> Completed in <date calendar="gregorian" normal="2004" era="ce">2004</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Photographs.</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">School yearbooks.</genreform>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education --Philippines.</subject>
    <geogname source="aacr2">Philippines --Description and travel --Photographs.</geogname>
    <geogname source="aacr2">Philippines --History.</geogname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Bordner, Harvey Albert, 1872-1938 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Bordner, Harvey Albert, 1872-1938 --Correspondence.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1938" type="inclusive">1902-1938</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00002" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Personal</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1918" type="inclusive">1902-1918</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mr. and Mrs. Tilon D. Bordner</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1903/1912" type="inclusive">1903-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e19a99c06a83a07cc98e17b346f0975" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_041ccc34b79deb72bb7ad408a19d5d10"><head>General</head><p>(brother and sister-in-law)</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tilon D. Bordner</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1918" type="inclusive">1902-1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b2565b7232628d0ba1809326ba2d571" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_40929c869362bbb3cf9d73da56df25c9"><head>General</head><p>(brother)</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mr. and Mrs. Tilon J. Bordner</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1914/1914">1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_111cbda43a309b434ec59619a0c3fc7f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_fc4ca19e5b5d442ed24c42f4e4f0db10"><head>General</head><p>(parents)</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Home folks"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1903" type="inclusive">1902-1903</unitdate><container id="aspace_93ca53daba657cb61caaffb4d41e8e74" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00007" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Professional</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1910/1938" type="inclusive">1910-1938</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alumni Office, Indiana University</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1910/1936" type="inclusive">1910-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_7217f6545f007fd80dbfc5a8b8318a2e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle>W.W. Marquardt, Director of Education</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc6c1c60f5fbf30ffc20b1173961856a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.C. Scott, Division Superintendent of Schools, Iloilo, Iloilo, Philippine Islands</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_b837bb0a2286bd5116b1df6d44b9ef95" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00011" level="file"><did><unittitle>Frank L. Crone, Representative for Virginia</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1c9b49ebb58ca416f32f704c40b5fd9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00012" level="file"><did><unittitle>Edna Scott Gibbon</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec00dd7f9253fd378eb27882b88fa281" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00013" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ciriaco DeLeon, Division of City Schools, Manila</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_98ae4bc1b9ca92c077fde5bdeb6dccef" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00014" level="file"><did><unittitle>Louis Ludlow, House of Representatives</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_18d1311f8437064a23985b7b872635b1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00015" level="file"><did><unittitle>Walter B. Foley</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d01520f2499e0a691204601bfc1212c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00016" level="file"><did><unittitle>Prudencio Langcauon, Superintendent of City Schools, Manila</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_b01586280be3cfbd9a344719d5108528" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00017" level="series"><did><unittitle>Articles and reports</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1940" type="inclusive">1902-1940</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00018" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">C.G. Cutter 'Negros' Inspection Trip</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_45c3896e6b595deb743a00083f95caae" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00019" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Manila to Apparri and Return</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1931-03-31/1931-04-04" type="inclusive">March 31 – April 4, 1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c625799b55590b7176fd03391d2236c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00020" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Philippine Islands</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1902-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_20dbfa526f54364cd91eb876e676b89e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00021" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Philippine Normal School</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1902-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_90f92eb88d603252f3103f7fc18da72c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00022" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Retardation and Elimination</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1902-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_a28e12ea98d3caaa9314eea4c4e5efcd" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00023" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Untitled</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1902-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_477903b049b9201aa4ec990775e96a1c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00024" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Church After the War</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1914/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1914-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_151e0623252d891348f1acd2487907c0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00025" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Manila, The Pearl of the Orient</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">c. 1939-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fb3521eed509c69a1ece3de3a62fb58" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00026" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Symbolism of the National Flag</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1901/1940" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e963317e241a922ba9280a4335285a11" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00027" level="series"><did><unittitle>Speeches</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">1902-1935</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00028" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">A Graduating Address</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1902-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_23b216deb202acd62592ca1c8bcaae70" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00029" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Revision of High School Courses of Study</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1902/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1902-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_aeb3d112ab6ced8618f8ce0558970da9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00030" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Philippine Normal School</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1914-12-13/1914-12-13">December 13, 1914</unitdate><container id="aspace_c10be1c9d180bd97c431475ecc75fd42" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00031" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Pitfalls Young Teachers Must Guard Against</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916-01/1916-01">January 1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_e239ed7d81b59485cb8fcf080ae6c8fc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_6e1c2a42d47500107805a83db656ff06"><head>General</head><p>File also includes "Paper read before the Committee Appointed to Consider the Revision of the High School Courses of Study"</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00032" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Discipline</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916-07/1916-07">July 1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_54a7c1a78955f3aced6b2fd3ba04382a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00033" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Law and the Observance of Law</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916-08-28/1916-08-28">August 28, 1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_94c222a71209d8a38e6909cbd7960c31" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00034" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Vacation Assembly</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1917-04-16/1917-05-18" type="inclusive">April 16 – May 18, 1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_04ee2e4a39696eaa7de68f6bb3cfdb72" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00035" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Is Indiana University a Real University?</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1917/1917">1917</unitdate><container id="aspace_273a8068b4a8f54a295f6b856c21f55e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00036" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Teacher Qualifications Sought by Superintendents</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918-09-30/1918-09-30">September 30, 1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f6e5979ab86231518292b8113043e96" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00037" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Welcome Address to Incoming Students at Philippine Normal School</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1919/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1919-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a0658027ff899057007f927cb193939" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00038" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">To the Graduates of the Philippine Normal School, Suggestions for Commencement Address</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1919/1935" type="inclusive">c. 1919-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_22254be5abd41ddaf53734730531f42f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00039" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">To the Graduating Class at Mary J. Johnson Hospital Training School</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1901/1940" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb6fd15ad75fbdf59a8ecbcb6883a543" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_a8d2f91cff287638e439bf9d31b4ea0a"><head>General</head><p>(location unknown)</p></odd></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00040" level="series"><did><unittitle>General Philippine informations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1904/1940" type="inclusive">1904-1940</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00041" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Books</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916/1916">1916</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00042" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Spell of the Hawaiian Islands and the Philippines</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916/1916">1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c7532e08b097872087f276376aaba28" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00043" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Philippine Folk Dances and Games</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_26f8f0e413c8ac634b908f85719f5ede" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00044" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Education</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1913/1913">1913</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00045" level="file"><did><unittitle>Composition Book and Director's Twelfth Annual Report</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1904/1912" type="inclusive">1904-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_13abcc98ee4eb5ae3ad4333c3b92fcf1" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00046" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Philippine Craftsman</title>, vol. I, nos. 8-9</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1913-02/1913-03" type="inclusive">February-March 1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8314bd2f95617fa4a1b2d5151b6c915" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00070" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Philippine Craftsman</title>, vol. II, nos. 2-6</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1913-08/1913-12" type="inclusive">August-December 1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_a26a23fb1d624029deeb4ad4193516b1" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00047" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Souvenirs</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1904/1909" type="inclusive">1904-1909</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00048" level="file"><did><unittitle>Postcards and cruise ship menu</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1904/1909" type="inclusive">1904-1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_7223db9962e9691f7152a0b51bfc6e92" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00049" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Travel and history</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905/1940" type="inclusive">1905-1940</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00050" level="file"><did><unittitle>Najeeb M. Saleeby<title render="italic"/></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905/1905">1905</unitdate><container id="aspace_aea8e77b446d020fb22cf37a77a0843f" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00051" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Manila Daily Bulletin</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1919/1919">1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a77ec2b09bc70851410481600f3d705" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00052" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Mineral Resources of the Philippine Islands for the Years 1917 and 1918</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1920/1920">1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e601a913db1b23375ea7fca2653d144" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00053" level="file"><did><unittitle>Austin Craig<title render="italic">South and Eastern Asia: Forgotten Chapters of World History</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1926/1926">1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_215b9c395a10d2328448e82be8d741fc" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA3099-00054" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Philippine-American News Digest</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e92b9d72385df39357af874f4a791dc" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00055" level="series"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1901/1955" type="inclusive">1901-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_81c0044d3e6a6c72c7528ce3d7cd5654" label="box" type="box">3</container></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00056" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1901/1955" type="inclusive">1901-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_4417e4303e5eeb35e75ce63d6b56cd4e" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00057" level="series"><did><unittitle>Diary</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1914/1915" type="inclusive">1914-1915</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00058" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harvey and Maude</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1914/1915" type="inclusive">1914-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ce72a96f78ca573c3e9f85919e1f20d" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00059" level="series"><did><unittitle>Yearbooks</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916/1921" type="inclusive">1916-1921</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00060" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Souvenir</title> Manila High School</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1921/1921">1921</unitdate><container id="aspace_772dca5a28a2098b91fe4ffc92378468" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00061" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Torch</title> The Philippine Normal School</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916/1916">1916</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3cf286f848f2fa77dd88977f5e41e48" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00062" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Torch</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7ef5ab32bcc32f77df9af1ccf998d4c" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00063" level="series"><did><unittitle>Certificates and awards</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1915/1929" type="inclusive">1915-1929</unitdate></did><odd id="aspace_4de808a8a0070c69cdd646d0fe968244"><head>General</head><p>(stored with oversized materials)</p></odd><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00064" level="file"><did><unittitle>Philippine Islands Anti-Tuberculosis Society</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d18426e3f5754f3538e0820c336b570" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00065" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificate naming Bordner "Superintendent of Schools of the City of Manila"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_26a4be7ff543d2a6924f89775a27266e" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00066" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Concilium Supremum Conciliorum Orbis Terrarum Parens"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1915/1915">1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_725974007586f8e9694b3fe6fe9e46c6" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00067" level="series"><did><unittitle>Memorial materials</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA3099-00068" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence, obituaries, etc.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_77a1f874213ba15061005d2ec62135e1" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA3099-00069" level="series"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1902/1936" type="inclusive">circa 1902-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_b98a1538fca825ade2492b0a08690181" label="boxes" type="box">4-5</container></did><odd id="aspace_4c00167348117d74b8334674b167bf08"><head>General</head><p>Photographs and scrapbooks are stored with the Archives Photograph Collection. Consult staff for details.</p></odd></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
