<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA1364</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Owen family collection, <date type="inclusive" normal="1826/1967" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1826-1967</date> <num>C89</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Collection at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Dina M. Kellams</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date> 2004</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:10:25 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>October 14, 2004</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>October 19, 2004</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>May 7, 2007</date><item>Editorial changes so file validates per DLP EAD check list.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Owen family collection</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Owen family.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C89</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic feet 1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1826/1967" type="inclusive">1826-1967</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1830/1890" type="bulk">1830-1890</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_fc5708008ad2ca8c63afa07755bb5e76">Indiana family headed by Robert Owen, who purchased Harmony from the Rappites in Posey County, Indiana, with the intention of establishing a utopian society, New Harmony. Owen's three sons were major players in the introduction of geology, biology, and psychology in Indiana and the United States. Collection includes correspondence, speeches, and publications of Robert Owen and his descendants. Most prominently featured in the collection are Owen's sons David Dale, Richard, and Robert Dale. Some materials are photocopies of manuscripts held by other repositories.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_768649f70a79bf72d6ce926d1a91f559">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_ad3da8f43ee3bf79d69f050446ab149e">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ae225a9500484368b5671ff5bd649380">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Born in Newton, Montgomeryshire, North Wales, March 14, 1771, Robert Owen first introduced important social reforms as a cotton manufacturer in New Lanark, Scotland. In January, 1825, Owen purchased Harmony from the Rappites in Posey County, Indiana, with the intention of establishing a utopian society - New Harmony. Although this venture eventually failed, Owen's three sons - Robert Dale, Richard Dale, and David Dale - were major players in the introduction of geology, biology, and psychology in Indiana and the United States (a fourth son, William Dale, died just as he was becoming known). Individually, Robert Dale and David Dale were largely responsible for the creation of the Smithsonian Institute and the organization of the United States Geological Survey.</p><p> Robert Dale Owen, the eldest son, was born in Glasgow, November 7, 1801 and educated at Fellensberg College near Berne, Switzerland. He came to the United States with his father to assist him in his efforts of founding New Harmony. In 1832, Owen married Mary Jane Robinson of New York. They settled in New Harmony, where he was elected a member of the Legislature 1835- 1838. Owen's political career continued throughout his life: from 1843 to 1847, he represented the First District of Indiana in Congress, where he took an active part in settling the northwest boundary question and introduced the bill organizing the Smithsonian Institution. In 1850, he was a member of the Indiana Constitutional Convention; he traveled to Naples, Italy, in 1853, as U.S. Charge d'affaires, and from 1855 to 1858, he held the position as minister. Owen published many works on several topics, including "Outlines of System of Education at New Lanark," "Discussion with Origen Bachelor on the Personality of God and the Authenticity of the Bible," and his autobiography, "Threading my Way."</p><p> David Dale Owen was born in New Lanark in 1807. He too accompanied his father to New Harmony, though he returned to Europe to study chemistry and geology at the University of London. After only a year, he returned to the United States to enter the Ohio Medical College at Cincinnati, from which he received a M.D. degree in 1835. In 1837, David Dale became the the first State Geologist of Indiana, assigned to conduct a geological reconnaissance of the state. Indiana Governor James Whitcomb was so impressed with Owen's work that when he became commissioner of the Federal Land Office in Washington, he selected Owen to lead a mineral survey of nearly 11,000 sq. miles of the Northwest Territory. From 1847-1852, Owen lead the geological survey of more of the Northwest Territory, chiefly the area now comprising Wisconsin, Minnesota, Iowa, and parts of Illinois and Nebraska, with his brother Richard Dale assisting. From 1854-1858 David Dale served as the first State Geologist of Kentucky; 1858- 1859 State Geologist of Arkansas, and in 1859 he was reappointed State Geologist in Indiana. David Dale Owen died November 13, 1860. After his death, his Richard Dale succeeded him as State Geologist.</p><p> Richard Owen, born January 6, 1810 in New Lanark, Scotland, also traveled to New Harmony with his father in 1827. After serving in the Mexican War, he returned to New Harmony to assist his brother David in the geological survey of parts of the Northwest Territory. In 1849, Richard accepted a position as chair of natural science at the Western Military Institute of Kentucky, a position he held for 8 years. In 1858, Owen received his M.D. at the Nashville (Tennessee) Medical College. After his brother David's death in 1860, Richard became the State Geologist of Indiana and in 1861, a member of the Indiana University faculty. Dr. Owen was called from this position, however, at the outbreak of the Civil War. He returned to his duties as professor at the University in 1864, a position he held until 1879. After his retirement, Owen continued his scientific studies in New Harmony. It was in New Harmony that he died on March 24, 1890, after mistakenly drinking embalming fluid.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c9a25c3076146b9fd57f58928588a8bb">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Organized into five series: Robert Owen; David Dale Owen; Richard Owen; Robert Dale Owen; and Owen family descendants.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_a1ae2b91804f6a2a35b1affd975117d9">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>Organized into five series, the Owen family collection consists of correspondence, speeches, and publications of the descendants of Robert Owen.</p><p> The Robert Owen series, 1826-1850, consists of correspondence and a single publication of patriarch Robert Owen. The correspondence subseries consists entirely of photocopies of correspondence held by a repository in England. The most frequent correspondent is Robert Peel about negotiations between Britain and the United States over the Oregon Territory.</p><p> The second series, David Dale Owen, 1844-1859, includes three reports and reproductions of his geological drawings. The reports include "Geological Reconnoissance of the State of Indiana made in the year 1837, in Conformity to an Order of the Legislature" (known also as the first geological survey of Indiana), "Geological Report on the Marble Hill Quarry" (1853), and an 1844 "Report of a Geological Exploration of Part of Iowa, Wisconsin, and Illinois."</p><p> The Richard Owen series consists of correspondence, publications, speeches. Within the correspondence subseries, there is a mix of originals and photocopies of originals held by another repository. </p><p> The Robert Dale Owen series consists almost entirely of photocopies of original correspondence and speeches from 1830 to 1865. Prominently featured in the correspondence subseries is RDO's father, Robert Owen. The speeches subseries includes copies of addresses made to the House of Representatives.</p><p> The fifth and final series, Owen family descendants, includes correspondence of Caroline Dale Owen Snedeker and Malcolm Dale Owen, grandniece and grandson of Richard Dale Owen, with Indiana University officials about the Owen family.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_dd982def3d6d53a7324712b3fbb0b632">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession 97/066</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b1c8eae3fb2a37b273ec1ed8b197f8b3">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_70c2d9c312e7d2daad0033ded0c5662f">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Owen family collection, Collection C89, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ab1f0e4307b180f7388b09aec93199d2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Dina M. Kellams.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2004" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2000</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Family archives --Indiana.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Politicians --Indiana --Archives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Politicians --Indiana --Correspondence.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Geologists --Indiana --Archives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Geologists --Indiana --Correspondence.</subject>
    <geogname source="aacr2">Indiana --History --Sources.</geogname>
    <geogname source="aacr2">New Harmony (Ind.) --History --Sources.</geogname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Faculty --History --19th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <famname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen family --Archives.</famname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Robert, 1771-1858 --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Robert, 1771-1858 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Richard, 1810-1890 --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Richard, 1810-1890 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, David Dale, 1807-1860 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Robert Dale, 1801-1877 --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Robert Dale, 1801-1877 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Robert, 1771-1858. Correspondence. Selections.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Richard, 1810-1890. Correspondence. Selections.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Owen, Robert Dale, 1801-1877. Correspondence. Selections.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_790bdeb3bfb0442ccbf194481f4786ca" level="series"><did><unittitle>Robert Owen</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1826/1850" type="inclusive">1826-1850</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_2627676b13083e24328685891dbc4338" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1826/1847" type="inclusive">1826-1847</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_48dbf6f7c747726c2b14992a21e123ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>"Lord Aberdeen" (George Hamilton Gordon)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1826-04-30/1826-04-30">30 Apr. 1826</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1826-05-26/1826-05-26">16 May 1826</unitdate><container id="aspace_5329d7fd69bc0551a17783b6de6aaedb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7985383769a208295f40b9443afba6f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Peel, Robert</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1826/1847" type="inclusive">1846-1847</unitdate><container id="aspace_c33955c1210b70bfa663e089c270e01f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7be1949772687b6309802b0b60ebd012" level="file"><did><unittitle>"My --- wife and daughters"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1830-08-27/1830-08-27">27 Aug. 1830</unitdate><container id="aspace_ded57bc69b5d140b2a184233c4d2cfa4" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_9fa11f76de8bd85d155360ccb1d5ff13" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1850/1850">1850</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_48fc98de3a820b59409cedb50ed925a1" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Letters to the Human Race on the Coming Universal Revolution"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1850/1850">1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_33ac0d5a6cd36b55f0c77623d3e61389" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a1634f170a7f2f6392aa60fc14b5c20c" level="series"><did><unittitle>David Dale Owen</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1844/1859" type="inclusive">1844-1859</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_02fbb51e9c81159386a542a3ad241c4a" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1844/1859" type="inclusive">1844-1859</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_3db8d08cd99845baeb50376ce277fe9c" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Report of a Geological Exploration of Part of Iowa, Wisconsin, and Illinois"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1844/1844">1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b734ad544f4e18be270c78ce5a8d0ea" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_db32b0826b7f1b58d0d38f9dc90ab4ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>Illustrations for "Report of a Geological Exploration..."</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1844/1844">1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_be122fb458b415359d3a46cf80325ee3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_8992defab5c464acd21908668996a3bd" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"A Geological Report on the Marble Hill Quarry"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1853/1853">1853</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd73f7c0fed3ffab830620a7351ab8be" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_6f7b6e32912eee8b3587d703f90cab12" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Report of a Geological Reconnoissance of the State of Indiana, made in the year 1837, in Conformity to an Order of the Legislature"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859/1859">1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_d848be1c77326c1234063c814de76013" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ef9fff93e6f6da910c46308c7dd48f70" level="series"><did><unittitle>Richard Owen</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1834/1890" type="inclusive">1834-1890</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_7bcc49d3d774e1289ef2fb9b418d1f7b" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1834/1889" type="inclusive">1834-1889</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_ce0c0c185cf9a42a0c32ad80b2ceef95" level="file"><did><unittitle>Baker, Conrad</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1869-02-13/1869-02-13">13 Feb. 1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_5740cb73d4bc2c5365d46557150a4249" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_b42ff3998e9f02c19b246b1f1ba4255e"><head>General</head><p>Indiana Governor</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_0344b74abbd2320b901d4afe7f6ef1e2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foster, John W.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1858-09-20/1858-09-20">20 Sept. 1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_f10d1824158b0ea1a56bbf63d190fb77" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_75ad6c8fc375f620640cbebbeb89464c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Owen, Robert</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1834-10-03/1834-10-03">3 Oct 1834</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1838-06-19/1838-06-19">19 June 1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_ece72eda15e0fe7510bf5023bc504fe9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_64d95e3a2d1c6c68ae54dbac61739bbc"><head>General</head><p>Father</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_02c6580f8a6a0f4967e78f93f0323021" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857/1890" type="inclusive">1857-1890</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_e23c4071ad0e095578e68fbf5ad74b23" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Report upon the Mineral and Agricultural Resources of the Lands owned by the Hopkins Mastodon Coal and Iron Mining and Manufacturing Company: The Result of an Exploration"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_5ed39a96a09240c2bd03a83cefbe6b64" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_2964e6c039b1a46e5797235dc88a7fff" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Report of Geological Examination made on the Lands of the Wabash Petroleum and Coal Mining Company, in Warren, Fountain and Parke Counties"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1866/1866">1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_25f925c9fd8d592f7d8e63b641352d4c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7ca5ccc3ed8aee1a8a515c7917938143" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Terrestrial Magnetism"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1871-10-01/1890" type="inclusive">after Oct. 1871</unitdate><container id="aspace_d450dc6f88524d21fe92207bca13c495" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_0a22d16a3d7413e9fe470400cd9ea652" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Report to the Trustees of Purdue University"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1873/1873">1873</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc9918180b98a4d49a114c5903b76aff" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_8b3e0378b3cf115df8ee905ce1f8adfd" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"The Dynamics of Land-Forming"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1877/1877">1877</unitdate><container id="aspace_f01e8632b71502ff01db759abdc1a709" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_50ac7f16ee892275dab721b76b493561" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"British Earthquakes and their Seismic Relations"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1884/1884">1884</unitdate><container id="aspace_2d2780da04bfe74153241aeaf4176222" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_53d2c58b4bba3a28b994f06516323f10" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Notes on Various Subjects"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1890/1890">1890</unitdate><container id="aspace_e366e781d6ca5567b9dfe20fee400b2b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_01faa87f8a671a5b1db2bbd485eacd3b" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Speeches</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857/1879" type="inclusive">1857-1879</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_8c1b43dda1cef87405ad04863bad5b70" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"'Honor to the Illustrious Dead': A Lecture on Behalf of the Mount Vernon Association"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_f803885a805432033d9acb5c1977ad03" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_83d27255e88227bf13ae4b0f960acec9" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Happiness and Home, Temporal and Eternal: A Farewell Address, Delivered at the College Chapel of the Indiana State University"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1879/1879">1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_890d979b4410e03f13b1b00f18966f3e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_4634eb373110cae165900949399ad4a0" level="series"><did><unittitle>Robert Dale Owen</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1830/1865" type="inclusive">1830-1865</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_4888098bb0dfba77419ab1e6a4317957" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1830/1865" type="inclusive">1830-1865</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_1c2f1dc6a351fcdffb640d3b3312e4f3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Allsop, Anna (?)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1845-10-08/1845-10-08">8 Oct. 1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c2b12beedf1f8c2c69e81a2f6efa490" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1e8058b7e4279c8971ec14cc0096c198" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brinton, Joseph D.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1865-01-24/1865-01-24">24 Jan. 1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_6dbb2651b551da90d92379f14cdc4763" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_b50c2707520ded571fb765bbec114108" level="file"><did><unittitle>Harris, H. J.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1830/1865" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_cabcb0c9928290a869ddf376a94aff3f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_d3af219b5b34963cab7c747141e46b22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Owen's handwritten copy of letter: Prof. W. C. Larrabee to President Franklin Pierce</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1853-01-18/1853-01-18">18 Jan. 1853</unitdate><container id="aspace_658ac3ece79a94e32302535a7f740c2c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_19c34eef953152d21d635ea28f3f8c7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Owen, Caroline Dale</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1830-01-04/1830-01-04">4 Jan 1830</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1930-08-12/1930-08-12">12 Aug. 1830</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae895039bf4a86480df2d1b7424303ca" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_cef2ebdcff6758f09cfdd8042e772d3d"><head>General</head><p>Mother</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_59841cc62a64a6994d92f127f62c18d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Owen, Robert</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1831/1858" type="inclusive">1831-1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_adb77bf42570dbe30b49770dbb44ee8d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_81f21024e6d74c3e9a13c1ef01a042c5"><head>General</head><p>Father</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_4ceba1da29bd7c0cdf31974fdca1f999" level="file"><did><unittitle>Watts, R.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1865-12-26/1865-12-26">26 Dec. 1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_b72518c063015d4ba2d8c3a3fa589c88" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_a490220b961fda018ed58d6a7690959d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Owen to ? regarding payment on an outstanding bill</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1830/1865" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_669d63e05d7895deba162db310ea295f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_4faaa49f66977b516b85c57c8fb931a1" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Speeches</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1838/1844" type="inclusive">1838-1844</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_4664e41adbb9bc20d00b5cbe4f0b59c3" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Address touching the Influence and Progress of Literature and the Sciences: Delivered before the Philomathean Society of the Indiana University at the Annual Commencement, September, 1838"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1838-09/1838-09">Sept. 1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_a930b343688e0cabe2fdc595cb9f30a6" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_b2a9cc1dc43675586aa940206f3cbbe0" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Address touching an Error of General Prevalance in Society; Delivered in the University Chapel, before the Monroe County Lyceum, on Commencement Day, September 1841"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1841-09/1841-09">Sept. 1841</unitdate><container id="aspace_d37d3b2b2c374f305f8cb6a30bfb389f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_c1a2aacf368ba84152a79a30506756cc" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"The Theory of Tariff Protection"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1844-04-22/1844-04-22">22 Apr. 1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_f47f3feb643927957b9152be30a2113a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_2b18db676d962a62df985ed09a310f4e" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Annexation of Texas. Speech of Mr. Owen, of Indiana, delivered in the House of Representatives, May 21, 1844"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1844-05-21/1844-05-21">21 May 1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_30276391bf017400bfcee76195af3494" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_3c24e0da2e01c99a930f64d4893f0bbf" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Native Americanism. Extract from an Address delivered at Madison, Indiana, July 26, 1844"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1844-07-26/1844-07-26">26 July 1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9e3dcc557e8ab0f08010f0ef4e2cb4b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_6e5c90c902430c7cb98b820601496b3e" level="file"><did><unittitle><title>"Native Americanism"</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1843/1845" type="inclusive">ca. 1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_31762d4c43729f78c178ef1a9c8996ed" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_f2e7f46102404fa12185af0dad27d711" level="series"><did><unittitle>Owen family descendants</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1856/1967" type="inclusive">1856-1967</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_bb7f6b0a2c1cbebab0b967f263c59bf6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1856/1967" type="inclusive">1856-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_5122e7e50e4539be5c30d15aa82cc85d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
