<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA3283</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana University School of Dentistry records, <date normal="1923/1980" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1923-1980</date> <num>C262</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Ryan K. Lee</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>ÂŠ 2006</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:57:10 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 30, 2006</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>March 30, 2006</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>May 6, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana University School of Dentistry records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Indiana University School of Dentistry.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C262</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.8 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">3 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">1923-1980</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1927/1929" type="bulk">1927-1929</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5e9b7c9bd4447f2ade341ab5a1bf3497">The Indiana Dental College was founded in 1879 in Indianapolis for the purpose of increasing the standards of dentistry in Indiana. Indiana University purchased the college in 1925, and in 1933 moved it to its current location on West Michigan Street in Indianapolis. The collection consists of minutes of the executive committee, collected histories of the school, lists of alumni, and correspondence.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_94fa720fa64e84ed1f52a156d82cce09">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f18279d5f1a82695cbc58ef8aa348170">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_6dc2b081e83bb168697c72963311cd36">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The Indiana Dental College opened its doors to students on October 1, 1879. The birth of the college was a result of the Mississippi Valley Association of Dental Surgeons, founded in 1844, and the Indiana State Dental Association, founded in 1858. Both organizations were founded by J.P. Ulrey, one of the earliest and most prominent dentists in Indiana history.</p><p> The mission of the Indiana State Dental Association was to upgrade the standards of dentistry in Indiana. One strategy they developed for achieving this was to get legislation passed that upheld dental standards. However, the Indiana State Legislature was hesitant to pass such legislation since there were no dentistry schools in Indiana at the time. Nonetheless, a law was enacted in 1879 stating that a diploma was required to practice dentistry in the state of Indiana. There is some speculation that the Indiana State Dental Association negotiated with the Indiana State Legislature, in which the enactment of the new law was contingent on the establishment of the Indiana Dental College.</p><p> Dr. P.G.C. Hunt, a member of the Mississippi Valley Association of Dental Surgeons, was the first president of the state board of dental examiners and was highly interested in a dental school being founded in Indiana. Dr. William Heiskell, president of the Indiana State Dental Association, instructed Drs. Hunt and Junius Cravens to invite all dentists in Indiana to a meeting at Dr. Heiskell's office in Indianapolis on June 23, 1879. A Dental College Association and board of trustees were formed during this meeting. On September 1, 1879, a two year lease was signed for a building at 147 East Market Street, in Indianapolis, Indiana, to house the Indiana Dental College.</p><p> However, with rising scholastic and administrative standards issued by the Dental Education Council in the early twentieth century, it became near impossible for privately owned schools to operate at a reasonable profit. Due to fiscal considerations, dentists seeking a reputable dental school in Indiana favored a dental college owned by the state. Consequently, Indiana University assumed ownership of the Indiana Dental College on June 1, 1925, for the price of $35,000.</p><p> In July of 1929 the Indiana University School of Dentistry issued a statement saying that all previous graduates of the Indiana Dental College were eligible to receive a diploma from the Indiana University School of Dentistry. The School moved to 1121 West Michigan Street in 1933 and has resided there ever since. Omicron Kappa Upsilon, the national dental honor society, formed the Theta Theta chapter of the Indiana University School of Dentistry in 1934.</p><p> The school continued to thrive throughout the 1930s and 1940s. In 1935, the U.S. Public Health Service designated Indiana University as a research center for the study of dental diseases of children. The federal government funded a children's clinic comprised of 15 modern dental units. In 1940 three new departments were created, Oral Diagnosis, Dental Materials, and Periodontia. This was followed up by the development of a Master of Science in Oral Pathology and Orthodontia in 1942. During World War II, the Dental School accelerated its program to aid in the war effort by creating a three-semester academic year. Remodeling also began on the school in 1948 with excavation of a basement for locker rooms and the construction of a postgraduate clinic on the third floor. The library was moved to the first floor and an elevator was installed. In 1962 and 1972, new additions to the building were completed.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_fff66f6c07a8ee23cef0bd59eec39733">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection is organized into five series: Alumni lists; Correspondence; Events; History; and Minutes. Correspondence is further divided into the sub-series General correspondence and Deans' correspondence. History is further divided into the sub-series General Files and Historical statistics.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c9fda94c0b9efffb8b64c3c048277105">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The records of the Indiana University School of Dentistry have been arranged into 5 series: Alumni Lists; Correspondence; Events; History; and Minutes. The collection spans the years 1923 through 1980.</p><p> The series Alumni lists contains information on alumni dating back to the first graduating class of 1879. There are several different types of alumni lists in this series, including a list by year of graduation, by addresses as of 1927, and by a determination if the person was living or deceased as of 1927. This series also contains a list of graduates from the Indiana Dental College who later received diplomas from Indiana University. This series is organized in alphabetical order.</p><p> The Correspondence series is divided into two sub-series: General correspondence and Deans. The General correspondence is comprised primarily of responses to a letter written in 1929 by George F. Heighway, IU alumni secretary. The letter was sent to alumni of the Indiana Dental College notifying them that since the school had been purchased by Indiana University, they were now eligible for a degree from Indiana University for $2.50. Some of the more noteworthy responses are from the president of the Indiana State Board of Dental Examiners and Chief of Dental Services from the Office of the Surgeon General. This sub-series is arranged in alphabetical order. The sub-series, Deans, consists primarily of interdepartmental letters about specific graduates of the Indiana State Dental College requesting degrees from Indiana University. This sub-series is arranged in alphabetical order.</p><p> The Events series contains a program from a 1958 luncheon of the dental honor society Omicron Kappa Upsilon, as well as four folders that contain a program from the 1978 graduation ceremony, a graduation invitation from 1924, an undated and unsigned diploma, and a copy of the dentist's oath.</p><p> The series, History, is divided into two sub-series: General files and Historical statistics. The General files sub-series contains a dissertation, an address, a faculty report, and a survey. The dissertation was written by Jack D. Carr and is entitled, <title render="italic">History of the Indiana Dental College, 1879â1925.</title> It focuses on the history of Indiana Dental College until the college merged with Indiana University in 1925. The address was given by William J. Gies in 1923 at the 65th General Session of the American Dental Association and is entitled, <title render="doublequote">The Dental Education Problem.</title> James R. Roche wrote the faculty report in 1980 entitled, <title render="doublequote">Faculty Promotion at Indiana University School of Dentistry.</title> The survey was conducted by the Council on Dental Education between 1942 and 1943. It is a review of the Indiana University School of Dentistry based on criteria defined within the survey. This sub-series is arranged in alphabetical order. The sub-series Historical statistics contains statistics from 1925 to 1966 pertaining to degrees, enrollment, equipment, matriculation, and rates charged. This sub-series is also arranged alphabetically.</p><p> The next series, Minutes, is composed of two bound volumes and one file of loose minutes. The first bound volume spans the period from June 1925 to December 1932. The second bound volume of minutes covers the years from January 1933 to July 1943. The loose minutes are contained within a separate folder. This series is arranged in chronological order.</p><p> Some material has been pulled from the archives reference files and interfiled into this collection.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7190786909cee58123527c36c98deaff">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accessions 006 and 7062.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b53118ac0e376ee4296e36026991a724">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2b447e13de86061c311092f92810180e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana University School of Dentistry records, Collection C262, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_931d3ac8637aa18c96a704587eb9b224">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Jeffrey Lewis, Serena Olson, and Kate B. Moore.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2006" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2006</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Dentistry --Study and teaching --Indiana --History --20th century --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Dental schools --Indiana --History --20th century --Sources.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University School of Dentistry --History --20th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University School of Dentistry --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University School of Dentistry --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_04cd9a389c0628494afaf983467d8d0b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Alumni lists</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_403045689d1fd3b9f5611e881b573d53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Complete list of alumni, 1879-1944</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_9ca0b53e13bf3acc0dcb6864fa126f41" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2faaa721741ba6cecba2753386e52e27" level="file"><did><unittitle>List of alumni with addresses, 1879-1927</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c306ea18f03f06aee16e2618f2b737f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cd7902e8e196cd726dd172d85bda93c6" level="file"><did><unittitle>List of those who received degrees, 1886-1950</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b1c8ba6cecb6cc66549ec83eae929be" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7d239ea50c33199aad5d4549ffcf44a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Working list of graduates, 1883-1944</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8a103b97c84f846e789aee58bc0a296" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_1702d8458e87220c29819f3891e34f73" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1924/1958" type="inclusive">1924-1958</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_e64d5ed19b73b92e2b29a64265fa7025" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>General correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925/1948" type="inclusive">1925-1948</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_0f81336eee928f43cd9fb406e8a28266" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-C</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1928/1933" type="inclusive">1928-1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a394b1ccf7811ef1c64e84a92c3b0eb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_f05b9596d766f911af459388425cc63e" level="file"><did><unittitle>D-F</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1929/1936" type="inclusive">1929-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b7738745c7bdfa52a919b849d296a06" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_ed4b84862f0c2046b39df717ea981715" level="file"><did><unittitle>G-I</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925/1936" type="inclusive">1925-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9567c5975b1cafb574ddafe14bc425e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_eb8a2bdfa13e7d246c882e3add25cc95" level="file"><did><unittitle>J-L</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1929/1948" type="inclusive">1929-1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_dcd99639eaaf2a77cfc0d306662b2e32" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_ff9778c5f62a3937ed4af7d5e1d02625" level="file"><did><unittitle>M-O</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1926/1932" type="inclusive">1926-1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_abd15501e3dd9690dd92294cbc6293d5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_f99b62e0c54d8fbb5a417547d9476716" level="file"><did><unittitle>P-S</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925/1948" type="inclusive">1925-1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_80ba11e60a709c529c9ced6e196f84ef" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_eab7c00d9aa04e89861137013fda4cc2" level="file"><did><unittitle>T-Z</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925/1936" type="inclusive">1925-1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_ecaf2a6c7d43267fe172369518911c72" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_e1c4369119fd7c9b2e5f566898b749d9" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Deans</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1924/1958" type="inclusive">1924-1958</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_3e18c5277c7e73c5bf1c696950055869" level="file"><did><unittitle>Crawford, William H.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1940/1944" type="inclusive">1940-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_49ff53ceecc57cde70fd2253b5683680" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_c5c4e7ae04963de3046e5fd620226db2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henshaw, Frederic Rich</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1924/1937" type="inclusive">ca. 1924-1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_2d80b763b3d2c7a5861239071c462637" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_db8066a938f1c02b0c48e2dca3226d44" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hine, Maynard K.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1949/1958" type="inclusive">1949-1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_aba272e0cb725031b356c62aa4c605bd" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_e8e6eed22db7e3a6e105898fe92b87cd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Timmons, Gerald D.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_117ca7b3759cda1649bb18b707c4337f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_4a98910c818d423122ecdef91f0c2c1f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Events</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1924/1978" type="inclusive">1924-1978</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_53cd3e3105e0ea2aea029c876be2bfd4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Graduation degree</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9de51e439110adec756ee476897b947" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1f7abb9901010cc52327a906394398d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Graduation invitation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1924/1924">ca. 1924</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1fdfb26f9699d200a2e543320251ba5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fe0ad82a753b0b742fd9b508a75684be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Graduation oath</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1962/1962">ca. 1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_1461009e56076e7c3316e7c0b8c54919" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9854d3ac9445a9377838139a9f81f94b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Graduation program</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1978/1978">ca. 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_64e9f052eb6acaf40731b5a8c5a8b148" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a6bc5fbe730d77e8e1f463e1cd2f2c7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Luncheon</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1958/1958">ca. 1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d81c70c78004ff20549e1aa8c825311" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_d9618088e7ed1d8a266f01b983dc1c50" level="series"><did><unittitle>History</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">1923-1980</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_45665c65b8ee2e6761d6a8c4f1a5fe1e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>General files</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">1923-1980</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_f4e5c85db61dba86ff95c6ac26e64b98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jack D. Carr, dissertation<title render="italic"/></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_d07c7de11efdb128032919aa953444af" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_c574b8b1527e708f0947226d66e17a5e" level="file"><did><unittitle>William J. Gies, address to the American Dental Association<title render="doublequote">The Dental Education Problem</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1923/1923">ca. 1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfafda25123c7862b9735f33a3fbdb67" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_74e00a489eea87b59a2939120a7748d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>James R. Roche, faculty report<title render="doublequote">Faculty Promotion at Indiana University School of Dentistry</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1980/1980">ca. 1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_d9fd521b0ed43b5027f9f185dcbacad2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_94ad037ce76bfbfe5d37f99c25414886" level="file"><did><unittitle>Survey of Dental Schools, conducted by the Council on Dental Education</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1943/1943">ca. 1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_1787b90908057c7559ea4fa2158a717b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_727af068f7c9b43d8ceeba2d0a8347f7" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Historical statistics</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925/1966" type="inclusive">1925-1966</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_162c12cbda991a43b504ce09233ebb2c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Degrees</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1926/1949" type="inclusive">1926-1949</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_96852f64c1031fd8aac0771e528687cf" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_2452edc516a1484d74efa3701844ea74" level="file"><did><unittitle>Enrollment</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1940/1966" type="inclusive">1940-1966</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_29dc0e1a5e6df8367e8ffe085d547372" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_5477d38fbe7c6d8b5b6634d396a255c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Equipment</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925/1925">1925</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_92898f7545274e1a66b142539709449f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_907f93905884629ac12c9132e35e43e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Matriculation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1940/1966" type="inclusive">1940-1966</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1980" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0837292a5b87311054b732975a15ac9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_617d383d3d513be13e99f0b65ec64a76" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rates</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1928/1928">ca. 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_d81b049b10f8646fc297bc380b3d197f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_bf0a0a275611cbb8101b98ab64146d6d" level="series"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925/1943" type="inclusive">1925-1943</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_503de35c062e46eeaf31d1856f23e129" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes, individual copies</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1943" type="inclusive">1937-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a78035c8a66fd0ed8dc76e46824debf" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f8b43e3191c1165284ea3b78a358dc2e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes of the Executive committee</unittitle><container id="aspace_7c51b66200e51bd953dccc8528122d7e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_75d1b4b5eaa60ed4c406f90e067205db" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925-06/1932-12" type="inclusive">June 1925-Dec. 1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_7fea6ac9792b688920e5236770bb432e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_354c021bc61bd043e37921c5df7f2f93" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1933-01/1943-06" type="inclusive">Jan. 1933-June 1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e003db170a5bdae7fafc21670d8b9ee" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c03></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
