<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAD9024</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>William T. Morgan papers, 1922-1945, bulk 1922-1928<date normal="1922/1945">1922-1945</date> <num>C671</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to his Papers at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Madison Chartier</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date> 2018</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2018"> 2018</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:01:40 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>April 10, 2017</date><item>Finding aid created.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William T. Morgan papers</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">William T. Morgan, Professor of History</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C671</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.4 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1922/1945" type="inclusive">1922-1945</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1922/1928" type="bulk">1922-1928</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f4811b770cb99a598424df4d2eab0707">William T. Morgan was a professor of history at Indiana University from 1919-1946. This collection includes typescript and handwritten essays by Morgan and other authors on pedagogy and the state of higher education; various annotated resources and notes related to Morgan's research on British history and educational practice; and a small amount of correspondence.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_534959c568d62e74e1fdfbef6d95c5dd">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_42fee9fbda0680557c4282f2e5bbabfd">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a91147dd7baa087282ed11099d83fb3e">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>William T. Morgan was born May 19, 1883 in Dell Roy, Ohio. He received his bachelor's degree from Ohio University in 1909 and served various teaching and administrative roles in a number of schools throughout Ohio. After earning his master's in history from Harvard in 1910, he served as an instructor in government at Iowa State Teachers College before pursuing and earning his Ph.D. in history from Yale University in 1916. He taught for three years at Columbia University and then joined the history faculty at Indiana University in 1919, where he ultimately remained until his death in 1946. He also served as an instructor at Ohio University, Boston University, Duke University, State University of Iowa, and the University of Michigan during summer sessions.</p><p> Morgan specialized in English history but had an educational background in pedagogy and frequently examined and wrote about pressing concerns in education in addition to and in association with his historical research. Of his numerous publications in history, political science, and education, Morgan is best known for his five-volume Bibliography of British History, 1700-1715, with a particular focus on the reign of Queen Anne, published between 1934-1942. He also published in the Political Science Quarterly, the South Atlantic Quarterly, the Contemporary Review, the American Historical Review, and the Journal of Modern History. He spent a considerable time abroad, especially in England, as part of his research, spending the summers of 1915, 1933, and 1936 and the academic years of 1923-1924 and 1929-1930 overseas.</p><p> Among the honors Morgan received during his career were membership in the Royal Historical Society and receipt of the Herbert Baxter Adams Prize from the American Historical Association. Morgan passed away on June 9, 1946.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_7cfd14853919dbecc7a4b2d36e87b5d6">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection is organized alphabetically by folder title.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2793df8385924bc07e645c2741f45bd1">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection includes typescript and handwritten essays by Morgan and other authors on pedagogy and the state of higher education; various annotated resources and notes related to Morgan's research on British history and educational practice; a copy of his 1945 publication, Topical Outline for the Study of English History, Pt. I (to 1688); and letters from H. Ernestine Bulger Ripley (1928) and Frederick J. Gould (1926).</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_78f80ec5a1f88378911be86d3d065a6e">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Related photographs may be available in the <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">Indiana University Archives Photographs Collection</extref>.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a2982397c27e7b4a10c16de7ed344c2c">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession: 2016/106</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_75e355699cc88c57b1c0af7dd61a6b74">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p>  The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p>  </userestrict>
  <custodhist id="aspace_f93cade33bf38a0e5977ffa6e6d4eac0">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Transferred from the Raymond H. Fogler Library of the University of Maine to the University Archives, July 2016.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_881abd7977c8dce581d630d1f98b86f6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[item], William T. Morgan papers, Collection C671, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f148518348234bce642ae3923d7f4229">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Madison Chartier.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2017">2017</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD9024-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>William T. Morgan papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1922/1945" type="inclusive">1922-1945 and undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b500ab20f551909446b1190eb518fc13" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_VAD9024-00002" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letter, H. Ernestine Bulger Ripley to William T. Morgan</unittitle><unitdate normal="1928-01-10/1928-01-10">January 10, 1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_d190784cec176af3af00cbc011b11ce0" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD9024-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>Pamphlets on education</unittitle><unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_838809b7b7e498f4937af8cb4a697c14" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_53e834504458f5848cd7b1d50a6bd252"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Includes a letter (October 1922) from Frederick J. Gould to Morgan regarding the teaching of history, economics, and government in Great Britain.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD9024-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Research material, circa</unittitle><unitdate normal="1923/1926" type="inclusive">1923-1926</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_9a91ac532079c00b285f4ac799d2373b">(2 folders)</physdesc><container id="aspace_e86b093e2e1a06670e2bdecab395192f" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_a8e04fb6f38863d71a7eecee676a6882"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Newspaper clippings, articles, and handwritten notes, mostly related to early twentieth century pedagogy and British politics.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD9024-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle>William T. Morgan, "The Professor's Dilemma" and untitled essay, undated</unittitle><container id="aspace_58e71d36bb37ab7f372e03b8f7a28343" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_af8477ff3093f505f9448b39e891f8c5"><head>Scope and Content Note</head><p>Both documents discuss the contemporary state of higher education.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD9024-00006" level="item"><did><unittitle>William T. Morgan<emph render="italic">Topical Outline for the Study of English History, Pt. I (to 1688)</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a59b7d283a907427807cbe5573e4f2a" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD9024-00007" level="item"><did><unittitle>Unknown author, "Confessions of a Pedagogue," undated</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6 pages</extent></physdesc><container id="aspace_470f3c6ec64db34c45c6a97db79d7cbf" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
