<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA2800</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana University Graduate Council records, <date normal="1900/2005" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1900-2005</date> <num>C278</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Donald C. Force</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2006</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:08:01 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 12, 2007</date><item>May 15, 1902 file added to Administrative files series. DMK</item></change><change><date>January 8, 2007</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>January 8, 2007</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>May 6, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana University Graduate Council records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Indiana University. University Graduate School. Graduate Council.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C278</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.3 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1900/2005" type="inclusive">1900-2005</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951/1980" type="bulk">bulk 1951-1980</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0953b0d4784f53498aaaf84164f8c105">In 1894, Indiana University instituted a standing Committee on Advanced Degrees charged with directing the growing number of students undertaking graduate studies. Formal organization of the Graduate School was authorized by the faculty in 1904, with the continued governance of the Committee until the office of the dean within the IU Graduate School was created in 1908. At that time, the committee emerged as the Administrative Committee and in 1909 became the Graduate Council. As the school's faculty took over the duties of the council in the 1930s, the council was deemed unnecessary and disbanded. However, in the 1950s the Graduate School underwent a reorganization and the Graduate Council was reestablished. The council is still active, meeting monthly during the academic year. Collection consists of memos, proposals, reports, and minutes of the Indiana University Graduate Council.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f58533e6b3893d98b58830cac53140ac">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_35ee56cc4e9f12532c70eb97fe18c074">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bc2b6c008d1f4bac83caa5435e26addd">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>In an effort to direct the growing number of students undertaking graduate studies at Indiana University, a standing Committee on Advanced Degrees was established in1894. All applications went through this committee of six faculty members, and graduate work was under the immediate control of the committee. On May 15, 1902, the committee, then chaired by Professor Carl H. Eigenmann, recommended the establishment of a graduate school, "in order to give dignity and coherence to the graduate work." The school was to be headed by an administrative board consisting of seven department chairs, with the university's vice president serving as ex officio chairman or dean. The administrative board was expected to perform the functions of the current Committee on Advanced Degrees.</p><p> Formal organization of the Graduate School was authorized by the faculty in 1904, with the continued governance by the Committee on Advanced Degrees until the office of Dean was created in 1908. This Committee was reorganized as the Administrative Committee of the Graduate School, and in 1909 it became the Graduate Council.</p><p> The Graduate Council continued to administer and oversee the school, including issuing recommendations to the Dean who acted on the Council's behalf. Meetings were held upon the call of the Dean to consider questions pertaining to admission requirments, advanced degrees, and various other problems relating to the administration of the school. The Council grew until each department offering graduate courses had a representative sitting at the table. In 1934, the Board of Trustees approved President Bryan's recommendation for recognizing the Graduate School faculty. Prior to this change, faculty members had been listed in some of the catalogs, but were not given official standing and authority as faculty of the School. With this change, the Council was deemed unnecessary and was disbanded.</p><p> With the retirement of Dean Fernandus Payne and John W. Ashton's interim appointment as Dean of the Graduate School in 1947, discussions began on the reorganization of the school. Upon the appointment of Stith Thompson as the new Dean, a new organizational structure was established. Within this structure, all faculty teaching graduate level courses would report to their respective school deans, and the school deans would report to a newly formed Graduate Council chaired by the Dean of the Graduate School. The Council also included the Assistant Dean and nine elected faculty, who served a three year term on the Council and were eligible for re-election.</p><p> This new Council elected its first members in time for the 1951-1952 academic year. They were charged with reviewing and modernizing the course curriculum, establishing procedures for administration of student programs, and reviewing graduation and admissions requirements.</p><p> As of 2007, there are thirty-six active members on the Council.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_738d28f0daeb3e0bb7c5784f1f932e90">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized into two series: Minutes and Administrative files.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_26e6651d07684aee59fd067bddea1fe6">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The records of the Graduate Council are organized into two series, Minutes for the period from 1900 to 2003 and Administrative files, spanning the years from 1901 to 2005. Oversized materials are indicated as such in the folder list and stored in Box 2.</p><p> The most prominent series of this collection is Minutes, which is comprised of the recorded minutes of the Graduate Council and its predecessor, the Committee on Advanced Degrees. Although the Committee was established in 1894, they did not begin recording minutes until their October 2, 1900, meeting. There is a complete run of minutes from 1900 up until the dissolution of the group in the 1930s. The minutes resume with the reestablishment of the group in 1951, but the Archives does not hold the minutes for the period from 1981 to 1999. Council minutes for 2000-2003 have been collected from the Graduate Council web site. Prominent topics include discussions on the reorganization of the Graduate School, new degree programs, administration of graduate programs on all of the Indiana University campuses, curriculum revisions, and admissions requirements for all graduate programs. The series is arranged in chronological order.</p><p> The Administrative files series span the years 1901-2005, but the bulk of the records date from the 1950s. Included in the series are lists of elected council members from 1956, 1962, and 2004-2005. Researchers will also find memos, administrative structure information, and proposals and reports of the Council. A prominent subject in the proposals and reports files is language requirements for the various graduate programs. The series is arranged in chronological order.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_a4a4ff6b71ebfd9db8dfb6e4d8f5dda4">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Duplicates exceeding 3 copies have been removed from this collection.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_55151432f38995b4b02298858dbe75fd">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accessions 5117, 0364; 0545</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_29d53c2ceec16e1f5960a6fbb93c9ecb">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_789f43ee482a455a9dbe579cd4bd53cd">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana University Graduate Council records, Collection C278, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5d890a8c038874da5cfc35436242a99b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Kristen Walker; revised by Dina Kellams.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2006" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2006</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges --Graduate work.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges --Indiana.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Committee on Advanced Degrees --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Committee on Advanced Degrees --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Committee on Advanced Degrees --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Committee on Advanced Degrees --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Committee on Advanced Degrees --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Committee on Advanced Degrees --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Administrative Committee --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Administrative Committee --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Administrative Committee --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Graduate Council --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Graduate Council --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Graduate Council --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Graduate School. Graduate Council --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Graduate School. Graduate Council --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Graduate School. Graduate Council --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Research and the University Graduate School. Graduate Council --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Research and the University Graduate School. Graduate Council --History --20th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Research and the University Graduate School. Graduate Council --History --21st century --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. University Graduate School. Graduate Council --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. University Graduate School. Graduate Council --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. University Graduate School. Graduate Council --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Graduate work --History --20th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Graduate work --History --21st century --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Committee on Advanced Degrees.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Committee on Advanced Degrees.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Administrative Committee.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Graduate School. Graduate Council.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Graduate School. Graduate Council.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Research and the University Graduate School. Graduate Council.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_7f289acaeb944528ec16072795bcdd77" level="series"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1900/2003" type="inclusive">1900-2003</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_b627a02ff2444e4403535591bbc3d377" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1900/1913" type="inclusive">1900-1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_88a311551d668f8a44c2c8a6e4c2165e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f9510f3bf83efd9045380d3cf86eca21" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1911/1930" type="inclusive">1911-1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_9586ea71f3b6741812d8ab68d13ad4f8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_6ddb40a05e5c135e75d5017e163e4b75"><head>General</head><p>Oversized – in Box 2</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_99ffce52b870c246024c1588394bd201" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1930/1935" type="inclusive">1930-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf7bd1cb492a380eead9938b5234b306" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_b0671a38e4c941c331ae0383c184f5a6"><head>General</head><p>Oversized – in Box 2</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_c9a818b6d8c0a014e1488832a8e4e214" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951/1952" type="inclusive">1951-1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a1af8ee48845d465bb7a93c0c8daa39" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_68ef9634adb88a651f427cf3cad51b8e" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1952/1953" type="inclusive">1952-1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd1b9867e15f9a12443170bed095fa5c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_10309c5889aac84e038bcbf6588fb00a" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1953/1954" type="inclusive">1953-1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_0268c0f67f5d8d0a4aa3ff5a2e5fcea3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7c8e29791e14d64070fcc38d422c0daf" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1954/1955" type="inclusive">1954-1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a983e910d07a6427572c93299902f36" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d98bb3ef8a68ab05d18cf8621e3a4836" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1955/1956" type="inclusive">1955-1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_be8d670f7bfc614a60318d4edd05ec1d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_920d156a83b880f785e2433a11e925e1" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1956/1957" type="inclusive">1956-1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a0eb2b141429676b0d11fe80a94cfd3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8d2ae6185269837d92c5767f00d49ddf" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1957/1958" type="inclusive">1957-1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4fe4f5d8ee2508cb3740de999ff6e08" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8a77c9f57c4a66552ccc74a8802dca5f" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1958/1959" type="inclusive">1958-1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b7a1568f1df852e6ec88d3668a86f74" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_85e3e3226c3bd07faceeb2befd921ea5" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1959/1960" type="inclusive">1959-1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_565aac4a5604175d12cd8e9980413352" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1f8a64410edb1aa9ebb8215431186e2b" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1960/1961" type="inclusive">1960-1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_1442f4266e34f5f323f7d51ac3c72376" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f6f3b765feab67cf94fb71c583555435" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1961/1962" type="inclusive">1961-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_532e528a103cf25daed8f1f4caf539f0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_998e8295abb0736c6433a0daa6d1f15f" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1962/1963" type="inclusive">1962-1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4b3947fd8ecbd051d3d41ef8cdf4425" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_912935da596622621c021840a8b0c63b" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1963/1964" type="inclusive">1963-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ce1073c9a1ceb0ea4211268e21d2657" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f51c251c2dff443aebd9af87f6ee5a4f" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1964/1965" type="inclusive">1964-1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_07e7cc5945978dfed85f8109d78f7bfe" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3c845b0f4e1471068a0d61f592038509" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_2af660ef6b72ba121e9b94464df14f95" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_900bd656c971e333b4b4e13eab2c8c2e" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1966/1967" type="inclusive">1966-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1344bba3906b527b63b80c9f768e40c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_979895908c0c502dd4ab29e2d9760b53" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_4668ff148000b0fd64a60b10f34dd934" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7f95bfc5f13cf2993b3aea1728148f30" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0e2469dd1f99d1cf4f87ddcef0bd65d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_93af4b1e282ef7d09b2f7e0098b4fd43" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6b2f7caded6a9846a8b83a4a73147e4" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_05f518f9a97ae8aa07fd21c90c8b8c14" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_7eeb16608abfade089b598c5056dffd7" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1bc720fac16d40b72178bb1f900500e6" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_df9a7c6e7260afae0f735e9c28a86bcb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9f2847eb45131141e350c783f81b9d19" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_590c1727b2bb2bd7a43dbd9ecccc2cd8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3599f34c4a95fcad6ab9b8dd61d4c3f1" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f8cbccc7b35a959487d51d6d538d016" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e63faf5067408615be99562ebc8dbba0" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">1974-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_d8f22bd8310b64f75a5ac843da3b9f3e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2c1f1f8ba1ed89327b62440c278ab49" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_830901ff47ab9713638f391ef140647e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2b3e30d460f04ee7f0cb3a8fc3c54ff2" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a9da548c9adc8cbc240224afc819cf0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8d10ce0f70152cd9655aec93947994c4" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1977/1978" type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e2a4ceee88426f0dcda21b2ecb0f1e1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_36f734eaaff4c59a3b2feb2ab14cb131" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_59be6404c0f8471c58c41688b412a2aa" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fc4fc87fb4bc1b72a632d4028dc0f16b" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3af5bbe8a90cf82612c7569846364a7" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ddb00db434a43e85006d70557e04234b" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2000/2000">2000</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ad6a249956ae4821dfbab293da12568" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_27c756108d0f4e2c901d2aca4ae8cd9e" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2000/2001" type="inclusive">2000-2001</unitdate><container id="aspace_29e5fc229a8b630dcb646259b063ac50" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5b85428fdc6b5545610875b086905714" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2001/2002" type="inclusive">2001-2002</unitdate><container id="aspace_59baf45d4dc56eabc227caddf82a8747" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_58cfe5c103a29120d7ed1ed666f79f8e" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2002/2003" type="inclusive">2002-2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d080f261bb1ec8013b1c3e97fe6746a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a84be1af5f0017054d9b3c18fbd69224" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2003/2003">2003</unitdate><container id="aspace_5bd51976a9bcc329df0e747ef7911d6a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_9d3a9bc5a216982092c768a03399d89b" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1901/1920" type="inclusive">1902-1920</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1950/1969" type="inclusive">1950-1969</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2004/2005" type="inclusive">2004-2005</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_1f351df550c8a2441ec3e2f9aff55f9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Committee on Advanced Degrees report recommending establishment of a graduate school</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902-05-15/1902-05-15">15 May 1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_643cb8032efd74a41cdccfb03ce86791" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_07329bf317873255a6da65fcb19aba69" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence – Claghorn, Henry T.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1908-06-09/1908-06-09">9 June 1908</unitdate><container id="aspace_94954fa1f58be48de50559eeb1a2b147" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_15b8da44f56e9442dbf23d33014c1f86" level="file"><did><unittitle>Notes on history of the Council</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1910/1911" type="inclusive">1910-1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_09fa420a544db93be3bba89c3c0ae064" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9705d99866d194e22a23e24fc8418ba3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carl H. Eigenmann memo re: Fellowships</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1911-06-05/1911-06-05">5 June 1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_cde702f81fb51a406e4d9ed3463fa2bc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_7ff30f528287cf77569c6b7d23613e6e"><head>General</head><p>Oversized – in Box 2</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_5a806c7030a033a01d2e68f47fd88da2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fellowship information, esp. State Scholarships</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1911/1920" type="inclusive">1911-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_2bba6d58f10494b1b8feb4512d5637b9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3b8336382e193e0081395cfc7bd27e7c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memos</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1950-01/1959-12" type="inclusive">1950s</unitdate><container id="aspace_e833156cfc2c62a86af67b582a9c3943" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e54ddedb55fba453a88af43d048f0875" level="file"><did><unittitle>Organization of the Graduate School</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951/1951">circa 1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_07db9d459ce9a32082a7b8b76fcde17b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9d65a41a683c3a580155649143c9b4ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Preliminary Report of the Committee on the Training and Preparation of College Teachers</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_85844b6b56bce381df68c53097cb6460" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_22a34fe049c3ee2e37255b687e5a69e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Report of the Graduate School to the Faculty Council</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1955-05/1955-05">May 1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9083543237a616d351b762bd4cce7ae" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3185b6e50378208ad97c97a622ccb87f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposed Change to Policy re. Graduate Work Done Off-campus</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1955/1955">circa 1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbf16d8fa35563e64b2d167093ab124f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e9f0a69486433d37919c5c106289d3c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Members of the Graduate School Faculty and</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_dcce105552006a6f70120407261fb972" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0de0b51a4d764347ac8f0f00ea6f02c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Report of the Curriculum Committee</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1956-04-26/1956-04-26">26 April 1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_196ea836e204ba07978856c223eb4986" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b74750f476e6a4bf7377eb13e42856bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal for the Coordination of the Graduate Program at Indiana University</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1957-02/1957-02">Feb. 1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a9399062f7d125e995aaadc29235826" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ba8efacfefa3099b88b8ad26e3eb128f" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Association of Graduate Schools, Report of the Committee on Policies in Graduate Education</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_a339fb331b52be788b4b3041be429935" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_82d1b6f66be86a0e9b2593b5d8290942" level="file"><did><unittitle>Committee on Language Requirements for the Ph.D. Degree Report</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1958/1958">circa 1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e3daa572fa8d90a0f76db4c4499c053" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1cf0212596271cdca1a9ca0b81a4573f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal for Integration of Graduate Work</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdaed82ad98012b114e1c6be915179fc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_efb564ce3df44f769a18ab50ce42bbfb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memos</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1960-01/1969-12" type="inclusive">1960s</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6c6e93e2feb76248e4a8e6896a7e245" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b10b5d86d3569601ceca280159fa6f88" level="file"><did><unittitle>Graduate School Committee "B" Report and Recommendations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e6863f25781fd9e36c47ed26410fcde" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_da34c4e2ed477340ab373dd030b81846" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal A and B</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1967/1967">circa 1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_19d6f558f308b9827b4b3488c9b06585" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fd4bd7dfea0c1153318692bef2b9b8a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Members of the Graduate Council</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2004/2005" type="inclusive">2004-2005</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0d0869dfecfa0f8bd1f7b9ea91809c6" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_84d7b802b5ff7d0c8e1397145bdc37dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposed Revision to Graduate Council Statement on Foreign Language Requirements</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1900/2005" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3087b36d0bbedd70a6f98d9831d8ba0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c8c3dd5a8e4e918dd100d8385d7b11e3" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="oversized"><did><unittitle>Oversized materials</unittitle><container id="aspace_bcf656b3e609d4c6ffb98b6946f87191" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
