<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA2758</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Danilo Orescanin speeches, <date normal="1976/1983" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1976-1983</date> <num>C225</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to his Speeches at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Kristen R. Sanders</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2003</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:52:58 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>December 22, 2003</date><item>Edited finding aid to be consistent with others.</item></change><change><date>July 18, 2003</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>July 23, 2003</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>November 3, 2003</date><item>Doc Type Declaration revised.</item></change><change><date>May 4, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Danilo Orescanin speeches</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C225</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.2 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">1976-1983</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1979" type="bulk">1976-1979</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_48874bf9f29a177f2ff97f50d7091842">Danilo Orescanin was a long time administrator associated with Indiana University in a variety of administrative roles. This collection contains speech files from his time as Chancellor of IU Northwest between 1976 and 1983.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_6aeff5d6fcf27295b809ec7064f2d128">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_972dd08091e5b8ea711ee0e539122c17">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_92910849dfc609589dfdfde0d2ee8020">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Danilo Orescanin served Indiana University in a number of different capacities during his career, most notably as Chancellor of the Northwest campus and subsequently as Vice President for University Relations. In both positions, he spoke frequently to university and community groups, and worked to strengthen I.U.'s relationship with the community at large.</p><p> Orescanin was born 7 April 1932 in Mingo Junction, Ohio, to George and Nellie (Kukich) Orescanin; his father had come to the United States from Serbia at the age of nineteen. Orescanin earned a bachelor's degree in business administration from West Virginia University in 1953 and an M.B.A. from Indiana University in 1954. He became an industrial engineer at Colgate-Palmolive in Jeffersonville, Indiana; was drafted into the army, in which he served in 1955 and 1956; and returned to I.U. to pursue a doctorate in business in 1957. By the time he received his doctorate in 1960, he had already had a taste of administrative work, having served as administrative assistant to the Dean of the School of Business.</p><p> Orescanin became an Assistant Professor of Business at the University of South Florida in Tampa in 1960, where he also served as Assistant Coordinator of Evening and Summer Sessions. In 1963 he returned to Indiana University as Assistant Dean of the Division of University Extension. Over the next nine years, he performed a variety of administrative functions for the University and held appointments first as an assistant and then as an associate professor of business. He was acting director of the Southeast campus from April to August of 1965, following the sudden death of Dr. Byron K. Laird. In the fall of 1965, Orescanin went to Dacca, Pakistan to establish a new graduate program at the Institute of Business Administration, Dacca University, serving as Resident Advisor until 1967. He returned to I.U. and served first as Assistant Dean and later Associate Dean of Research of Advanced Studies, meanwhile serving as Acting Director of Data Systems and Services. In 1969, he was appointed Assistant to President Joseph L. Sutton and Associate Dean for Administration, and continued as Assistant to President John W. Ryan until he was invited to follow David R. Derge to Southern Illinois University following the latter's appointment as president there early in 1972.</p><p> Orescanin served as Derge's executive assistant at S.I.U. from February to July of 1972, when he became Vice President for Administration and Campus Treasurer. Between July 1973 and March 1974, he also held the position of Executive Vice President. However, in late February 1974, Orescanin called Derge's attention to procedural irregularities in the use of some $5,000 from the Southern Illinois University Foundation to buy alcohol for presidential functions. As the accounts were under his control, Orescanin resigned from his administrative duties and requested reassignment to a full-time teaching and research position in the business school, which Derge granted. Orescanin was charged with tampering with public records by a grand jury of Jackson County, Illinois, but was acquitted. </p><p> Orescanin began his term as Chancellor of Indiana University Northwest in the fall semester of 1975. At that time, according to a routine review of Orescanin's performance conducted in the fall of 1981, the financial and physical conditions of the campus, the morale of the faculty, and the community's attitude toward the campus were all poor. This review credits Orescanin with "[turning] things around at IUN" through "a clear understanding of what IUN should be, patience, tact, consummate skill in working with diverse community groups, and sound fiscal and managerial policies." The review describes a leadership style that emphasized communication and the delegation of responsibility to others. He seems to have had an image among the faculty as a manager, rather than an academic, but was able nevertheless to develop a good relationship with the faculty as a whole.</p><p> The review notes his efforts in working with the community as a particular strength, which his extensive involvement with a large number of community organizations supports. He served in leadership roles in the Gary Chamber of Commerce (President, 1977-79; Board Member, 1975-at least 1981), the local chapter of the American Red Cross (1976-at least 1981), the Urban League (1975-79), the St. Mary Medical Center (1976-at least 1981), the Lake County Chapter of the Mental Health Association (President beginning in 1981, other leadership positions from 1977-81), and the Northwest Association of Commerce and Industry (1979-at least 1981), and was active in a number of other organizations, including several scholarship committees and the Chicago District of the President's White House Fellowship Committee (1978-79). As campaign chairman of the local United Way, he set a fundraising record in 1981. He was awarded a National Award for outstanding contributions and service by the Association of Teacher Educators in 1979, the first time the award was ever given to a non-education faculty member. </p><p> In June 1983, Orescanin was appointed Vice President for University Relations. In this capacity, he oversaw the News Bureau, and the offices of University Publications, Community Relations, and Special Events, as well as the offices of University Relations at all campuses, and implemented programs intended to create a strong statewide image for I. U. He served in this position until January 1, 1988, when he returned to teaching management and business policy classes in the business school. In 1992, he was given the Otteson Undergraduate Teaching Excellence Award. He retired in December 1992, and died 22 May 1999 at the age of 67 in Tampa, Florida. Orescanin and his wife, Kathleen, had a son, Danilo II, and a daughter, Lori, both of whom earned degrees from I.U.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_decd9e35dd142fd1946364d379d3dc56">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is organized into one series, Indiana University Northwest Chancellor Speeches. They are arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_93d962607130683c28be023565e6caf9">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection consists of speeches given by Danilo Orescanin during his tenure as Chancellor of the Northwest campus; the material is arranged chronologically. Nearly half of the speeches were given to campus groups, such as the Faculty Organization, or at university functions, such as graduation ceremonies and new student orientation. A number of others were given to community organizations, including some that he served in such as the Gary Chamber of Commerce, and others to which he was invited as a guest, such as an elementary school dedication. Perhaps most notably given Orescanin's desire to increase interaction between the campus and community, several were given at community functions hosted by the university, such as the Spring Arts Festival, a high school counselors' meeting, and the Humanities Seminar for High School Students. The items range from polished drafts to handwritten notes, with some falling in between; a few are statements written by Orescanin to be read at certain functions in his absence. The collection also includes some correspondence and programs relating to the functions at which he spoke, as well as information for references which Orescanin seems to have kept in his speech file so that he could use them in future speeches.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_0fe5421c0745c63f2c17d2916f04cc6a">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Newsletter articles removed and filed in the clippings files under Orescanin, Danilo.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_257ebe2b989be7ec4c57e0328511f2af">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>See also Collection C226, Danilo Orescanin speeches. These are speech files from Orscanin's term as Vice-President for University Relations between 1983 and 1987.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_0c870d719f0a1ece51e53f60d8a04c99">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession 8221.</p><p> Material was also integrated into this collection from Collection #29, Records of Assistant Vice-President James L. Green.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_763f18a2df339bf99dff1b1abb87ef5e">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c54b1b562865fe128c3df48b7e2be9da">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Danilo Orescanin speeches, Collection C225, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_f858b8803ba23c956546a03ca63dcf1b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Elizabeth Rytting</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2003" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">College orations --Indiana University Northwest.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College administrators --Indiana --Gary --Speeches.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College administrators --Indiana --Gary --Archives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College administrators --Indiana --Gary --Correspondence.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University Northwest. Office of the Chancellor --History --20th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo --Speeches.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo. Speeches. Selections.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_30136c4a976d8ac34803e8c1a4cbb3e6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Chancellor's speeches</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">1976-1983</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_28784ddd32f8fa7892bb0788b4429823" level="file"><did><unittitle>SPEA Minority Fellows Program</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976-01-23/1976-01-23">23 Jan 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_47fd698bca7fc45a9358741cea155501" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dfd17105f252627fc23aff0749653ffc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Urban League Installation Dinner</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976-01-24/1976-01-24">24 Jan 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_08ad202b8be7e1c34f3be97f2b8285b9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9f4516c7cc5044316f4f236efb37cd72" level="file"><did><unittitle>Spring Arts Festival</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976-06-05/1976-06-05">5 Jun 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b576d3d15f6ee431364536a2b3df578" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_eeb499051366431c85a56ced396aa953" level="file"><did><unittitle>School of Dentistry Graduation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976-08-20/1976-08-20">20 Aug 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_b36ecf3ff74b61f0e07a9ee81e77518f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d7d8c49eb6ba9a6ced627f3139df03f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>IUNW Segment—State of University Address</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976-09/1976-09">ca. Sep 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_3856bc9ebe915f32d24b2a987196dd97" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7c88708849db66018bfb531544540109" level="file"><did><unittitle>High School Counselors meeting</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976-10-01/1976-10-01">1 Oct 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_13008a23af61ee4a6db04adc2c3ed027" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_953f0db02adf5d0707c7f986fb746d14" level="file"><did><unittitle>IUNW Faculty Organization</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976-10/1976-10">Oct 1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b71f4678ea2865fe2ba9562ca89f9f4" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c59256935391f20aaa3186cd473be17c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Untitled (possibly to a faculty Organization)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">ca. 1976-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_099ddc89df6963809f57868d71377276" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4678dc9e00c5eeb4175e3bc377d1dc24" level="file"><did><unittitle>Luncheon for Jessie Smith</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1977-05-06/1977-05-06">6 May 1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d52c64a2da3d0a3477598d5510978cb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2020de3eaaabbf3017df6c7f1238c629" level="file"><did><unittitle>Untitled (re: budget)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978/1978">ca. 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f24867fa076db21e2b4882c59f97757" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1c1edaad9f42ea5514156f06eafbee89" level="file"><did><unittitle>Humanities Seminar for High School Students</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978-03-10/1978-03-10">10 Mar 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e06a93c8fb2ec3f05156c99acdb5bf8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_01aa82585b984a5bd1e913d0d439ff98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Open House</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978-04-29/1978-04-29">29 Apr 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_78e66d5f283769ecc0f6dc61d4195bd9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ab5596b7da422e858d4c5eda2a82dbdf" level="file"><did><unittitle>IUNW Alumni Association</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978-05-10/1978-05-10">10 Jun 1978 (?)</unitdate><container id="aspace_279a7d56a90d439a40697506c061e5ac" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_02ea0f31d7022458f5679d5492b711a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>New Student Orientation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978-08-11/1978-08-11">11 Aug 1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_c293f33fd11926a94e340e1f55bfa2f1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_542595e32a323bf01d1caf323ce00569" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference for Students in Social Studies</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979-05-05/1979-05-05">5 May 1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_29ed5b9894cda56a2df30b746018f9c5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fe471f552f39243d1be91e1981241ec1" level="file"><did><unittitle>School of Dentistry Graduation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979-05-18/1979-05-18">18 May 1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_fdc2b5b06500bcfa7c479f06e2c8a62c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d5112b0ce03c1cad0159783678abed0e" level="file"><did><unittitle>James H. Watson Elementary School Dedication</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979-05-20/1979-05-20">20 May 1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_311c565a89dc2024ab36d0b4a26ee0f8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_609abd2583dd1393e823f31567968064" level="file"><did><unittitle>National Honor Society—River Forest High School</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980-03-18/1980-03-18">18 Mar 1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_70404a52a542638eb7cfb17bef1ec7a6" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_87183805dc863d8f1bc67beb86100c91" level="file"><did><unittitle>Information for speeches re: science majors at IUNW</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980-08-04/1980-08-04">4 Aug 1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d674db968124fe30d83cdb695c1d17f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_457e23cf3c08925f7fc65190d3cbff5a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Untitled (re: state of Northwest campus)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1981-09/1981-09">ca. Sep. 1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_bba45810f5c06e6b91342b7a1a48bbba" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_350e8d8a88fc2cf07b2ec19d6909e6c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Untitled (re: economic status of Gary)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1982-01/1982-02" type="inclusive">ca. Jan-Feb 1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_33b0be8a0f125437270162824b18b4ab" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_90f840c954f64c9cbd8bf4aee08fd41e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lake County Community Development Committee</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1983-01-13/1983-01-13">13 Jan 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_b99fa026d255d26166ffe64d47ab62ec" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9a5001db648f28b6fe09cec56286d783" level="file"><did><unittitle>St. George Serbian Church Graduation Luncheon</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1983-06-05/1983-06-05">5 Jun 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_cbb9d2feb3287c42a55a591050f68e2d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a966de11f31110f1f5467183e8b94c5f" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="doublequote">Commencement is a Beginning</emph></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_596e2fd01fd869b4f492f3e8602912a9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_044424ccc50d2b0d310193b0d9d6a04c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gary Chamber of Commerce</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_94a4c429a6020372da5e583b8bbdf614" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7fe6d70037f14cfc72c3d172bcf63675" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="doublequote">Indiana University Northwest—Your University"</emph></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_69053ee6baada9ff7275c4aa02cd7672" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7a6b64f714d9ad128dff0433926d1f32" level="file"><did><unittitle>Omicron Sigma Delta initiation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb70cba897efd16328c7bc3843ccb3d7" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_807effc9f4e52a6301dde32fffecb5d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Omicron Sigma Delta Honor Society</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3583ad9ca7e07d14b89307f52526304" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7ce0697814784b56414f4622e6807a98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Untitled (re: cancer research at I.U. School of Medicine)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c23f05e9e7f404f890e5de2078902fe" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c5460b0ab570c8c9ad052d6751f6fcce" level="file"><did><unittitle>Untitled (welcome to unspecified regional meeting)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8cf083be0c608dc7ef255b18d4576886" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_df38adc6965675349ce521c263cf5ea4" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="doublequote">Women and Leadership</emph>Delta Kappa Gamma</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_9cd8ee7e09cc9d0fcb270f2839b9b0c3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
