<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAC0929</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Ward Gray Biddle Campaign papers, <date normal="1932/1933">1932-1933</date> <num>C279</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to his papers at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Elia Van Lith.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2010</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2010">© 2010</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:15:22 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ward Gray Biddle Campaign papers</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Biddle, Ward Gray, 1891-1946.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C279</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5a9328e0166015f1e374cc77990ae12a">Indiana University administrator Ward Gray Biddle's political career began in 1930 when he was elected to the Indiana state legislature as a Democratic representative from Monroe County, a position he held for the 1931 General Assembly session. In 1932 he was elected to the State Senate from Brown, Greene, and Monroe Counties and served for two more sessions of the General Assembly (1933 and 1935) and two special sessions (1932 and 1936). This collection consists of correspondence, maps, and voter information from Biddle's successful first campaign for the state senate seat from Brown, Greene, and Monroe Counties.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_026e6a45f5848f89d60f510cf668dfa4">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_466132099c11c78d743ae8f7be8504e9">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_c7beb95f9a98e00626d298bbca4f5974">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Ward Gray Biddle was born on March 23, 1891, on a farm in Adams Township, Madison County, Indiana. He first came to IU in 1912 as an economics major, and after graduating in 1916 he returned to Madison County and went to work in the banking business. Biddle was married to Dona Ruth Roberts, an IU graduate (B.A. 1929) and teacher from Oxford, Indiana, on June 3, 1917. The couple had two daughters: Elizabeth, born in 1918, and Nancy, born in 1920. In 1923 Biddle returned to the Bloomington, Indiana, campus to take over management of the University Bookstore, first moving it from the basement of the Library to a temporary structure near the center of campus, and from there into custom-designed quarters in the newly constructed Indiana Memorial Union, quarters largely designed by Biddle. That year, 1932, he was elected by the Board of Trustees as the first Director of the Union. He was a life member of both the Association of College Unions and National Association of College Stores.</p><p> In 1936 Biddle was promoted to University Comptroller, making him responsible for the financial operations of the entire university. That same year he helped found the I.U. Foundation, serving on its board of directors for years. Following a campus-wide reorganization in 1942 his title was changed to that of vice-president and treasurer, a position he held until his death. During the 1930s and 1940s Biddle oversaw the construction of the buildings for the Schools of Dentistry and Music, Bloomington's School of Medicine, the Business, Economics, and University School (now the Simon Music Library and Recital Center) buildings, North and West Halls (now Cravens and Edmonson Halls), Beech and Forest Halls (now Morrison and Goodbody Halls), Sycamore Hall, Swain Hall, the Services building (now the School of Journalism), and the Administration building (now Bryan Hall). Probably the most significant addition to the campus during this period was the million-dollar Auditorium finished in 1941. </p><p> As head of university financial affairs Biddle was responsible for several innovations in the business administration of Indiana University, including: centralization of purchasing for all departments into one office; establishment of a student fund to provide central banking and uniform accounting systems for students and student groups; creation of a Safety Department; establishment of the Personnel Division for non-academic personnel; expansion of the staff group insurance plan; creation of the non-academic staff retirement program; and establishment of a central storeroom for the supplies of all departments.</p><p> Biddle's political career began in 1930 when he was elected to the Indiana state legislature as a Democratic representative from Monroe County, a position he held for the 1931 General Assembly session. In 1932 he was elected to the State Senate from Brown, Greene, and Monroe Counties and served for two more sessions of the General Assembly (1933 and 1935) and two special sessions (1932 and 1936). During these years he served on numerous committees, including County and Township Business and Military Affairs as a representative, and Judiciary C, Libraries and Public Buildings, Mines and Mining, and Railroads, Banks and Trust Companies as a senator. He also served as chairman of the Committees on Education and Finance.</p><p> During World War II Biddle worked to make Indiana University a part of the war effort and was instrumental in executing the emergency housing program implemented following the return of many veterans to campus in 1945. Ward Biddle passed away on May 28, 1946.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_75e95065f51ffd10e5dc469a58d282e0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection is organized in a single series, Campaign papers, arranged alphabetically by folder title.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_28b8bcc97ab7c229d2051206412e49b8">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Ward Gray Biddle Campaign papers 1932-1933, are arranged alphabetically by folder title and include correspondence, three issues of the <title render="italic">Indiana University Democrat</title>, Bloomington maps delineating voting districts, student enrollment lists, student voter lists, and voter materials from Biddle's successful first campaign for the state senate seat from Brown, Greenee, and Monroe Counties.</p><p> The correspondence consists of two short letters written in October 1932 from Herman B Wells concerning the campaign and two undated handwritten letter drafts by Biddle. Jackson Club materials consist of an invitation (Oct. 31, 1932) from Jackson Club President Bob Ritchie to attend a meeting where members of the local Democratic Party will be introduced and what appear to be two blank organizational charts documenting the Jackson Club's role in manning polling stations during the upcoming election. The voters' materials consist of blank Indiana Voter's Affidavits, Democratic pamphlets, a sample ballot provided compliments of Biddle, and a flyer warning against the use of the <emph render="doublequote">100 per cent</emph> slogan by State and National Democrats.</p><p> One oversize campaign poster has been filed separately.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_0a4db074d241fbc7bfb37010967c07a1">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>One oversized election poster is stored separately.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_64f873024e4b908558149fc417983c22">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession number 0730.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9612c5247a2a892b066f2a0d30d4f929">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_9440a70ef195b272bc58265da9a99e06">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Ward Gray Biddle Campaign papers, Collection C279, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_ea72399e43828bb1750e894f892fbbe5">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Elia Van Lith.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2004">2004</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political campaigns --Indiana.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political candidates --Indiana.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Elections --Indiana.</subject>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Indiana --Politics and government --20th century.</geogname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Biddle, Ward Gray, 1891-1946 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Biddle, Ward Gray, 1891-1946 --Correspondence.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAC0929-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Subject files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate><unitdate normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_875bd18acbcfd2056e684c2218b5c852" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><container id="aspace_c8cbcdd8306bf17998bf336924325112" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Indiana University Democrat</title>, vol. I, nos. 2-4</unittitle><unitdate normal="1932/1932">1932</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f283aa0e2a288a6b0ba91a0b63d347c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jackson Club</unittitle><container id="aspace_eb5c5270c8d188e603e0aa62dc88341d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle>Maps delineating voting districts – Bloomington and Perry Townships</unittitle><container id="aspace_383a69602e2f4d5a65a19adb0fd3262f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle>Student enrollment lists</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_8e97ba358b68106e88c64320e8f36671">(3 folders)</physdesc><container id="aspace_8be6d1003fa08f305b0d4c373b7b2df9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00007" level="file"><did><unittitle>Student voters, Bloomington and Perry Townships</unittitle><container id="aspace_37aaeeea070f8d65555d7e709018b49e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC0929-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle>Democratic</unittitle><container id="aspace_e19a722001f60d40ce01458ade46f609" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC0929-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle>Democratic women</unittitle><container id="aspace_36fca2b2cdde9cc1d504d61144f7a9a8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC0929-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle>Republican</unittitle><container id="aspace_b14d316174e1398bf2d4bec19336c1c5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00011" level="file"><did><unittitle>Student voters by district</unittitle><container id="aspace_a14502ad73d45a4e7a1d13de216a8f70" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC0929-00012" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bloomington Township</unittitle><container id="aspace_85a51222491bcd0c3eef8f4332e00033" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC0929-00013" level="file"><did><unittitle>Perry Township</unittitle><container id="aspace_cefd01f4175c12c18e36c6875d21e9b2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC0929-00014" level="file"><did><unittitle>Voters' materials</unittitle><container id="aspace_ff0357dbe1cde6acb2e790eb723d7f3e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
