<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAC8992</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Kabul University Administration Program records, <date normal="1964/1972">1964-1972 </date> <num>C498</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Alison Reynolds</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2013</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2013">© 2013</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:08:09 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>July 11, 2013</date><item>Encoded finding aid started.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>July 11, 2013</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kabul University Administration Program records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Office of Research and Advanced Studies.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C498</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1964/1972" type="inclusive">1964-1972</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1964/1972" type="bulk">1967-1972</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_bc952c2eab238da072a00a36388f49f6">The Kabul University Administration Program focused on improving the administrative structure, leadership, and business practices of Kabul University in Kabul, Afghanistan. Additional goals included revamping student services and activities offices, refining account management practices, improving conditions for female students, and further developing the university library's collections. The project was administered by the Office of Research and Advanced Studies and funded through a grant from USAID from 1966-1972.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_dd3c7ace4b042511606f035984741703">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language> and <language langcode="ara">Arabic</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1a577cd6bc4aceb2e6ea247161ac6b81">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0d082af54c7a4eea07e54f1985e6a613">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The Kabul University Administration Program focused on improving the administrative structure, leadership, and business practices of Kabul University in Kabul, Afghanistan. Additional goals included revamping student services and activities offices, refining account management practices, and further developing the university library's administration and collections. The project was administered by the Office of Research and Advanced Studies and funded through a grant from USAID from 1966-1972. The following faculty and staff from Indiana University served as team members in Kabul for this project: Dr. Chris W. Jung (Education) served as Chief of Party, Dr. Thomas C. Schreck (Dean of Students) served as Advisor in Student Affairs, Mr. Robert L. DeBard served as Advisor in Business Affairs, and Mrs. Barbara Louden served as secretary. Several additional faculty members also acted as short-term consultants throughout the course of the project. Dr. Taulman A. Miller (Economics) took over as Chief of Party in 1970.</p><p> The idea for the Afghanistan project began in January 1966 when Touryalai Etemadi, Rector of Kabul University, requested assistance from the United States Agency for International Development (USAID). USAID responded by sending Indiana University Chancellor Herman B Wells and Dr. Lynne Merritt, Vice President for Research and Dean of Advanced Studies, to conduct a survey in May 1966 in order to assess the types of assistance required by Kabul University and to decide whether or not IU would be an appropriate match for the project. After these preliminary surveys, a contract between Indiana University and USAID was created and signed on October 22, 1966.</p><p> Initial field reports in Afghanistan suggested that the primary areas for improvement at Kabul University included the organization of administrative positions and job descriptions, accounting procedures, student affairs, and the maintenance of building facilities and laboratories. At the time, it was customary for Kabul University to admit all students who applied and to provide free tuition, housing, and a small living stipend to all students. These practices led to problems with student overpopulation, such as lack of housing and lack of funds to support the large number of students, creating a need to reassess the criteria for student admission. In order to address these issues, the project goals focused on providing advice and assistance to the executive and management staff of Kabul University in order to develop more effective operations in university administration, student personnel services, and business administration. The project also included improvements to the university library by increasing acquisitions of books and periodicals and training staff in library science.</p><p> The initial contract allowed 4 members of the Kabul University personnel to attend Indiana University for a degree program in management and 4 more people to attend short-term participant training in Kabul. Additional representatives from Kabul were sent to Indiana University throughout the course of the project as it expanded. Overall, the project team sought to reorganize university administration so that a central administration would assume administrative and academic policy authority throughout the entire university. The project also resulted in advances for the women of Kabul University. Women were admitted to the university, but did not have adequate housing, advisors, or curriculum options. A 1967 Field Study Report by Robert DeBard states, "Promotion of feminism is the second program. Free the women from second class citizenship. An educated mother is an obvious asset to her children" (p. 36). As a result, additional instructors and advisors, increased housing, and an athletic program for women were developed during the course of the project.</p><p> Toward the later years of the project, political unrest and violence began to slow the project's progress. In 1971, students went on strike multiple times against faculty members across several departments. University-wide strikes sometimes occurred over issues such as changes in admissions policies. These strikes caused delays in classes ranging from weeks to months. Additional setbacks in 1971-1972 occurred as a result of unrest among students from dissenting religious groups. These sometimes escalated into violence, with one riot injuring between 35-40 students. Despite these setbacks, the project's final report indicated that progress was made to the university's administration and organization and conjectured that operations would continue to improve slowly over time if the same practices continued. Although this project was coming to a close, the Indiana University team advised that assistance from the U.S. was vital to Kabul University's development and recommended support for the university's leadership and administration for another 5 to 10 years in order for progress to continue.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_b5e07d92b0333a8e59b77215c173e8c0">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection is organized into three series: Administrative files, Correspondence, and Library</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_fc79455829d30e6c80892a89d6e9a915">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection is organized into three series: Administrative files, Correspondence, and Library.</p><p> The Administrative files series (1964-1972) contains papers relating to pre-contract surveys and project plans, semi-annual reports, observations and information about Afghani history and culture, and participant information for project members. It also includes budgets, purchasing information, and various reports and memos about the project's status and goals.</p><p> The Correspondence series (1966-1972) contains personal and professional correspondence from people involved with the project. Several folders describe the project's administrative details progress and goals.</p><p> The Library series (1967-1972) contains book orders, purchases, and requisitions, a card catalog from 1970, and correspondence related to the development of the Kabul University library.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_0b50967c166c6baa7bb405b2bbeaecf4">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Two copies of a photograph of Touryalai Etemadi, the former Rector of Kabul University, shaking hands with President Lyndon B. Johnson at the International Conference on the World Crisis in Education in 1967 were removed and transferred to the Archives Photograph Collection.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_29e7f6004f2380579641ff755ff969a2">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory: <extref xlink:href="http://institutionalmemory.iu.edu/aim/">http://institutionalmemory.iu.edu/aim/</extref> </p><p> Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database: <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/</extref> </p><p> Collection C488, the University of Islamabad Project records, contains a Reference series of reports, contracts, and books about international programs sponsored by other American universities that were used as reference materials for the international programs administered by Indiana University. Some of these files may have been used as reference materials for this program.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ed2288c24751e3a1a3f5e08055f8ce03">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession 0505</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3373b1ccc4fb402552401dcb1eb898bc">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_2a6c32bc12d21679dc761aef5fc66e4a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Kabul University Administration Program records, Collection C498, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <appraisal id="aspace_6499e950f53e35c984d8cc5d1f45eede">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>Items with information about personal bank accounts, blank travel voucher forms, and duplicate materials were discarded. Payroll information and requisitions were also discarded.</p>  </appraisal>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a2d8d1f1f626011e52eeecc3fa5645a2">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Alison Reynolds.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2013">2013</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher --Afghanistan --Kabul --History --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Academic libraries --Afghanistan --Kabul --History --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education, Higher --International cooperation.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Office of Research and Advanced Studies --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Office of Research and Advanced Studies --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Office of Research and Advanced Studies --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Kābul Pohantūn --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Kābul Pohantūn. Kitābkhānah-i Markazī --History --Sources.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAC8992-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1964/1972" type="inclusive">1964-1972</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>Absence Reports</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_ad56fd4c1e1543a485ca0be265b3838c" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00003" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Afghanistan</unittitle><container id="aspace_b76961ece12adf82ff7210453d4b6d9b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00004" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_e73444ab0bf94fdd78c298aeaaf1ccf7" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00005" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_1aebcb0c0aa9e71efe4a5d546bb03627" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><separatedmaterial id="aspace_57712e214204d4d19e185b93a9b07b77"><head>Separated Materials</head><p><emph render="bold">(2 photographs removed)</emph></p></separatedmaterial></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00006" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1965/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_5bc482d0b54fa8121dbde68e0009488e" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00007" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d0d42d2441661017d4b21d14f313de3" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00008" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2cd717d256403c7423d78d1923e4d5dd">(2 folders)</physdesc><container id="aspace_5dca6220ba68696627f709104767103b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00009" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4948b7000b6b2627350ce16725db40c" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle>Agency for International Development (AID)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1972" type="inclusive">1969-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_171f03d10d3d2a54df3d13dfbb7778b8" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00011" level="file"><did><unittitle>Banking</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5e256da03ff256ddec872c7719bff36" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00012" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Budget</unittitle><container id="aspace_ce1efc8858ee69ea73ce35903401cfb5" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00013" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c803a39f6908ac2f8611f93b028dcb4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00014" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_a60a596a30429fcef6d79b06ca18b852" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00015" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Consultants</unittitle><container id="aspace_9df1d73cb2739da175c68a7589d97f6e" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00016" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_caf7a10abd06e9fecc9349ba46751d70" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00017" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_a218ffd98bddf805968e12653fe874b4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00018" level="file"><did><unittitle>Contract</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_93823b99e0f8898c206d1f9749c51332" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00019" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Kabul</unittitle><container id="aspace_1934a02265d23ce24222ff34d878e980" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00020" level="file"><did><unittitle>After assignment; also general correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1969" type="inclusive">1966-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_837e96fb7475bfe18459d10e16da762f" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00021" level="file"><did><unittitle>Info re: Afghanistan customs, visa, travel regulations, misc, maps</unittitle><unitdate normal="1964/1967" type="inclusive">1964-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_23faf8214a6a844aefe9bf69e008e299" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00022" level="file"><did><unittitle>Robert DeBard</unittitle><unitdate normal="1967/1969" type="inclusive">1967-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_edbe0d8de9b38ebd7ac7125989d2f99b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00023" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Kabul University Administration Improvement Semi-Annual Reports</unittitle><container id="aspace_6d906336d9d5d353934bb2e5e89b4f55" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00024" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1966-11/1967-04" type="inclusive">November 1966-April 1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_ebc432eea252c85f51ae2f455b79480f" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00025" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1967-05/1967-10" type="inclusive">May-October 1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_8407c9c10178a20f984d2db280f2f436" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00026" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1967-11/1968-04" type="inclusive">November 1967-April 1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a6c3e9edd8b188b5972ea5020bd893e" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00027" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970-05/1970-10" type="inclusive">May 1970-October 1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_13425ac6c45f870ef271f775b4a3fbb7" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00028" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970-11/1971-04" type="inclusive">November 1970-April 1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_9edd99a06844686d52477b6503805e14" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00029" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971-05/1971-10" type="inclusive">May 1971-October 1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_d10e27944f0d9c1d142a547508fbf1db" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00030" level="file"><did><unittitle>Kabul University Business Affairs Office Report</unittitle><unitdate normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b00a16872bd88bdb2c830d4b2f7bfc6" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00031" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_fac55d8dad2432ec526046323200e816" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00032" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Participants</unittitle><container id="aspace_4d3f1e6a742b0c5d58b774fff1c39663" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00033" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd5e79e99dbbd9cee5ff0eb588dd70c7" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00034" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_eda39c6e0f850253c5c8ab1d23aebaf3" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00035" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Reports</unittitle><container id="aspace_f85ddfe6b148708f2df52f27c6cdbb51" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00036" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_459d4c73daedbd098b9d3355d9f10443" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00037" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c5051da3e9bf1c33757f55fc5154a80" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00038" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Requisitions</unittitle><container id="aspace_7a8604230219b6f0e8a7938c33dfbb55" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00039" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1969/1972" type="inclusive">1969-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_e408f187836589f7a61d4307f1b07579" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00040" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_a776a7ee4741e04bd5e3afc49eaacdae" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00041" level="file"><did><unittitle>Travel</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_d142f06eb940253653dd70edb79266a4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAC8992-00042" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1972" type="inclusive">1966-1972</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00043" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Cole, Marvin M.</unittitle><container id="aspace_36ab5eee0787be80e59e1c3e87b07780" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00044" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_bbd66ec58a76d108d66abddf29109006" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00045" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_a10c48dc32bee641258985d2b710d801" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00046" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Chief of Party</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_b27f5a412111dfa1741db0c1932db725" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00047" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence from Taulman A. Miller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_77218ff9893edee15774aef2bdb55c44" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00048" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Chief of Party</unittitle><unitdate normal="1969/1971" type="inclusive">1969-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0bf38d6a5edbe08032c26f0dc01ef38" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00049" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence to Taulman A. Miller</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc16f21692de90d5ce9b5b84dbab0d84" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00050" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gouttierre, Mary Luella</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_692f046c92a74cdf546a2c008826a05e" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00051" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Greenberg, Robert M.</unittitle><container id="aspace_f21adba4e641d84ac7ab4ad773276f52" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00052" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_c00795f48809577129315c5ff35a1b68" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00053" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9ff6c1b58997cd5e81b6a9c7e4eca2c" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00054" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hendricks, Jules</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d30bee70713176e6640ac5eff54bfa5" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00055" level="file"><did><unittitle>Jung, Chris W.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1966/1971" type="inclusive">1966-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_108f52d61bf596c16fbdfad37e52a695" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00056" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miller, Taulman A.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1972" type="inclusive">1970-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_cfa56677e04d7d141dd2bfebc501a077" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00057" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Neat, Mrs. Ethel V.</unittitle><container id="aspace_fccad898cba221fbbf6130d602c57853" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00058" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ee01e11fed10672d41609c0e7174a9f" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00059" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_75b89b4e7d618bbd4c3cdf29aa93d55e" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00060" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Trosper, Joseph F.</unittitle><container id="aspace_8cb79f67439e7301b3963a71797c4860" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00061" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_e78226ffe9cdb3478cd1edcead72b35a" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00062" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_b807aa7234a21ab73a857cba7e9f8719" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAC8992-00063" level="series"><did><unittitle>Library</unittitle><unitdate normal="1967/1972" type="inclusive">1967-1972</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00064" level="file"><did><unittitle>Book Orders</unittitle><unitdate normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_bb5c72a567e29ab1f52d2d9d46c501c2">(3 folders)</physdesc><container id="aspace_28592ef64c486cd48bad0b1bdb089e32" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00065" level="file"><did><unittitle>Card Catalog, Books in English for Kabul University</unittitle><unitdate normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_f822fa06d9d90335e4d229c17aae8fd6" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00066" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Library</unittitle><container id="aspace_52c695663ec614067cdd99a31b56f8a1" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00067" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1970/1971" type="inclusive">1970-1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_64605e245f3d32f5c2eed10020c5cd76" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00068" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_67d07d1700fe098981c6b1cb1c75e165" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC8992-00069" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Purchases</unittitle><container id="aspace_02a4fd80795f5cf8f902d45326690d87" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00070" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_a668772863facff66df42f02a06221ed" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC8992-00071" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1971/1972" type="inclusive">1971-1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_f382960bea83ed988cd35570101bba52" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
