<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA1975</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Elmer O. Wooley correspondence and publications, <date normal="1935/1952" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1935-1952</date> <num>C281</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Papers at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Ryan K. Lee</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date> 2005</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:04:31 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>November 3, 2005</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>November 10, 2005</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Elmer O. Wooley correspondence and publications</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Wooley, Elmer O. (Elmer Otto)</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C281</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.2 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1935/1952" type="inclusive">1935-1952</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_d3d92764069f2978f3b634b9eb921c44">Collection consists of correspondence and publications. The correspondence consists of two sets of letters compiled and edited by Wooley and presented to Indiana University President Herman B Wells. Two of the publications in the collection are about Theodor Storm, a German poet who greatly interested Wooley.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_eefce8823d6296b21c407b3bb6d63a6c">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language> and <language langcode="ger">German</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0cbb059b0dff506d8c0c6b390e469dea">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b88a60786e13642e1cf74c0b7cb02334">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Elmer Otto Wooley was born on 15 September 1883 to Cary Allen Wooley and Sarah Louisa Laws in Flora, Indiana. He earned the nickname "Professor" while he was growing up due to his serious demeanor. Dr. Wooley began his educational journey at the Indiana State Normal Teachers College in 1902. He transferred to Indiana University a few years later and received his A.B. in 1907. He went to Germany for the first time in 1910 and studied at the University of Leipzig for one year. He earned his A.M. from Harvard University in 1913 and his Ph.D. from Indiana University in 1915. Dr. Wooley taught on a part-time basis throughout his time as a student in order to pay for his education. </p><p> Dr. Wooley began his career at Denison University as a German instructor. He also worked as an instructor at the University of Alberta, Canada. He returned to Bloomington in 1922 and became a critic teacher at Bloomington High School under the auspices of the Indiana University School of Education. He taught both German and French at the high school until 1930. Dr. Wooley was also a German Instructor at Indiana University during this time. He was made assistant professor in 1930, associate professor in 1944, and full professor in 1953. Dr. Wooley retired from IU in 1954 after 38 years of service. He continued to tutor young students in both German and music after his retirement. </p><p> Dr. Wooley had three passions in his life: teaching, choir, and the German poet Theodor Storm. Outside of teaching, he devoted the majority of his time to studying the life and works of Storm. Dr. Wooley first became interested in Theodor Storm when he read his novel <title render="italic">Immensee</title> as a college student. Wooley traveled extensively to the German town of Humsum, a province in Schleswig-Holstein, where Theodor Storm lived most of his life. He became acquainted with Storm's son and daughter, and he collaborated with Storm's daughter to create an illustrated book depicting Storm's life. Storm's daughter died before the book was finished, and Dr. Wooley continued the work by himself. In August of 1953, Wooley published the illustrated book <title render="italic">Theodor Storm's World in Pictures</title>. Amongst Dr. Wooley's many publications, he also published <title render="italic">Studies in Theodor Storm</title> in 1943. </p><p> Dr. Wooley also had a passion for music. He was the choir director of the Bloomington First Baptist church for 24 years. In addition, he also was a choir member in the First Christian Church in Bloomington. He joined this choir in 1947, and it has been said that he was never late to a choir practice or church service.</p><p> Dr. Wooley celebrated his eightieth birthday by donating his library of first editions, articles, and manuscripts regarding Theodor Storm to the Indiana University Lilly Library in Bloomington. Dr. Wooley died on 7 July 1964 at the age of eighty.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_24c983a06b5c6f08a2a4f4b7add41962">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is divided into two series: Correspondence and Publications.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c5f1d1e0072d52214345dea2eb6994f8">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Elmer O. Wooley correspondence and publications span the time period from 1935 to 1952, during which Dr. Wooley was a German instructor at Indiana University in Bloomington. This collection contains primarily correspondence and publications written by Dr. Wooley. The bulk of Dr. Wooley's papers and letters are housed at IU's Lilly Library. The items in this collection were removed from the Archives reference files and are organized into two series: Correspondence and Publications.</p><p> The Correspondence series consists of two sets of letters written by Dr. Wooley during two pivotal times in his life. Letters from "Old Germany" are an abridged version of letters written by Dr. Wooley to his mother and sister when he was studying in Germany at the University of Leipzig from 1910-1911. Dr. Wooley did not include letters strictly pertaining to his own family. Instead, he included letters that reflected the German culture, history, and people. This compilation of letters was presented to IU President Herman B Wells in June of 1948. Letters to the " Homefolks" is a set of letters written to Wooley's mother and sister while he was attending Indiana State Normal School from 1902 to 1904. Dr. Wooley compiled excerpts from a large body of correspondence and made some editorial changes. Dr. Wooley compiled this series in hopes that his past experiences as a young student would be helpful to current students at the university. He presented the collection to President Wells in 1952. The two files in this series are arranged chronologically, according to the date when they were compiled by Dr. Wooley.</p><p> The series entitled Publications consists of four works published by Dr. Wooley while he was at IU. Files exist for each individual work. The majority of these publications relate to Dr. Wooley's work as a German instructor. However, "<title render="italic">Storm and Bertha Von Buchan</title>" is a series of letters and poems written by Theodor Storm and Bertha Von Buchan. These excerpts from letters and poems depict the relationship between Storm and Von Buchan. Most of these excerpts are in German and reveal the influence Von Buchan had on Storm throughout his early years as a poet (1836-1843). Von Buchan was Storm's first muse, and he claimed he fell in love with her the first time he saw her. However, it was an unrequited love that never blossomed. The files in this series are arranged chronologically.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1a1a1451b3eb0b0ff41e72a878706292">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>See also: www.indiana.edu/~liblilly/lilly/mss/html/wooleye.html. Letters and papers of Elmer O. Wooley are also housed at the Indiana University Lilly Library.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_ce33398ffdcf3bdc3a55f92f99461c09">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession 1197</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_271218c200300ba00ab0586481181607">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_89d77d8a017ad843a450d3927925bc05">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Elmer O. Wooley correspondence and publications, Collection C281, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_b9160e3ae8e7578004f535c668bb4d2e">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Serena Olson.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2004" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2004</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">German teachers --Indiana --Bloomington --Archives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">German teachers --Indiana --Bloomington --Correspondence.</subject>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Wooley, Elmer O. (Elmer Otto) --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Wooley, Elmer O. (Elmer Otto) --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Storm, Theodor, 1817-1888.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAA1975-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1949/1952" type="inclusive">1949-1952</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA1975-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters from Old Germany</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1949/1949">1949</unitdate></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1975-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to the Homefolks</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA1975-00004" level="series"><did><unittitle>Publications</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1935/1951" type="inclusive">1935-1951</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA1975-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle>"<title render="italic">"</title>"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><physdesc><physfacet id="aspace_7f03285d81753e0ffaacda28835c73c0">(Mimeographed)</physfacet></physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1975-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle>"<title render="italic">Storm Imensee Heath Visible Vocabulary German Series</title>", D.C. Heath and Company: New York</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1975-00007" level="item"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">"Studies in Theodor Storm"</title> Indiana University Publications Humanities Series, No. 10</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1975-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle>"<title render="italic">Report on Special Sections in Elementary German at Indiana University</title>", Reprinted from The German Quarterly</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1946-01/1946-01">January 1946</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_2222485157fee69646e1465f8cc1205b">28pp.</physdesc></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1975-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle>"<title render="italic">Storm and Bertha Von Buchan</title>", Bloomington: Indiana University, Spring</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><physdesc><physfacet id="aspace_d989f962ad9a8235d3c470db0902599f">(Mimeographed)</physfacet></physdesc></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
