<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAD1665</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Ernest P. Bicknell papers, <date normal="1914/1959">1914-1959</date> <num>C520</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to his Papers at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Allison Haack</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2013</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2013">© 2013</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:02:06 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>Feburary 03, 2014</date><item>Enocded finding aid began.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>Feburary 03, 2014</date><item>Enocded finding aid completed.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ernest P. Bicknell papers</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Bicknell, Ernest P. (Ernest Percy), 1862-1935</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C520</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 cubic foot</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">3 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">1914-1959</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1914/1929" type="bulk">1914-1929</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8030bbbbc12274008bafa955dd634935">A graduate of Indiana University, Ernest P. Bicknell is best known for his work with the American Red Cross, most notably during the First World War. His humanitarian service earned him great respect and numerous awards from European governments. The collection contains material related to his Red Cross service in Europe, including scrapbooks, newspaper clippings, photographs, and two awards.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_4441867e2558e3010d729e461cd1fb36">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_5ee748e26364b5376540956205278594">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d4b6932f6bdc656252bd437995685bc0">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Ernest Percy Bicknell was born in Vincennes, Indiana, on February 23, 1862. He attended Indiana University, graduating in 1887 with an A.B. Bicknell married Cora Scott in December of 1886. Together they had one son, Clarence Scott Bicknell. Cora died in January of 1888, and Bicknell was remarried to Grace Vawter in 1891. Ernest and Grace had four daughters.</p><p> Upon his graduation from IU, he worked for six years at an Indianapolis newspaper and then for five years as secretary to the Indiana Board of Charities. Bicknell then worked as the General Superintendent of the Chicago Bureau of Charities. During that time, he was chosen as the representative for Chicago and Illinois in charge of distributing Red Cross funds to San Francisco in the wake of the 1906 earthquake. In 1908, he was named the National Director of the American Red Cross, a position created specifically for him. He then served as the Director-general of civilian relief for the Red Cross in Washington. Additionally, he served as the president of the National Conference of Charities and Correction from 1908-1909, and as the director of the National Association for the Study and Prevention of Tuberculosis.</p><p> When World War I broke out in Europe, Bicknell was named Deputy Commissioner to France. He also served as a member of several international relief organizations. He served as Commissioner to Belgium from 1917-1918, during which time he was given the military title Lieutenant Colonel. He later served as the Special Commissioner to the Balkan States. After the war ended, he was named Red Cross Deputy Commissioner to Europe, and later Acting Commissioner to Europe, and finally Commissioner to Europe. He also served as the Director of the Rockefeller Foundation War Relief Committee, which sought to aid non-combatants who had suffered due to the war. In April of 1923, he became the Vice Chairman for Insular and Foreign Operations.</p><p> His humanitarian work earned him the honor of "Commander of the Crown" by King Albert of Belgium, the Legion of Honor from the French government, the Order of the Crown of Italy, Order of the Red Cross and Order of Prince Danilo of Montenegro, the Order of the Red Cross of Serbia, Order of Saint Anne of Russia, Order of St. Savior of Greece, and Order of Poland Restituta of Poland. Bicknell was additionally awarded the gold medal from the National Institute of Social Science for his work abroad. His wife, Grace, was awarded the Order of Elizabeth by the Queen of Belgium.</p><p> Bicknell's book <title render="italic">Pioneering with the Red Cross,</title> published in 1935, records his life and humanitarian service. Bicknell was awarded an LL.D. from Indiana University for "representing American charity to all the world." Ernest Bicknell passed away in 1935.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_f5ab375ea829f649c2dd8e099570513a">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Due to the small amount of materials and the focused nature of the collection, the Bicknell papers are organized into one series of Biographical materials.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3cc1846d03a7d16027afc83b10e81029">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection only contains one series of Biographical materials 1914-1959. This series consists almost entirely of materials related to Ernest Bicknell's humanitarian work with the American Red Cross. There are four scrapbooks in the collection. Two awards are present in the collection, as well as two books about the history of the Red Cross.</p><p> The Assorted Items folder consists of a small number of letters to Bicknell from doctors and Red Cross colleagues, pamphlets concerning his recognition of service, a small amount of biographical information, and newspaper clippings concerning his Red Cross service.</p><p> The collection includes several scrapbooks. The 1914-1938 Red Cross scrapbook largely contains correspondence sent by Bicknell's Red Cross colleagues, with several letters sent by members of the French Red Cross. A smaller number of the letters were sent by other acquaintances of Bicknell.</p><p> The scrapbook of tributes contains obituaries and letters and telegrams of condolence written on the occasion of Bicknell's death and funeral. The condolences were written by a variety of people and organizations, including the International Red Cross and the American Red Cross. This scrapbook also contains biographical information.</p><p> The Family Photograph and Red Cross Scrapbook contains a few photos of Bicknell's ancestors, dating back to the 1860s; numerous photos of Bicknell, many of them portraits, and photos of a trip to Hawaii. The last portion of the scrapbook documents Bicknell's time serving in the Red Cross and includes pictures of him and fellow Red Cross volunteers overseas in France and China. Very few dates are given for any of the photos.</p><p> The undated Red Cross scrapbook contains pictures solely from Bicknell's time serving the Red Cross. The photos document Bicknell's Red Cross colleagues, members of the military, those receiving aid, and the destruction in Europe. Locations depicted include Ypres, Paris, Verdun, Soissons Brussels, Venice, and Constantinople. Bicknell provided captions for the photos. The photos at the very end of the scrapbook are of Bicknell's wife and children.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1ba15fdfbcd18bd3ab1633d2b243ea48">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Related photographs may be available in the <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">University Archives Photographs Database</extref> </p><p> Additional Bicknell papers are held at Indiana University's Lilly Library. Contact the Lilly for further information.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_35e8a91d4b0dd67f66981af5716d6efa">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>2004/071, 2004/099</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4dec2f9eff9a98b562f338c7ca0e44f4">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University through a Deed of Gift. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_06639403738827b925cf878256c82b9b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Ernest P. Bicknell papers, Collection C520, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <custodhist id="aspace_7931e2bdd66abad6a16513205b010d18">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Transferred from Charlotte W. Osgood, Bicknell's granddaughter, to the University Archives, August 2004.</p>  </custodhist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_114f769dcc90052713616afbd44224d8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Allison Haack.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2014">2014</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1914-1918 --War work --Red Cross --History --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Philanthropists --Indiana --Vincennes --History --Sources.</subject>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Bicknell, Ernest P. (Ernest Percy), 1862-1935 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Bicknell, Ernest P. (Ernest Percy), 1862-1935 --Correspondence.</persname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Alumni and alumnae --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Alumni and alumnae --Correspondence.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD1665-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Biographical materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">1914-1959</unitdate><unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAD1665-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>Assorted Items re: Ernest Bicknell</unittitle><unitdate normal="1908/1935" type="inclusive">1908-1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_67b6e4c4a107b9ded30f9b6a180f3f4a" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD1665-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Compact History of the American Red Cross</title> by Charles Hurd</unittitle><unitdate normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_513a06d0eee8d466b8abb1b2ce0355af" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD1665-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Medal that reads <emph render="doublequote">Galla Victrix</emph></unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6f5a57ebb702c77007e56a6ace3cab8" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD1665-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle>Military Order of the Legion Loyal of the United States Award</unittitle><unitdate normal="1923/1923">1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_10ffdbf83f553d19068a35f83d12bcc4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD1665-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">The Report of the American Red Cross Commission to China</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_43014d45dd3f1a1ecb945764e81fbf32" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD1665-00007" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks - Correspondence</unittitle><container id="aspace_8e806e6c4341bd3cec36d7dd7a3da7be" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAD1665-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle>Red Cross</unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1938" type="inclusive">1914-1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_367a56e97370b9e413eb06cba86031cc" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAD1665-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tributes to Colonel Ernest P. Bicknell</unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ebfc641ba87ccb967f1fd9aa1c89c252" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD1665-00010" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Scrapbooks – Photographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_46cdd5f00a414ffab81ccbd32e64aeea" label="box" type="Box">3</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAD1665-00011" level="file"><did><unittitle>Family pictures, and Bicknell Red Cross photographs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_67a28769351d1d959de1477a88b39933" label="box" type="Box">3</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAD1665-00012" level="file"><did><unittitle>Red Cross</unittitle><unitdate normal="1914/1959" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1d694015d67c33bb9e0214763fc1a51" label="box" type="Box">3</container></did></c03></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
