<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA2760</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>William M. Daily collection, <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1835/1925" era="ce">1835-1925</date> <num>C227</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to his Collection at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Processed by Anne Pederson <lb/>Electronic finding aid encoded by John Cash and Francis Lapka</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>ÂŠ 2004</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:52:56 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 23, 2011</date><item>Collection cleaned up and prepped for digitization.</item></change><change><date>June 7, 2004</date><item>Encoding finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>June 15, 2004</date><item>Encoding completed.</item></change><change><date>May 4, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>William M. Daily collection</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Daily, William M., 1812-1877</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C227</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1925" type="inclusive">1835-1925</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1859" type="bulk">1835-1859</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b141ebb763c83023b8cb5ad5a2509ddd">William Daily was a Methodist minister, and served as president of Indiana University, 1853-1859. The collection includes correspondence, speeches, financial records, administrative records relating to his presidency at Indiana University; most prominent are records relating to charges brought against Daily during his presidency.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8ecfe3de3f2a8554b85a8b4029f8311d">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fa15b5d9d250ee514520d86784d11e3b">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bb0a9f5760073c8f610f1f55e9a5996f">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>William Mitchell Daily was born in Coshocton, Ohio, in 1812, but was raised in Indiana. He became a Methodist minister at the age of 19 and traveled throughout Indiana preaching. In 1835 he came to Bloomington with his ministry and began studies at Indiana University; he graduated the following year. Daily moved to St. Louis in 1838 and worked as an agent for the Missouri Conference. Shortly after this move he became a professor at St. Charles College. He returned to Indiana in 1840 to recover from a medical condition called hemorrhage of the lungs; upon recovery, he resumed his ministerial career. Daily married Permelia Northcraft in 1843 while he was a minister in Madison, Indiana. Beginning in December 1844 until November 1845 Daily served as Chaplain to the United States House of Representatives. Later he became an agent for Indiana Asbury University (now DePauw) and a member of the Indiana General Conference in 1852.</p><p> Upon his return to Bloomington, he became a member of the Board of Trustees at Indiana University on February 10, 1853, and attended his first meeting on July 30, 1853. On August 3, a mere day and a half after the resignation of President Ryors, the Board elected Daily as the third president of the university. Daily's appointment came in the midst of rife sectarianism on campus and in the community. From the beginnings of the university, Presbyterians had constituted most of the school's staff and faculty. This caused the Bloomington community to raise questions about the diversity of the school and about the politics involved. The Indiana Methodist Conference, established in 1832, made it a priority to be represented at the university itself, not just on the board. The sect met with certain opposition. Samuel Bigger, who was elected Indiana governor in 1840, declared that "there was not a Methodist in America with sufficient learning to fill a professor's chair if it were tendered him." (Woodburn p.115) But in 1853 the state had a new governor, Joseph A. Wright, who believed Daily's status as a Methodist and a Democrat could help the institution with its financial troubles. Daily's lack of credentials as an educator, however, caused many members of the IU faculty to feel he was unqualified for such an important position.</p><p> Daily's presidency was threatened in July 1858, when Dr. Alexander M. Murphy filed eleven separate charges against him. These charges included incompetence, plagiarism, and incurrence of debt. Other charges concerned incidents of sexual advances towards young women while his wife was away, with these being particularly damning. Murphy maintained that Daily was a "lecher and a lewd man at heart," and that he had used his position to seduce women. </p><p> Murphy's statements were compounded by other incidents involving Daily at the end of 1858. Louisa J. Smith, who did not know Daily, stated that on December 29, a strange man had accosted her in the streetâthe man matched Daily's description. On New Year's Eve, prominent Indianapolis citizens William Wallace and Benjamin Harrison (future President of the United States) testified that they had seen Daily intoxicated in public. These complaints came to the Board with Murphy's charges in January 1859. The body decided that Murphy would need to produce a list of witnesses to sustain the accusations. The next morning, instead of producing this list, Murphy dropped the charges altogether.</p><p> Although none of the charges against Daily were substantiated, he resigned his presidency on January 26, 1859, "in order that the unfavorable publicity connected with the trial might not be prejudicial to the University." (Myers p. 328) In a separate farewell address he delivered in February, Daily spoke of the affair as "slimy subterranean damnable conspiracies, brought about by malignant selfish, fiendish, devilish men who are instigated by malice." He also called the members of the faculty "a set of pusillanimous, narrow-minded bigots." </p><p> Local Methodists were disappointed by Daily, who was the first major Methodist faculty member at the University. In October 1859, the Indiana Methodist Conference met in Bloomington to decide upon Daily's fate in the association. It was a closed meeting; there were no witnesses presented and no minutes recorded, except for the decision: William Daily was expelled from connection with the conference. Regardless of the university's decision, the Conference felt that Daily should have been free of all suspicion in his position. </p><p> During the last years of his life Daily continued his ministry. Anxious to move South, he accepted the appointment of President Lincoln to become hospital chaplain in 1862. He served with the Louisiana Conference beginning in 1869. Daily was in the midst of this new career in the North New Orleans district when he became ill and died a few days later on February 5, 1877. He is buried in Madison, Indiana.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_842426d0ee4c3b3b1478786f805e25ad">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Organized into five series: Correspondence, Financial records, Administrative files, Speeches, and Testimony.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2709002040142e860e59bf2a7bca72ae">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection has been organized into five series: Correspondence; Financial records; Speeches; Testimony; and Administrative files. All files are arranged chronologically within their series. Because the Archives holds so little from Daily and his tenure as president of IU, this collection holds both his administrative records and a small amount of personal papers.</p><p> The collection begins with a Correspondence series and includes both university and personal correspondence. Prominent are letters written by Daily to his brother, "D.O." in Huntington, Ind., as well as letters written to Theophilus Wylie regarding his appointment at IU. </p><p> This is followed by a small series of Financial records, which has two receipts from Samuel Buskirk to the university. </p><p> The next series, Speeches, consists of formal addresses from Daily's presidency. Of note is a report on his fiery farewell address in February 1859. This latter item was not written by Daily; it appears to be in T.A. Wylie's hand.</p><p> The Testimony series chronicles the charges made against Daily in 1858 and 1859. Included are the initial charges brought by A.M. Murphy in August 1858 and testimony collected by Reverand F.A. Hester on behalf of the Methodist Church on Daily's immorality charges. Witnesses include several prominent Indianpolis citizens, including Benjamin Harrison, then an Indianapolis attorney, who went on to become the 23rd President of the United States. Also found here are responses of the faculty, written by T.A. Wylie. </p><p> Within the Administrative files, researchers will find additional records relating to Daily's dismissal, but also a subscription book of donations given to the university after the 1854 destroyed the First College Building, tuition announcements, and a resolution regarding standard text book adoption for the state.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_9f6a2d22bfb0780798486e3c74fbefce">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accessions 1135 and 7031</p><p> Some materials in this collection were transferred from the University Archives' reference file.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_8479fa87261b5d244e07e0efb6f33057">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection contains materials both in copyright and in the public domain.</p><p> The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_90d6fc7ff13ac892bfcaa1f7655767ea">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], William M. Daily collection, Collection C227, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_093425bb0f49ffcfebc9f7de393030aa">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Anne Pederson, <date normal="2004">2004</date>.</p><p> Revised in 2011 by Dina M. Kellams.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges --Indiana --Bloomington --Administration --History --19th century --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College presidents --Indiana --Bloomington --Arhives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College presidents --Indiana --Bloomington --Correspondence.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Methodist Church --United States --Clergy --Archives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Methodist Church --United States --Clergy --Correspondence.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --History --19th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Administration --History --19th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Daily, William M. (William Mitchell), 1812-1877 --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Daily, William M. (William Mitchell), 1812-1877 --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Wylie, Theophilus Adam, 1810-1895 --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Daily, D. O. --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Wylie, Theophilus Adam, 1810-1895. Correspondence. Selections.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Daily, D. O. Correspondence. Selections.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAA2760-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1854/1933" type="inclusive">1854-1933</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00002" level="item"><did><unittitle>Buskirk, S. to Unknown</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1925" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_23c7526aec314613ec61eb2ead7a30e8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_947727e7b5d7d02f0771021e1c693df4"><head>General</head><p>re: Support of Daily for the Presidency</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00003" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Wylie, T. A.</unittitle><container id="aspace_ec55fb6fa868a177c6d31c6ee6dd3d17" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00004" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1854-01-09/1854-01-09">9 January 1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_a36ef32b89895b01104f116fbb661446" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_36d0a41aa5bde4a7d0c94e349fa56721"><head>General</head><p>re: Wylie as potential professor</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00005" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1854-06-17/1854-06-17">17 June 1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_13fae6d48a637f22dc1cd9ed10ec9f2a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_f8607eb0b8d2c6dd466dc99935e01eef"><head>General</head><p>re: Reverand Elias H. Sabin's honorary degree</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00006" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Lane, Joseph</unittitle><container id="aspace_696294c97b7cb71cf271776ab82ce3ab" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_ca7bac96d46fbdd1786d5870d52e7c91"><head>General</head><p>Typescripts; origin unknown</p></odd><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00007" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1854-11-20/1854-11-20">20 November 1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_27656e6015c7ef1d89129b003f3c37bb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_d52e7366be2476ed62f0609ab5241e09"><head>General</head><p>re: IU's endowment problems</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00008" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1855-02-08/1855-02-08">8 February 1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_561d3ea70c6216a0e18d096a8d2ee86b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_1fdea155d952b2300b7b44a3a684bf10"><head>General</head><p>re: appointment of Loyd Glazebrook</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00009" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1855-02-08/1855-02-08">8 February 1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb73a0c0b137254576cc61956618011b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_f9ec772e2259e6509d49ce6c255efbc1"><head>General</head><p>re: criticism of the state legislature</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00010" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>to T.A. Wylie</unittitle><container id="aspace_6a32c2847a3fc414c05b4903c3723d6c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00011" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1855-03-24/1855-03-24">24 March 1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_c18553849de89f684072c207985ceba2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_07fbffc0623d46e4dc36cdca4e24fe5c"><head>General</head><p>re: Wylie's acceptance of position at IU</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00012" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1855-04-07/1855-04-07">7 April 1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_7695be32a98f8622ed202db92a480906" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_b331a157abc700f91c18dd74d06287bd"><head>General</head><p>re: Unanimous election of Wylie as professor of philosophy and chemistry</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00013" level="item"><did><unittitle>Woodburn, J. to Whom it May Concern</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1856-08-08/1856-08-08">8 August 1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfe2cd31b886680120a9017240ec5047" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_8308bfc1669386d29794020d496eba1e"><head>General</head><p>re: Sarah McCalla's teaching certification</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00014" level="item"><did><unittitle>Wylie, T.A.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857-03-03/1857-03-03">3 March 1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ab306bd6341960de06984222f21486f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_c51f85a80a7f0f0a8917db677ba62625"><head>General</head><p>re: Daily's delay in Indianapolis</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00015" level="item"><did><unittitle>Rogers, J. to President and Board of Trustees</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857-01-03/1857-01-03">3 June 1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7e95496372ec7a9a43530882007df45" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_ea0799756e082abc61ac26309dad1598"><head>General</head><p>re: construction costs</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00016" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Wylie, T.A.</unittitle><container id="aspace_682d368417a0c7d9a0debc6e90dc95ba" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00017" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1858-07-20/1858-07-20">20 July 1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f22dbdda5b23adc40c6307efea015e1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_26df17148267c088e64f882083d42ab2"><head>General</head><p>re: Request for Wylie to be present in August</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00018" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-01-10/1859-01-10">10 January 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0460f83a52fb7d7b97ec3fc38933e60" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_ede594a851f48d5747eb65fa4a9c5b07"><head>General</head><p>re: Wylie as surrogate president while Daily is out of town</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00019" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-01-14/1859-01-14">14 January 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_f499c739106678862baef77caca3b1ce" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_845a7f6f5fb4d97e240fed4625bd7307"><head>General</head><p>re: Daily's decision to resign</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00020" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-01-29/1859-01-29">29 January 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_42ac82e435470e5044c9c6b5e0ac024d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_7d8f2de3966d38ec5ad7640d09f059c2"><head>General</head><p>re: Daily's transfer of university register, seal</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00021" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>to W.H. English</unittitle><container id="aspace_2cffc3feccdb445ee4bed5ec2310236b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_f83028fdd51cea1a4fe72f9ec9c007b2"><head>General</head><p>Photostats. Originals held by the <extref xlink:href="http://www.indianahistory.org/our-collections/collection-guides/william-hayden-english-family-papers-1741-1928.pdf">Indiana Historical Society</extref>.</p></odd><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00022" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-11-22/1859-11-22">22 November 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_a9dd607903bdcdbfe41f3cb50d626827" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_32de813578285c0e9942fbdacbebb74d"><head>General</head><p>re: supplication for employment</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00023" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-12-16/1859-12-16">16 December 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_d72434c91203fa27137841dc5da4b90a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_6f5cb18ac7409d3481674b5509ae066d"><head>General</head><p>re: English's influence with the administration</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00024" level="item"><did><unittitle>Cravens, J.A. to W.H. English</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1860-11-25/1860-11-25">25 November 1860</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfc05c65df0f2552d7f20c2ff0a09216" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_61e084da7da201c27468b072266cc28f"><head>General</head><p>re: thanks for a favor</p><p> Photostats. Originals held by the <extref xlink:href="http://www.indianahistory.org/our-collections/collection-guides/william-hayden-english-family-papers-1741-1928.pdf">Indiana Historical Society</extref>.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00025" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>to D.O. Daily</unittitle><container id="aspace_a3f6631d28def73e9f1d3d1f07cdce09" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00026" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1864-11-22/1864-11-22">22 November 1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_43b4c220d12d72bc4f8bdfbe1af3a082" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_68e6eb52fbcbba1145a94bbb156d1bc0"><head>General</head><p>re: William's decision to stay in Indiana</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00027" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1865-07-23/1865-07-23">23 July 1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_10b903c9d887c348ce3b748628c1afce" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_6b78db27f527eeec06ae1a09e58278cc"><head>General</head><p>re: William's life in the "Benton Barracks"</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00028" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1865-10-02/1865-10-02">2 October 1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc807b3f1b0a4f554946cd5280aa4e6f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_b3dbfc031ff587667d152953d3f8bf2e"><head>General</head><p>re: Lizzie's aborted trip to see D.O. Daily</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00029" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1865-10-03/1865-10-03">3 October 1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb0b6bf4aead27e942137aa7c0b6c66a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_ed411967cef5646858d48cc39a466bf4"><head>General</head><p>re: William's commission to Special Agent of the Post Office</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00030" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1865-10-10/1865-10-10">10 October 1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_e60bcdf7d29e2fa564fec4632dee5263" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_c7b0c9976367edf0064a075d6101ae26"><head>General</head><p>re: William's trip to New Orleans</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00031" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1866-03-23/1866-03-23">23 March 1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd6d819a451ed9bded56c5b82c0c7968" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_631ffe2d4cde7a6eacc30afe428f0fe5"><head>General</head><p>re: William's new life in New Orleans</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00032" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1866-04-11/1866-04-11">11 April 1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_04baf299cea43697534116363f95a5d1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_ee3134ae0e52ce2a0268a129c30f7b4a"><head>General</head><p>re: Lizzie's stay with D.O. Daily's family</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00033" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1866-05-05/1866-05-05">5 May 1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_876d36d36c83d85412fedaf7580f52ca" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_83177f20929e2bef7a3297eedd2b01db"><head>General</head><p>re: D.O. Daily's possible application as Attorney General</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00034" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Lawton, Lizzie E. (Daily's daughter) to Miss Louise Maxwell</unittitle><container id="aspace_8e568329f8587be33ae9c40d3f054d37" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00035" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1898-02-01/1898-02-01">1 February 1898</unitdate><container id="aspace_c12a7a84a199e5800f07fbb6a6ef8795" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_c9e4c2f7e11864659c981a9794208345"><head>General</head><p>re: memorabilia Lizzie found about her parents</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00036" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1898-07-11/1898-07-11">11 July 1898</unitdate><container id="aspace_d076816085ffdd01f77a7ae38e23a1c9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_867345996250095d35b6c29555fb0861"><head>General</head><p>re: contact information for Lizzie and her mother</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00037" level="item"><did><unittitle>Daily, Thomas to John Cravens</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1925-04-01/1925-04-01">1 April 1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_39623e7bfe61c1b784e22a77dac92ac7" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_d117ab394d6855751008e999b67cbfef"><head>General</head><p>re: information about burial site of William M. Daily</p></odd></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA2760-00038" level="series"><did><unittitle>Financial records</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00039" level="item"><did><unittitle>Receipt for IU signed by Samuel Buskirk</unittitle><container id="aspace_8558e96a4741c36bbd3956da30d5467f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00040" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857-01-01/1857-01-01">1 January 1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac93ddda65fb60f4c194bdd0e7f58f4f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00041" level="item"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857-01-08/1857-01-08">8 January 1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd29c321261757f3e83d366f64b95cbe" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA2760-00042" level="series"><did><unittitle>Speeches</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1851/1859" type="inclusive">1851-1859</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1925" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00043" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Funeral of a Minister, or A Righteous Public Man"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1851/1851">1851</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d51a4a43d196c6a6f93abc22e601bb1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_1ce097efae86187690c9391cd86a7c74"><head>General</head><p>Sermon delivered at funeral of first Indiana University President Andrew Wylie</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00044" level="item"><did><unittitle>Transcript of William Daily's inaugural address</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1854-08-02/1854-08-02">2 August 1853</unitdate><container id="aspace_42d5b9443fc106c8d99a1b196f0d13fa" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00074" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Our Banner." A Baccalaureate to the Graduating Class of the Indiana University, at the Commencement of MDCCCLVI.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1856-08-03/1856-08-03">3 August 1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_7459932f25480413b3126d4ccc5d4abe" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00045" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Dedication of a New House, Indiana University"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1856-11-30/1856-11-30">30 November 1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_34b6df966e1d4127e24fae4a27e72acc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_7773df646533786138cfb75f51e48b97"><head>General</head><p>Second College Building dedication</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00046" level="item"><did><unittitle>Baccalaureate to the Law Class of 1857</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1857/1857">February 1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d41aa8e0a4e068121a196c60941cf52" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00047" level="item"><did><unittitle>President Daily's Farewell Address</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-02/1859-02">20 February 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_f20a770d8e1bc0f8fbc8e1c5bcc7641d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_805c542004b7de5fc8dcc4c8bdc93d7b"><head>General</head><p>(This was not written by Daily; looks to have been written by T.A. Wylie)</p></odd></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA2760-00048" level="series"><did><unittitle>Testimony</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1858/1859" type="inclusive">1858-1859</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1925" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00049" level="item"><did><unittitle>Testimony</unittitle><container id="aspace_a242f3623882769766fd5f1c9d3378ed" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00050" level="item"><did><unittitle>in favor of Dr. William Daily</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1858-07/1858-07">July 1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ceb1e6a3bb66eb42990cb9f654f4943" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00051" level="item"><did><unittitle>"Mrs. Murphy's Testimony reported by T.A. Wylie"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1858-08-17/1858-08-17">17 August 1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_65aed11f37f17f46cd9d6d7533b082fb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00052" level="item"><did><unittitle>Rev. F.A. Hester's charge to collect witness testimony for the Daily Trial by S.L. Gillet</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-01-12/1859-01-12">12 January 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_97ec395277188aead887ca70c21fec3d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00053" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Statements</unittitle><unitdate normal="1859/1859">1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_a14c9ad7a0ba5e03daec96b856749881" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00054" level="item"><did><unittitle>against William Daily by Indianapolis law partners William Wallace and (future U.S. President) Benjamin Harrison</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-01-11/1859-01-11">11 January 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f71fe3741c9449fe112ffc7cf4dd030" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00055" level="item"><did><unittitle>of Ellis W. Brown and M.S. Ohn</unittitle><container id="aspace_0e4376b4bc154946fa650c54ec7d3251" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00056" level="item"><did><unittitle>of John Plowman</unittitle><container id="aspace_85bd4bd6f0af8d4d78655e8ec9520115" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00057" level="item"><did><unittitle>of S.M. Douglas</unittitle><container id="aspace_db73d978bec8eff4de5c42d0e296a4ca" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00058" level="item"><did><unittitle>of R.M. Patterson, W.N. Jackson, John Plowman</unittitle><container id="aspace_34002df8456ad86b66185ffaefc53618" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00059" level="item"><did><unittitle>of John F. Wood, James Sulgrane</unittitle><container id="aspace_b44f5f946e334ba6a77c34a1f65abecc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00060" level="item"><did><unittitle>by Louisa J. and Sophia Smith</unittitle><container id="aspace_daa1dfa85dd42f9d7b68298c2c8679bc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00061" level="item"><did><unittitle>by R. Browning</unittitle><container id="aspace_125408518891673f9e702ddab069f22d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2760-00062" level="item"><did><unittitle>by T.A. Goodwin</unittitle><container id="aspace_e00938ede8370f67fe498a6356a94aeb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00063" level="item"><did><unittitle>Faculty response to charges - supportive</unittitle><container id="aspace_cca5d951039db8baf77bdcd03a914563" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00064" level="item"><did><unittitle>Faculty response to charges - negative</unittitle><container id="aspace_06d6085fc0aa0dc15b48eb1da8e70db2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00065" level="item"><did><unittitle>Faculty response to charges against <emph render="underline">them</emph></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859/1859" type="inclusive">1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_81be25cb9270eccbbc08d335d6380fba" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_1028e617bc263ac5e8e1a1b14d76c007"><head>General</head><p>Written by T.A. Wylie</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00066" level="item"><did><unittitle>Faculty response as to why Daily was denied use of College Chapel for his farewell address</unittitle><unitdate normal="1859/1859">1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_02a6f57963b31a009d3128e38784e9cd" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_8c32828b778d35ae8a2b76f6c882231e"><head>General</head><p>Written by T.A. Wylie</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00067" level="item"><did><unittitle>"An Address to the Faculty as is Present Constituted," by James P. Applegate</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1925" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_2761f18eaeff1f0cd50acae7435367f6" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_7858a2d1c836f8b155054ff904d01388"><head>General</head><p>Letter to faculty from the sophomore regarding faculty actions against Daily</p></odd></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA2760-00068" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1853/1859" type="inclusive">1853-1859</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1925" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00069" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tuition and Boarding fees information</unittitle><unitdate normal="1853-04-16/1853-04-16">16 April 1853</unitdate><container id="aspace_cfeb43cd2dba291884de8bc3ebcf78a4" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00070" level="item"><did><unittitle>Resolution re: uniform text books for state schools</unittitle><unitdate normal="1854-03-04/1854-03-04">3 April 1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f9fe4466ef73728457a92d99ec8035e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00071" level="item"><did><unittitle>Seminary Square - subscription/donors for rebuilding after the 1854 fire</unittitle><container id="aspace_ea1ff2b87e4da4ea50dc9f9af036d539" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00072" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letters written to parents of students requesting dismissal after resignation of Pres. Daily</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1859-02/1859-02">February 1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_57fe2ebd525c79670705ee1e1060e9d3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2760-00073" level="item"><did><unittitle>Report on activities surrounding Daily's departure to the Board of Trustees</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1835/1925" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8fce7c667ce0f40ac79cc8a516d42ef" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
