<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA3601</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Ralph L. Holsinger World War II training notebook and letters, <date normal="1942/1945" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1942-1945</date> <num>C315</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Papers at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Donald C. Force</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>ÂŠ 2006</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:57:07 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>August 31, 2006</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>August 31, 2006</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>May 6, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Ralph L. Holsinger World War II training notebook and letters</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Holsinger, Ralph L.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C315</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1942/1945" type="inclusive">1942-1945</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_f6836fed96e23e50c00f025448543a63">Ralph L. Holsinger served as an Army infantryman during World War II. After his war service, Holsinger was a journalist for several years before coming to Indiana University in 1965, where he was a professor in the School of Journalism until his retirement in 1989. Collection consists of Holsinger's training notebook from the Army radio repair school he attended during World War II as well as letters sent to his parents during his war service. Included in the training notebook are journal-like entries and stories Holsinger wrote throughout his travels. The bulk of the letters are those to his parents but there are also letters sent to his friend Joe Augustine which were given to Holsinger's hometown newspaper, the Covington, OH Stillwater Valley News, for publication. These were clipped and placed in a scrapbook.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_2bb394e1d01db69e4bf12ca336bbb3aa">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_105cbc26d9a59ffaf4e1dfac9ebecb2b">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e4b261aa1d9cc39d2956c5fe48b2ebf1">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Ralph L. Holsinger was born in 1918 in Covington, Ohio. Shortly after graduating from Ohio Wesleyan University where he majored in economics and political science, Holsinger served as an Army infantryman in World War II. After the war, he returned to Ohio, where he began his career in journalism working for the <emph render="italic">Piqua Daily Call</emph>. He quickly moved up in the newspaper world, serving as the Washington correspondence for the <emph render="italic">Dayton Journal-Herald</emph> and managing editor of <emph render="italic">The Cincinnati Enquirer</emph>. In 1965 his interests turned to teaching, and it was then that he came to the Indiana University School of Journalism.</p><p> At IU, Prof. Holsinger taught courses in reporting and editing, and for three years served as the adviser of the student newspaper, the <emph render="italic">Indiana Daily Student</emph>. It was under Holsinger's guidance that the student paper became an independent operation in 1969. Discovering he had a fascination for communications law, Holsinger became a self-taught student of the discipline and literally wrote the book on the topic â his Media Law was first published in 1985 and is currently in its 4th edition.</p><p> Holsinger had a very successful career at IU and during his tenure was awarded the Distinguished Teaching Award of the College of Arts and Sciences and the Graduate School Alumni Association, was selected by the students for the Brown Derby Award, which is given to the most popular professor on campus, and was elected to the Indiana Journalism Hall of Fame in 1989, the same year he retired.</p><p> Prof. Holsinger died on Dec. 8, 2004, at Brooke Grove Nursing Home in Sandy Spring, Maryland.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_55a22e15873ffc336ab8abecbe98dd46">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection is organized into two series: Training notebook and Letters.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c6b61798c8f979dcccfe3a0d997bf783">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Ralph L. Holsinger World War II training notebook and letters spans 1942-1945 and comprises .6 cubic feet. The collection is organized into two series: Training notebook and Letters.</p><p> The first series, Training notebook, consists of a single folder containing a spiral notebook with Prof. Holsinger's notes from the Army radio repair school he attended in Kansas City, Missouri, from October through December 1942. After the school, he took the notebook with him to North Africa, where he continued to log his thoughts until 1944. Included in the folder are 9 pages of transcripts from the notebook's journal entries, typed up by Prof. Holsinger a few years prior to his death.</p><p> The Letters series is the larger series of the collection, and consists primarily of Holsinger's letters to his parents describing life in the Army from August 1942 through December 1944. However, there is also a large scrapbook containing clippings of Holsinger's letters that were published in his hometown paper, the <emph render="italic">Stillwater Valley News</emph> (Covington, OH). Most of these letters were addressed to his friend Joe Augustine, and were written by Holsinger with the knowledge that they would be printed in the paper. Because of this, these letters seem a bit more "literary" in nature, and he focuses more on storytelling than he does in those letters to his parents. These letters span the period from May 1943 through October 1945.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_221047915de5c09a856a02375a060de1">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Papers presented to the Archives in November 2005 by Prof. Holsinger's wife, Margie Holsinger; Accession 2005/124.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2faa50c3049649134c02b0997428ca5b">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_723b4699df8172bc0a4639047d04cec6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Ralph L. Holsinger World War II training notebook and letters, Collection C315, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5d230a3e94aba06e8a20133364a962a8">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Dina Kellams.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2006" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2006</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945 --Personal narratives, American.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Soldiers --United States --History --World War, 1939-1945 --Correspondence.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">United States. Army --Military life.</corpname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Holsinger, Ralph L. --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Holsinger, Ralph L. --Archives.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_310a86e3c3a42f30d3d9044f2879a122" level="series"><did><unittitle>Training notebook</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">1943-1944</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_d6e1125a6801c4da7c64b939c0926cfb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Training notebook</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">1943-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_b4369d859127a06f7f328aefd12e9a66" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_3b27761b75fb7b2e947463c281cfe294"><head>General</head><p>(Note: folder includes Holsinger's transcriptions and memories of the training, circa 2000)</p></odd></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_94fca88f93f240b5061f71dae5be9d94" level="series"><did><unittitle>Letters</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1942/1945" type="inclusive">1942-1945</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_21f1244a1ae7e965bc4e0a10761f7150" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1942-08/1942-12" type="inclusive">Aug.-Dec. 1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b32bc9812214ff24b061090d592260d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f247753847d34c0677e254eddeee9427" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943-01/1943-01">Jan. 1943</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943-09/1943-12" type="inclusive">Sept.-Dec. 1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_82099d655025227c2f9b84546ba1b95c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6e013700037a79b9d192b603514c8b27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters to parents from North Africa</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943-02/1943-08" type="inclusive">Feb. 1943-Aug. 1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_a767913ee7f8da6777c237430cdf9958" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6cc818cb95ebfb364e55e48ef50ed309" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944-01/1944-05" type="inclusive">Jan.-May 1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6c5d500f7efbac56bf039cb288d178e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_39a61a5be2ff144320c12feae299de4d" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944-06/1944-09" type="inclusive">June-Sept. 1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_9be9efe03f78eb4a50c2e8429b76c38d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2e69f347e8827be714e7cdc6a6e9eae0" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1944-10/1944-12" type="inclusive">Oct.-Dec. 1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c54cd34307dccabe50cd9985ff1ae0b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f6b0fb296bcebce894534c1d540f7771" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scrapbook containing Holsinger's letters that were published in his hometown paper, the<emph render="italic">Stillwater Valley News</emph>, Covington, OH</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943-05/1945-10" type="inclusive">May 1943-Oct. 1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_56fbf9e4b4dd75691b4bb8882c72a6cc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><odd id="aspace_40612748347eb93ee351f128befd77e4"><head>General</head><p>(Note: most letters were originally sent to his friend Joe Augustine)</p></odd></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
