<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA2737</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana University Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC) records, <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1970-1982</date> <num>C196</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Dina M. Kellams and Ryan K. Lee</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date> 2002</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2002"> 2002</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:57:12 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>February 23, 2004</date><item>Additional materials added to collection and finding aid updated by DMK.</item></change><change><date>November 7, 2003</date><item>Finding aid revised by Linda Cantara to bring into conformance with v.2002 DTD.</item></change><change><date>August 4, 2003</date><item>Added accession number to Acquisition tag.</item></change><change><date>October 22, 2007</date><item>Updated finding aid to schema. ML.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>May 14, 2018</date><item>Moved Access Restriction from Administration Information. Moved Administration Information to proper place on hierarchy. Fixed broken indexing links. - MLM</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana University Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C196</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.8 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1970/1982" type="inclusive">1970-1982</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_7ef14d054c8a70141766ef5db984842b">Collection consists of .8 cubic feet of records from the IDPYC spanning 1970-1982. These records were deposited in the Archives by Myrtle Scott, who served as director of the program for most of its existence. It includes administrative files, reviews, meeting minutes, and conference files.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_5d7ec24c692f5651ec27b783bc42bd6b">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_157ecbb90c850108b7c3fbf45a3d7060">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_bc548005453d67452a9e6fc71340e268">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>When she transferred these records to the University Archives, Dr. Myrtle Scott, who served as Director of the program for most of its existence, included a letter detailing the history of the Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC). With her permission, the letter is reprinted here: </p><p> 'These folders contain all my files on the Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC), which operated here at IU from about 1972 until about 1982. One of the reasons I was hired at IU was to develop such a program. IU (chiefly through two School of Education administrators {Larry Brown, Division Director of the Division of Foundations and Human Behavior, and Richard Turner, Associate Dean for Research}) was interested in developing a doctoral program that would combine (a) child development, (b) early childhood education, and (c) policy. These three foci had come together very powerfully in the United States during the 1960s. Because of my background (Ph.D. from Peabody with one focus in child development; subsequent work at the National Laboratory for Early Childhood Education), I was asked to head up this effort. A planning group of faculty spent the better part of 1970-71 and 1971-72 designing the program, discussing it widely with colleagues in various departments, and shepherding it through the program approval processes. </p><p> 'We actually began working with some students informally in the spring of 1972, but the first students were formally admitted for the fall of 1972. The program then operated until about 1982 when the severe financial cutbacks administered to the School of Education at IU (due to sharp declines in enrollments in the previous few years) caused administrators to take a hard look at programs that used a lot of time for a few students (as IDPYC did). </p><p> 'There were several major evaluations of the program, all of which found that it was a very successful program that prepared national leaders in this multidisciplinary field. Reports of these evaluations are included in the folders. Graduates got very good jobs and many continue to be national leaders today. The IDPYC program was eventually folded back in to the Department of Educational Psychology, which was home of the Child Development program and one of its nearest group of colleagues (more of the IDPYC faculty had originally come from the Ed Psych than any other area). The program continued operation until all of the students in progress had either completed their Ph.D.s or made other plans. The last student finished in the early to mid-1990s. </p><p> 'I served as chairperson of the planning committee (197-72) (sic) and then director/chairperson of the program from its formal inception in 1972 until about 1978 (except for one sabbatical year, 1976-77, when Joan Prentice was acting chair). At that point Sadie Grimmett became chair and continued until IDPYC was folded back into Ed Psych. </p><p> 'IDPYC was a really good program that had lofty objectives, but demonstrated through several external reviews that it met (and exceeded) those objectives. It was expensive, because of the amount of faculty time spent per student, which made it an attractive target when the severe budgets of the late 1970s were experienced by the School of Education. The Department of Educational Psychology made every effort to be sure that all students in progress completed their programs in a reasonable and timely manner. These were completed largely under the direction of the IDPYC faculty from whatever their new departmental home was. </p><p> 'I hope these documents will be useful to persons interested in the history of university program and curriculum development at the doctoral level, and in particular persons interested in interdisciplinary endeavors.'</p><p>  In 1974 IDPYC decided to help sponsor an international conference, the Indiana International Conference on Young Children, that had three major objectives: 1) to bring together researchers from around the world who had done important work on young children and their care and education; 2) to call attention to IDPYC as a doctoral program that was training leaders in this field; 3) to be a learning experience for the doctoral students in the program. The conference proved to be a success and many of the papers from the conference were published by the National Association of Young Children in a book entitled Current Issues in Child Development (Scott &amp; Grimmett, 1975). Because of the success of the 1974 conference, the IDPYC faculty decided to host a much smaller conference in 1975. For this conference all researchers came from Indiana University-Bloomington.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d8480accbdbf0121caf202f49ef766bd">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection is organized into four series, Administrative files, Minutes, Indiana International Conference on Young Children, and Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC) Conference. </p><p> The Administrative files series consists of correspondence, memos, evaluations, and other miscellaneous records of the Program from its planning stages until IDPYC was folded back into the Department of Educational Psychology. It is arranged chronologically. </p><p> The second series, Minutes, consists of agendas and minutes from faculty meetings and retreats. It is also arranged chronologically. </p><p> The Indiana International Conference on Young Children series consists of items from the 1974 conference sponsored by IDPYC. This series is further organized into three sub-series: Administrative, Correspondence, and Presentations. The Administrative sub-series includes folders on conference planning, presenter information and general information. It is arranged alphabetically by subject. The second sub-series, Correspondence, includes in-coming and out-going correspondence between the chairpersons of the conference, Myrtle Scott and Sadie Grimmett, and those who were invited to present at the conference. These are arranged alphabetically by surname. The Presentations sub-series consists of the papers presented at the conference, including rough drafts and the final papers. It is arranged alphabetically by surname. </p><p> The Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC) Conference series includes financial information, programs, memoranda, and general information sheets from the 1975 conference. It is arranged alphabetically by subject.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_32b9bd9b4cbf08759127b47ca2b86303">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Organized into four series: Administrative files, Minutes, Indiana International Conference on Young Children, and Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC) Conference.</p>  </arrangement>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_796793827a3293f24936bed116b318e1">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Transfer; Myrtle Scott, 2002; Accession 2002/033.</p><p> Transfer; Myrtle Scott, 2003; Accession 2003/087.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3ebbf68b6b3e3726b4f7af20fb75021e">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fe21d42457e698178e5e57050e27ae83">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana University Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children records, Collection C196, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_7690e5b18e393bca5be4ea7e088c7897">
    <head>Processing information</head>
<p>Processed by Dina M. Kellams</p><p> Completed in <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002</date> </p><p> Additional materials added and finding aid updated by Ryan K. Lee, <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2004</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Early childhood education --Study and teaching (Higher) --Indiana --Bloomington.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Child development --Study and teaching (Higher) --Indiana --Bloomington.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children --History --20th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children --History --20th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Scott, Myrtle, 1937- --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Scott, Myrtle, 1937- --Correspondence.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_c2e27bb07f1bbf2f87fe5ca13f86f4b8" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1970/1982" type="inclusive">1970-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_c18b3502e1ec41ea0dffb3350ddca4f0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_0401eded629ef7a98d2038e19118d28f" level="file"><did><unittitle>IDPYC historical documents</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1970/1979" type="inclusive">1970-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_52e68141b19828145aedfb5232f2ed76" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cef20ca96bb112fd3ac675387df21049" level="file"><did><unittitle>IDPYC seminars</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_b760b8cc14d1f02612208473b2204602" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_de13b20166945af1242ca892251d0f52" level="file"><did><unittitle>"The Functioning of an Interface Person," by Myrtle Scott</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8afd1294b48bcf1020add6552e1104c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2b67e1a6c2d7f2da1efbc7904b78bceb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Advisors-Advisees</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1979" type="inclusive">1973-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_83312dfb0a19638ac2f4788beb3cde72" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7edfff7696cac0b4b3122b52204c2261" level="file"><did><unittitle>James O. Miller visit (Consultant)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_234b0cbf57736d5d832958428c3cdd22" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ac809a53f300c7a9f5991d1fe858de5b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Enrollment data doctoral programs</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f126835caf96de70fae2b240e5eee71" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8da112bec22679b5411c06ef48cc0f9d" level="file"><did><unittitle>IDPYC evaluations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1977/1978" type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_0fac2e6cc7bae0c4ff76c44cabcdb90b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_43e176ddd68a3ea1c670b1a222ced667" level="file"><did><unittitle>Millie Almy visit - evaluation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_d216ad9fc9f938386ed64a258eb72d77" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b5f5003ac01d4a2d67086b3016b4d54e" level="file"><did><unittitle>IDPYC - memos, correspondence, etc.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_831b5a54f52d90ca359229d2439035aa" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0dcc31f6e2fccf915d20b18bcbf2083b" level="file"><did><unittitle>C650</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_14e0af70736002139cb87662a2cd3d6f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_18aa8e227ac3859a3291ce81fc21f062" level="file"><did><unittitle>IDPYC - memos, correspondence, etc.</unittitle><container id="aspace_e3c31129378094551e84242ba64fa029" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_afe4e88e97a88a7f28c32478c8cbe873" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_1701b4a7dbf2e24f1d543ceefedf1a98" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_f21c43bc1f27c6d650fe36c1e5ead25e" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5b93b25f7b5e2dba8c36ef8b5e994c8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_2e712d7d80fca05f101455cb1943b20f" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1981/1982" type="inclusive">1981-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_802d763d7bad3ddb3ad12a8bb8e7f036" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_13da6e48f229142daf4e081f02d67807" level="file"><did><unittitle>Program brochures</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1970/1982" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a0898910ad3c2877045670fb23a8643" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bc3032a10af3dae2ce2607baf09949fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>Student vitae, products, etc.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1970/1982" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_549617a474eea281a5b8f57215f11775" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_11709c22ca1e02a419b7a359538fad94" level="series"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1972/1981" type="inclusive">1972-1981</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_43b8c3bb299543f5646240d53d2ba207" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1972/1973" type="inclusive">1972-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e80228be4cfb8bc08ed2e6444b5f6fe" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b56daab194efc74cb0a36ede29f37b0d" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1974" type="inclusive">1973-1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_3e106e9062dadac831461557cbb6370b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3170446fc4d48c286837d64f6a57bd82" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1975" type="inclusive">1974-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_80e4f0d924cc0091e6b3dfdbbad81f7c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6f9871d7caeddd5b5182a3d4fb6f9a0b" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1976" type="inclusive">1975-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_f885f290cd02fe83068ed806adb43a57" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ee941cfee3e6a95c9563b6f2c771a972" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">1976-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_a031f1a888ccfe9a607d2b1184861298" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9f040eef04c5ef3a2d70d0a41503267a" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1977/1978" type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_c58a4ececd31824a7f99b7d77c6dbbf8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_77543e480230c05b650e4775cfe46c7d" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_e51bdf0064e5a03605594eb98826d462" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f2f2a60da1f8466a95b1b2714ecbf490" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1979/1980" type="inclusive">1979-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf508e7f528e370b590ac4c703e9f091" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bcd11a97939d32e547bd23f734bf928b" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_684d7efabdf24497dba1cb219ceb6626" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_2ec5e66edb8f842d9b1c47feca3350cc" level="series"><did><unittitle>Indiana International Conference on Young Children</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1977" type="inclusive">1974-1977</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_5519606c873cb0410247dac613ec3188" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1976" type="inclusive">1974-1976</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_4487de367d5122f6ee78d2fcc61b9b91" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference Information</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_07b385e675d1334c59298d48c6bcc4cc" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1fc3eb66876c5446ffeee5c423173a79" level="file"><did><unittitle>Planning</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec0bcd1e565f7860e98007e4a4a8895d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_2e6c428d70c437e93689a1acbdd9fdfd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Presenter Information</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_e966d85f54a199e0abc1022951fd8324" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_5a7dff9ccb79bd7c03e35b2880ecf331" level="file"><did><unittitle>Table of Contents, "Proceedings of the Indiana International Conference on Young Children"</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_7232ca28103731fd7a3b29d3c406f95b" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_81271e731884d34066e7a7a81fe54ad8" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1977" type="inclusive">1974-1977</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_6f5f03b364fb7ecc2eb654863508e049" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anastasiow, Nicholas</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8bc24a0b01649b429df874eff119bba" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_0313c7578c63ca15feb31b186668fd06" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bernstein, Basil</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1977" type="inclusive">1974-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_70e115e7f07d38e640a04d28aaaa59c5" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_d4b5e254b04b619459e75167850aadf1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Caldwell, Bettye</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_21ce3a1751a07603e109d73e12badb8e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_466bd8de82316f69215a7dcf081bfb4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Datta, Lois</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_21c42e9a6b3772c8752a4eea819a05b8" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7c05d0a9ded360511c693bb9b8c65d72" level="file"><did><unittitle>General, E-L</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1976" type="inclusive">1974-1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_39728bd08439b1cafcc5380f775a5098" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_0cedfdf786def850c0f47b6941379d11" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gordon, Ira</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_7736bbded3d46ee5af4c054f3327444d" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1621948a1b0cc0601b96b9c396407a75" level="file"><did><unittitle>James, Thomas</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb890503b0484df4c7c38b61790b1098" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_840f7ce36415ea372e995a644dc68fe5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Katz, Lillian</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_943453065e670e55b533c915e24edaf4" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_3c738a8c83610f6abb6fe0cabd9602b5" level="file"><did><unittitle>General, M-W</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1977" type="inclusive">1974-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_e75c159b1d3d4980ef14aedf551fc11f" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_9d456753ce0541df4b275e0a2012f0a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>McDaniel, Gary</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_c9dbd5e89f2c02da9e0426c83117bd13" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1a2b6f61f741fc4660966e6b693424f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shipman, Virginia</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_8365ca6eb4c5b5e94602a313ac426f31" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_54819aa37e4ed8e57927e1f397186049" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shultz, Thomas</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_08b2d947aa13369a121c9c0eb3895431" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_e0e04fd4b0a8c94c383f440665c63b53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smilansky, Sara</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_485534531546be2c5a42b7eeb60d2711" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_55723390a56c0d3855e9c78cc174b3a1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wilson, George</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_3df309010b5fe994441d3b2f261250a5" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_97028a4997b0693cb623722f363b9f22" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wise, Arthur</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_44fab4e7a918055e7cbd94f8853f3acc" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_b46d45a957a90f0d62d240cd3429145e" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Presentations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_1a3f83927ac5ab1663bbda88e4cc3972" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anastasiow, Nicholas<title render="doublequote">Developmental Parameters of Knowledge Transmission</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_b40a5df20c2a8d4275929284b28f9db0" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_962ab6edbb337618dc04d5d03b137a3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bernstein, Basil<title render="doublequote">Classification and Framing as Two Dimensions of Knowledge Transmission across Social Classes</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_1aa4499d43e0976fa544ba3278e51bcc" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_79beed0e0d17dccfa921ff88765a498a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Caldwell, Bettye M.<title render="doublequote">Child Development and Social Policy</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_91f317fc1d71396922c0712519842b56" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_44d9e07489f41cb30241fbc35916be86" level="file"><did><unittitle>Gordon, Ira J.<title render="doublequote">The Application of Infant Research: Policy-making at the Local Level</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c84edbd1db753f1c9d9384da9771439" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_f575080144d30a129c2b4abca4baebe8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Grimmett, Sadie A.<title>Synthesizing International Perspectives</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_3d03355fd12a140ac4aaa79e8830a880" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_93fefd1cb74691a1012fbf13d39263d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>Scott, Myrtle<title render="doublequote">The 1970's: A Critical Period for Young Children?</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a5e728425daafbd88968de07cca260c" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7b16dbaecf8118943e6ac4c752d6b4e6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Shipman, Virginia<title render="doublequote">Research Findings as Related to Educational Programming</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_4dbc9cc32acb4377e5fa889d39b2fb9e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_287c446374cd37b51d5cd5bc234ed5f1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Smilansky, Sara<title render="doublequote">Some Main Dimensions of Educational Programming for Disadvantaged Young Children across Cultures</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e66d2cf3a201b2927ecd5732be256e9" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_99ffaccac49bedbffbcef25b91a8c642" level="file"><did><unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1974/1976" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6b994bac7cde61ba215083cd69dfe8b" label="box" type="box">2</container></did><odd id="aspace_2d677e4df746cf3d0d985574a800e068"><head>General</head><p>Note: Copy of paper entitled, <title render="doublequote">To the Anonymous Educational Prisoner</title> with the inscription "Introduction to Class Codes &amp; Control, Vol. III" written in ink at the top of the front page, author unknown.</p></odd></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c4d68ee126fdea27ba1a65440ec5b1d5" level="series"><did><unittitle>Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC) Conference</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_3f6719c66491411186f7bcaf0b0115a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Programs</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_e456ad2ffac771b6e50863b029d99eda" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_57bc9a8baf5958f483640122787f781f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memoranda, to Psychology students</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc9981e675b67d41b7a791f519cca98e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3eaca0939b6d2ca8974e27ec28c7d5c3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Interdisciplinary Doctoral Program on Young Children (IDPYC) Conference</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8905aa86fb97d05d32e5e15a4c8e427" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cc87396471598b151ee017fbe569ea68" level="file"><did><unittitle>Consent Forms</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_2873482639f21965ad3df9b8926f3189" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e15795f6c1bcf56721c69222525dcc60" level="file"><did><unittitle>Finances</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_b2fe90118ffbf5d2e4bcb1be67639364" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9edc78e3e7ae6e395659d5413f950df9" level="file"><did><unittitle>General Information Sheet</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_1631cf5b0e7b9b38f581bbec4ceddb5e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
