<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA1623</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana University Publications Editor's records, <date normal="1905/1972" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1905-1972</date> <num>C84</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Ilias Kyriazis and Ye Ja Sanders</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2005</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:09:47 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 8, 2005</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>June 15, 2005</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana University Publications Editor's records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Indiana University Publications (Firm)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C84</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.5 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905/1972" type="inclusive">1905-1972</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1935/1955" type="bulk">1935-1955</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ca721d46525abdfd27d35d12d72208d6">The Indiana University Office of Publications is one of the oldest non-academic offices on campus. Its records date primarily from the tenure of Ivy Leone Chamness, who served as Head Editor of University Publications from 1917-1952. Collection includes correspondence, manuscripts, and newspaper clippings. Prominent in the collection are edited manuscripts of the two volume <title render="italic">History of Indiana University</title> written by Burton Dorr Myers and James A. Woodburn.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_bff945b00f6c62dc9ee79edfbaa3b2fc">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_baa77d272b1b4a59d0b3ab358f3ffccb">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_91e81fc3fb0e593c5ffcfe237bac6e98">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>According to Myers's <title render="italic">History of Indiana University</title>, the I. U. Publications Office (now known as the Indiana University Office of Publications and not to be confused with Indiana University Press) is one of the oldest non-academic offices on campus. Originally, the publishing of the university catalogues, bulletins, pamphlets and scholarly essays was the responsibility of the President. Prior to the start of the 20th century, this duty fell to a standing presidential committee, composed of faculty and administrators, and printing jobs were executed under state contracts. It was not until 1914 that a full-time editor was appointed to head the University Publications Office. This event coincided with the establishment of a printing plant primarily designed to print the Indiana Daily Student, but that initially handled small University jobs as well. Ivy Chamness was named Assistant Editor of University Publications in 1914 and would be promoted to Head Editor in 1917. She also served as Assistant Editor of the <title render="italic">IU Alumni Quarterly</title> and promoted to Associate Editor in 1919 and finally Editor in 1921. She served in this position until 1938.</p><p> By 1937, the duties of the Publications Office included a wide array of products, including not only the bulletins for the university, its extensions, and the more autonomous schools, such as the School of Education, but also such items as the commencement program; the annual telephone directory; the scholastic publication series for the sciences, the humanities, folklore, and social sciences; and the <title render="italic">Indiana University Newsletter</title>, a precursor to the <title render="italic">Alumni Magazine</title>. The office also handled the editing of the <title render="italic">Alumni Quarterly</title> and the publication of the numerous forms and brochures needed by departmental offices. In 1938, the <title render="italic">Newsletter</title> and the <title render="italic">Quarterly</title> merged to form the <title render="italic">Indiana Alumni Magazine</title>, and Chamness was named as the Associate Editor of the <title render="italic">Magazine</title>, a post she retained until her retirement in 1952.</p><p> As the University expanded and new departments were added, and as the number of scholarly publications grew, along with new aesthetic demands of printing requiring greater uses of color and photographs, the burden on the office expanded. By 1945, a post-war committee on publications began discussions on reorganizing the office to meet the new printing necessities of the expanding university, and the initial discussions for creating a University Press commenced. In 1950, Chamness noted in her last annual report as the Head Editor of University Publications that the growth of Extension Division publications and the increasing numbers of large scholarly studies, including a full catalog of educational motion pictures totaling 430 pages and 15,000 copies, placed the greatest demand ever on the Office. Included in that year's output were six publications of humanities studies, four studies in folklore, three studies in the natural sciences, and two books on I.U. history (<title render="italic">Trustees and Officers of Indiana University</title> and the Myer's <title render="italic">History of Indiana University, Vol. II</title>).</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5ecfd2196f75b5e54cd90c6d98f18415">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Organized into four series: Correspondence; Edited manuscripts; Donor relations; Clippings.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d3337f3c5757e5465eec03f4fea16a1d">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection has been organized into four series: Correspondence, Edited manuscripts, Donor relations, , and Clippings. The predominant topics are the <title render="italic">History of Indiana University</title> volumes, which Chamness edited, and a gift book compiled in 1915, which was a record of substantial donations to the university. (The <title render="italic">History of Indiana University</title> was written in two volumes, both published by the university in 1940. James A. Woodburn, a professor of history at IU, wrote the first volume, which covered the school's history from its beginning in 1824 to 1902. Burton D. Myers, then dean of the School of Medicine, continued the history to cover the years from 1902-1937. For further information about these works, see Collections C82 and C83.) Other materials concern her activities as an editor for the <title render="italic">IU Alumni Quarterly</title> magazine and later, the <title render="italic">Indiana Alumni Magazine</title>.</p><p> The Correspondence series (1905 – 1972) has six sub-series: World War I Alumni, <title render="italic">IU Alumni Quarterly</title>, Woodburn manuscript, Myers manuscript, Wylie House and Pering family history. The sub-series have been arranged in chronological order, and within the sub-series each folder of correspondence is arranged alphabetically. Of particular interest are the letters between Chamness and family members of IU alumni who fought in World War I. These letters delineate the experience of the men during the war. There is also correspondence about the Wylie House and the Pering family history, which were part of Chamness's research efforts for the alumni magazine.</p><p> The Edited manuscripts series (1923 – 1954) is divided into three sub-series, the <title render="italic">IU Alumni Quarterly</title> and the Myers manuscript and the Woodburn manuscript for the <title render="italic">History of Indiana University</title>. These titles are amongst the more prominent titles Chamness edited. In the Myers' manuscript, Chamness' early notes and revisions are placed first, followed by rough drafts of chapters by various authors, which have been arranged alphabetically. Revisions and records documenting events just before publication of the manuscript have been placed last in the sub-series. The Woodburn manuscript is organized similarly with rough drafts first and Chamness' corrections and revisions second. The Myers' manuscript papers are the most detailed, as they include typed copies of most of the chapters in the final copy.</p><p> The Donor relations series (1905 – 1935) relates to the Gift Book Chamness edited, which has been organized into three sub-series, Gift Book, Gift Book correspondence and Clippings. She kept track of all major donations and donors to the university from the time of the Gift Book's first publication (1914), often relying on newspapers clippings to provide leads and to initiate correspondence with donors who had yet to be included in the Gift Book. Among these gifts are collections of books, portraits of prominent figures and financial contributions to different funds, such as the Student Building Fund. It appears that the 'Gift Book' was never actually published and that the information she continued to collect was published in the "Gifts and Bequest" section of the Indiana University Bulletin. This series has been arranged in chronological order.</p><p> The Clippings series (1929 – 1938) contains newspaper clippings about the establishment of the <title render="italic">IU Alumni Magazine</title>. The file has been organized in chronological order.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_fc00eb841ee1e09d1a488fa2c17e5044">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>For the personal papers of Ivy Chamness, see IU Archives Collection C239.</p><p> For more information about the <title render="italic">History of Indiana University</title> manuscripts, please see the Burton D. Myers papers, Collection C82, and the James A. Woodburn papers, Collection C83.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_88ec1bda7b052eb4aaf84cb7f0f2af1a">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accessions 7026, 0910, 9368, and 9189.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_2ca1d8edea32e682a9830aea5eb3236f">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cdcdb45f1be452b04b8362d849fdb1c1">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana University Publications Editor's records, Collection C84, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d2ecd263ecffdaf8bfb3fdb495670037">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Anne Pederson and Thomas Bongiorno.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2005" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2005</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">College publications --Indiana --Bloomington --History --20th century --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="ingest">History of Indiana University.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University Publications (Firm) --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University Publications (Firm) --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University Publications (Firm) --History --20th century --Sources.</corpname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Chamness, Ivy Leone --Archives.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Chamness, Ivy Leone --Correspondence.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Myers, Burton Dorr, 1870-1951. History of Indiana University.</persname>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Woodburn+James+Albert+1856+1943</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAA1623-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905/1972" type="inclusive">1905-1972</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00002" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>World War I alumni</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918/1937" type="inclusive">1918-1937</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-L</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918-11-29/1937-10-19" type="inclusive">29 Nov 1918 - 19 Oct 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b2b8381c8917037c46345725f24c070" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>M-Z</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918-02-26/1920-12-20" type="inclusive">26 Feb 1918 - 20 Dec 1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_51637dd71192877cf16ae9b20ce6e856" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00005" level="subseries"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">IU Alumni Quarterly</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1911/1938" type="inclusive">1911-1938</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle>Katharine Greenough</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938-02-21/1938-02-24" type="inclusive">21 Feb 1938 - 24 Feb 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_00835ef04699e135503e60092ea7ffed" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00007" level="file"><did><unittitle>Walter Myers</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1911-06-21/1922-01-31" type="inclusive">21 Jun 1911 - 31 Jan 1922</unitdate><container id="aspace_f706f65ddd1d125c7529623d2be6171b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle>General correspondence A-Z</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1916-11-14/1938-11" type="inclusive">14 Nov 1916 - Nov 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_da6e17cd320c6712224bbed782a66999" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00009" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Woodburn manuscript</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1933/1945" type="inclusive">1933-1945</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle>General correspondence A-Z</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1933-10-23/1945-06-27" type="inclusive">23 Oct 1933 - 27 Jun 1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_65806befd2ee6e9bb315cd140bfcb3ac" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00011" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Myers manuscript</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943/1952" type="inclusive">1943-1952</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00012" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-L</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1950-11-28/1952-06-09" type="inclusive">28 Nov 1950 - 9 Jun 1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d488f593ca8d9ae12eeae3f9e023b87" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00013" level="file"><did><unittitle>M-Z</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1943-10-04/1952-06-09" type="inclusive">4 Oct 1943 - 9 Jun 1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_d60eb36259248c4148286d5c0057595e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00014" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mrs. W.A. Alexander</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1952-06-04/1952-06-09" type="inclusive">4 Jun 1952 - 9 Jun 1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_229b8f27b7128dae0b3fd6c6cb11d919" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00015" level="file"><did><unittitle>Robert Cook</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1952-01-21/1952-03-20" type="inclusive">21 Jan 1952 - 20 Mar 1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_5788de6b27d17862a1c2a4d2c8fefecb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00016" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Mahoney</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951-12-08/1952-03-20" type="inclusive">8 Dec 1951 - 20 Mar 1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d5ba287855df702aaef9e9f1774fbb9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00017" level="file"><did><unittitle>Velorus Martz</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951-09-14/1952-06-09" type="inclusive">14 Sep 1951 - 9 Jun 1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_de411268e9b8d057f14ea3b6e8a1d95a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00018" level="file"><did><unittitle>Burton D. Myers</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1948-01-02/1950-07-20" type="inclusive">2 Jan 1948 - 20 Jul 1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_377c53ad495f97f4e77b91d52b1d6eb3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00019" level="file"><did><unittitle>Henry Prange</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951-07-18/1951-07-20" type="inclusive">18 Jul 1951 - 20 Jul 1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_39c552f0a1edbc979826b2d69f2ef814" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00020" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Wylie House</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951/1954" type="inclusive">1951-1954</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00021" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anton Boisen</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951-08-27/1954-12" type="inclusive">27 Aug 1951 - Dec 1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_17e6fa721c4559c0bf284bd535a13612" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00022" level="file"><did><unittitle>Marie (Boisen) Bradley</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951-11-29/1953-06-26" type="inclusive">29 Nov 1951 - 26 Jun 1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_7358c0960128e235b2de3fd8e85d1d91" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00023" level="file"><did><unittitle>General correspondence A-Z</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951-08-18/1954-11-04" type="inclusive">18 Aug 1951 - 4 Nov 1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1ccfb2887b1bf138ba91aff984e9796" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00024" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Pering family history</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1932/1933" type="inclusive">1932-1933</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00025" level="file"><did><unittitle>Karl Fischer</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1932-01-13/1933-08-09" type="inclusive">13 Jan 1932 - 9 Aug 1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_d16e441fe968098edab4a48309ec3fea" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00026" level="file"><did><unittitle>Alfred Pering</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1933-07-17/1933-07-17">17 Jul 1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_7cc39836dbb6831e2da15534d0aca7d1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA1623-00027" level="series"><did><unittitle>Edited manuscripts</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1954" type="inclusive">1923-1954</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00028" level="subseries"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">IU Alumni Quarterly</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923/1938" type="inclusive">1923-1938</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00029" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rough drafts</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1923-05/1938-05-15" type="inclusive">May 1923 - 15 May 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_c58756ee6cb9acf8e6bc8dea412864ee" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00030" level="file"><did><unittitle>Copies of <title render="italic">Indiana Alumni Magazine</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938-10/1938-11" type="inclusive">Oct 1938 - Nov 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_8ee18929d854bd609c7f2b19cff89dea" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00031" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Myers manuscript</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">1936-1948</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00032" level="file"><did><unittitle>Early versions of chapters used with Ivy Chamness's comments</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_266da49a8a1954b70377002acc4976a5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00033" level="file"><did><unittitle>W.A. Alexander</unittitle><container id="aspace_9e3ee4120a8f00e5016eaa761a8b7069" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c04 id="aspace_VAA1623-00034" level="file"><did><unittitle>Library (used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937-02-22/1937-02-22">22 Feb 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_a1d2ee0999a135af064f6a7dafe036b1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAA1623-00035" level="file"><did><unittitle>Memorial Fund Campaign (not used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3df6c957e54a288be9503aa431c596cf" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00036" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Lowe Bryan—"Adventures in Psychology" (not used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ade4a0175814985311da07e0bd4fdea5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00037" level="file"><did><unittitle>Cedric Cumming—Extension Division (used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1948-06-28/1948-06-28">28 Jun 1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_17c946a8c24f11d53fb1f4e0d12e964e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00038" level="file"><did><unittitle>Karl Fischer—Campus Life, Fraternities, Sororities (not used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">c. 1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ea8ce30ec848c936d18ff1b94524706" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00039" level="file"><did><unittitle>Velorus Martz</unittitle><container id="aspace_0c05bdcfb6cdfcfcbebf399f0a09468d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c04 id="aspace_VAA1623-00040" level="file"><did><unittitle>School of Education (shorter version—used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb5e709d199145137931c7c126569bd8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAA1623-00041" level="file"><did><unittitle>School of Education (larger version—not used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">c. 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c574cf5aee6d38b863d2d793b1ef665" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00042" level="file"><did><unittitle>B.W. Merrill, Winifred Merrill, and Dr. Myers—(some used, some not)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1948" type="inclusive">c. 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_363e91a4080054dacfda96be5fe89d13" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00043" level="file"><did><unittitle>Johanna Miller Olmstead (Fox)—The Christian Associations (not used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1954" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_170763d377b57cfdbf8a2da09a7b1e88" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00044" level="file"><did><unittitle>B.D. Myers—Medical Social Service/Appts. Of Deans Emerson, Gatch (used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1954" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_280680291e12562980caa7563e8c1838" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00045" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fernandus Payne—Graduate School (used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1937">1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d7b3221a1e9b169fff4196e0a2f4f7c" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00046" level="file"><did><unittitle>William A. Rawles—School of Business (part of this used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1954" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_374b2ed70115fe430f9ae0226a2b0571" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00047" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lloyd Wilkins—<title render="italic">Daily Student</title> (used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937-05/1937-05">May 1937</unitdate><container id="aspace_263e73d8fa3e0945454734116039e56e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00048" level="file"><did><unittitle>Author Unknown—Extension Division (not used)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1954" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a7ee10d02777779dabb08a8e6fc7f83" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00049" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ivy Chamness's revisions and suggestions</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1954" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1fe263b390d1f3c631fa4c04637c4d1" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00050" level="file"><did><unittitle>Preparation for publication</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1937/1954" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb9ac4a135cf6aa73803bd6aa89dc64a" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00051" level="file"><did><unittitle>Distribution</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1951-04-30/1953-03-16" type="inclusive">30 Apr 1951-16 Mar 1953</unitdate><container id="aspace_fbf15c5d18faa95e25471ed64c144dde" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00052" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ivy Chamness's interviews, notes and research prior to publication</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1941-04-21/1954-06-23" type="inclusive">21 Apr 1941- 23 Jun 1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fde88d5d2fb0d798e3eb947169e4bd6" label="box" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_be8f659046fa0c5b6d621dfe2a3f8b65"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">(See also Collection C82.)</emph></p></scopecontent></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00053" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Woodburn manuscript</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1940" type="inclusive">1936-1940</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00054" level="file"><did><unittitle>Handwritten drafts for the Woodburn Manuscript</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1940-05-02" type="inclusive">Winter 1936 - 2 May 1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_021ce6ad9ededcd6cac807d9782c22d4" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00055" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rough drafts with Ivy Chamness's comments and suggestions</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1936/1940" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_5557086c1181368f1ef392cfe7720b29" label="box" type="box">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_405309e03ea9ed2505dac09ad1a6d470"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p><emph render="bold">(See also Collection C83.)</emph></p></scopecontent></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA1623-00056" level="series"><did><unittitle>Donor relations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905/1935" type="inclusive">1905-1935</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00057" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Gift book</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905/1935" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00058" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ivy Chamness's notes and descriptions of donors and donations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1935/1935">1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dc154f57184718b2540302a0c969e65" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00059" level="file"><did><unittitle>Lists, descriptions and acknowledgments of donations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905/1935" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_519a9333da1ae89a9ee6f85696678ca4" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00060" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Gift book correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1915/1935" type="inclusive">1915-1935</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00061" level="file"><did><unittitle>J.W. Fesler</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1915-11-16/1934-09-20" type="inclusive">16 Nov 1915-20 Sep 1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_02dd667e814a1dd71ca01c8126c7c5a8" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00062" level="file"><did><unittitle>Theodore and Margaret Rose</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1915-11-16/1915-12-10" type="inclusive">16 Nov-10 Dec 1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_e70c899e22957aa80a566a5360fd2a86" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00063" level="file"><did><unittitle>General correspondence A-Z</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1905-04-27/1934-04-05" type="inclusive">27 Apr 1905-5 Apr 1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_5586fa32f0ac19b0cd591ead8f28407e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00064" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA1623-00065" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings (copies) about donations to IU (used for Gift Book)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1934-04-09/1935-01-27" type="inclusive">9 Apr 1934 – 27 Jan 1935</unitdate><container id="aspace_b07abca7c862386100fbff76a2e9887e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA1623-00066" level="series"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1929/1938" type="inclusive">1929-1938</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA1623-00067" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings about Ivy Chamness and <title render="italic">Alumni Magazine</title> and the <title render="italic">Alumni Quarterly</title></unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1929-01-09/1938-07-24" type="inclusive">9 Jan 1929 - 24 Jul 1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_5deab463e8e120c4dd1f8f21c1866cad" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
