<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA2724</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>History and Political Science Club and the Logan Esarey Graduate History Club records, <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1902/1958" era="ce">1902-1958</date> <num>C106</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to their records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Kristen R. Sanders</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date> 2003</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:55:24 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>August 18, 2006</date><item>Folder list updated. DMK</item></change><change><date>May 15, 2003</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>May 15, 2003</date><item>Encoding for finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>November 3, 2003</date><item>Doc Type Declaration revised.</item></change><change><date>May 4, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>History and Political Science Club (Indiana University) records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">History and Political Science Club (Indiana University).</corpname>
    </origination>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Logan Esarey Graduate History Club (Indiana University).</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C106</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1958" type="inclusive">1902-1958</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_82d16dce558fd343c1696f17d5a7a240">The original Indiana University History Club was chartered in 1902 with various name changes and grouping changes in the years leading up to 1958. The intent of the clubs was to promote historical research, method of historical study and teaching interests. This collection includes constitutions, meeting minutes and officer books of the Indiana University History Club, the Graduate History Club, and the Logan Esarey Graduate History Club. The collection includes records of two distinct organizations due to the fact that the records were bound together in a series of journal style notebooks.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_245c565a076affaead5aa31dbcdc3544">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_1f7cfb2c7de8ecc9c4062a6603c3fc8a">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e1312720f78bd847c71e2f80895a1322">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The History Club was started during the Fall Semester 1902 at Indiana University. This organization was conceived of with the purpose to promote historical research, method of historical study and teaching, and to cultivate mutual interest in historical study. At one point the club was the largest departmental organization on the Bloomington campus. The organizational structure of the History Club was as follows: a President, a Vice President, and a Secretary-Treasurer. An Executive Committee with the club's Vice President as Chairman and two other members appointed by the President were responsible for preparing the club's programs and notifying members of their duties. At first, membership was restricted to undergraduates majoring in history with a minimum of 30 credit hours completed in their major. Membership was also open to professors in the History department as well as other individuals with special historical interests. On February 23, 1911, the club's constitution was amended to allow membership for graduate students as well as undergraduates having completed only 20 credit hours in the history major. </p><p> The History Club met every 2 weeks at faculty homes, university buildings, or other Bloomington locations. At the meetings members presented papers and were called upon to lead discussions. Aside from serious scholarly discourse, the club also enjoyed social activities including a mysterious game they often played at their monthly meetings called "Woodburn's Delight." The club sponsored many scholarly and social activities beyond their meetings, such as the celebration of Benjamin Franklin's 200th birthday on January 21, 1906. </p><p> In 1918, the club was renamed the History and Political Science Club, and a new constitution was written in 1922-1923. The History and Political Science Club was very similar to the History Club with the exception that membership was open to faculty, seniors, and graduate students in the Political Science department. </p><p> Since the History and Political Science Club was mainly an undergraduate organization, the Graduate History Club was formed on October 6, 1938. Membership in this scholarly club was open to graduate students pursuing history degrees as well as faculty. Due to the minimal organization of the club, the only offices created were those of President and Secretary-Treasurer; Mr. Henrickson being elected as the club's first President and Miss Bay elected to the position of Secretary-Treasurer. </p><p> One of the first committees appointed by the President of the Graduate History Club was the Program Committee which was comprised of 3 members who were responsible for considering the topics suggested for the group to discuss relating to history and current issues. Later committees appointed by the President were the News-Letter committee, Ways and Means Banquet Committee, and the Nominating Committee. The News-Letter committee resulted from the club's desire to continue contact with Indiana graduates now working in history related fields. </p><p> In the early years of the Graduate History Club, meetings were held on a monthly schedule most of which took place at the homes of faculty and later on university property, sometimes in connection with the meetings of the undergraduate History and Political Science Club. During these meetings the club entertained presentations of topics by faculty and other scholarly researchers as well as presented their own papers and criticisms of published works. </p><p> On October 29, 1942, after the death of I.U. professor Logan Esarey, the Graduate History Club officially adopted and continued their scholarly pursuits as the "Logan Esarey History Club" in tribute of the first man to earn a Ph.D. in History from I.U.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_fb601ae937b74d0ea5c0718c25c740b1">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is organized into two series: Administrative files and Secretary-Treasurer books.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_b0382747c1144c78c667fd427102e5b1">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection contains information on three Indiana University organizations: The History Club, which became the History and Political Science Club, and The Logan Esarey Graduate History Club which first assembled under the name the "Graduate History Club". The earliest records start in 1902 regarding the beginning of the History Club and end with the General file in 1958. The records of these two clubs are all contained together due to the fact that they are bound in a series of journal style notebooks.</p><p> The collection is organized into two series. The Administrative files series includes general information on the History Club, constitutions, and minutes. The second series is entitled Secretary-Treasurer books and consists of the Secretary-Treasurer books of the History and Political Science Club.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_8c1a4a89beb5e403477b6de82c6eeec4">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accessions 7195 and 94/039.</p><p> Deposited by Jim Madison, Indiana University History Department, Ballantine Hall 835.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_01ff6516929bc73fda76cc82c42e2848">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>For information regarding the copyright status of this collection, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a1320f37c15252371e00df1a3ec0e948">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], History and Political Science Club (Indiana University) records, Collection C106, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_062f9d0b41574a24480628408949a221">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Christopher S. Eaton.</p><p> Completed in <date calendar="gregorian" normal="2003" era="ce">2003.</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">History --Societies, etc. --History --20th century --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">History --Study and teaching (Higher) --Indiana --Bloomington --History --20th century --Sources.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History Club (Indiana University) --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History Club (Indiana University) --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History Club (Indiana University) --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History and Political Science Club (Indiana University) --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History and Political Science Club (Indiana University) --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History and Political Science Club (Indiana University) --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Graduate History Club (Indiana University) --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Graduate History Club (Indiana University) --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Graduate History Club (Indiana University) --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Logan Esarey Graduate History Club (Indiana University) --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Logan Esarey Graduate History Club (Indiana University) --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Logan Esarey Graduate History Club (Indiana University) --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="ingest">Indiana University --Students --Intellectual life --20th century.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Students --Social life and customs --20th century.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Faculty --Intellectual life --20th century.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Faculty --Social life and customs --20th century.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History Club (Indiana University)</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">History and Political Science Club (Indiana University)</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Graduate History Club (Indiana University)</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Logan Esarey Graduate History Club (Indiana University)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAA2724-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1958" type="inclusive">1902-1958</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2724-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>History Club, General</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938/1958" type="inclusive">1938-1958</unitdate><container id="aspace_d357b9bc25a6430334e175645aee0f5c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2724-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>History and Political Science Club, Constitution</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b81df1370419425256fde48a62b9d44" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2724-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting minutes and proceedings</unittitle><container id="aspace_239308e1cdaf11faa6a858dfa8e36675" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAA2724-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle>History Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1902/1912" type="inclusive">1902-1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_8c7b487d028a7522a664d91b33a72069" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2724-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle>History and Political Science Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1918/1920" type="inclusive">1918-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_3750da907ff08f3130cabae5bbf21bcd" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAA2724-00007" level="file"><did><unittitle>History Club, Graduate, Logan Esarey Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1938/1954" type="inclusive">1938-1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_20c094e0a874388d975a30bce97feae7" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAA2724-00008" level="series"><did><unittitle>Secretary-Treasurer books</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1920/1943" type="inclusive">1920-1943</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2724-00009" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1920/1929" type="inclusive">1920-1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_c4c5b8df9cd326a9272c33025f5550c5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2724-00010" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1931/1943" type="inclusive">1931-1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_ade960ce1cd39fcadfa01af694661a9f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
