<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAC1061</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana University Student Religious Cabinet records, <date normal="1938/1951">1938-1951</date> <num>C430</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Shannon K. Larson.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date> 2010</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2010"> 2010</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:48:18 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>April 27, 2011</date><item>Finding aid created.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana University Student Religious Cabinet records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Student Religious Cabinet.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C430</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.6 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1938/1951" type="inclusive">1938-1951</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1940/1948" type="bulk">1940-1948</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_a675ecc124ff72bb44effb9bf708863c">The Student Religious Cabinet existed as a student group at Indiana University from 1938 to at least 1951. The Student Religious Cabinet's purpose was to promote interest in religion, bring about fellowship among students of diverse religious affiliations, and sponsor activities meant to counteract religious and racial tensions. The collection contains meeting notes and attendance records from 1938 to 1951 and publications including <title render="italic">The Voice of Religion on Indiana University Campus</title>, <title render="italic">Communique</title>, pamphlets from a <title render="italic">War-Time Victory for Brotherhood</title> program held from 1943 until 1945, and the <title render="italic">Campus Home Front </title>, another student publication concerned with the war effort, published in 1943.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_ee465ac844f33e638e89a224d75e33c5">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_974ce36525b0c346d8ec48c35e3978d6">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_ce3a74999b4da45c41c6a12cd41c951e">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The Student Religious Cabinet of Indiana University was a student organization founded in October of 1938 in order to promote interest in religion and fellowship among students of diverse religious affiliations. The group's establishment came about as a result of President Herman B Wells' decision to found the University Committee on Religion in December of 1937. The committee consisted of faculty members, community religious leaders and students from four major religious groups: Catholicism, Christian Science, Judaism and Protestantism. Frank O. Beck, the original Executive Secretary for this committee was an active organizer and participant in the Student Religious Cabinet, which was comprised of representatives from all of the religious student organizations on campus. The purpose of the Student Religious Cabinet echoed that of the University Committee on Religion. Both groups wanted to support and bring about unification and collaboration between all religious denominations represented on the Indiana University campus.</p><p> During the group's existence between 1938 and 1951, the Student Religious Cabinet sponsored a variety of activities with the purpose of dispelling not only religious, but also racial tensions. Sponsored activities included but were not limited to religious conferences and seminars, Sunday morning breakfasts, chapel colloquies, peace rallies and efforts to support military troops during World War II.</p><p> In addition to sponsoring a variety of activities, the Student Religious Cabinet also published a weekly publication called <title render="italic">The Voice of Religion on Indiana University Campus</title>. This publication consisted mainly of event announcements and a daily schedule of activities sponsored by the group. The Student Religious Cabinet also began publishing <title render="italic">The Campus Home Front</title> and <title render="italic">Communique</title> when the United States became involved with World War II. These publications focused on building morale on campus and suggesting ways for students to get involved with wartime activities.</p><p> During the war years, the S. R. C. centered most of its activities and meetings around the war effort. For example, the group became involved with <emph render="italic">A War-time Victory for Brotherhood Program</emph>, assisted the Army and the Navy by compiling directories of religious organizations, and also organized registration for military trainees who wished to become involved in a religious organization during their training. </p><p> There are no records on the Student Religious Cabinet after 1951.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_321aca73f7c8df814a75ab9503241cde">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged in a single series, Administrative files.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d90d271fab7e5ca0318ae55933baf0af">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The records of the Indiana University Student Religious Cabinet consist primarily of meeting notes and publications for the group from 1938 to 1951. </p><p> Drafts of the meeting minutes exist from 1938 to 1950. Many of these notes were formatted as reports to the University Committee on Religion. Minutes from the very first meeting, which took place on October 2, 1938 are included. Some interesting topics discussed by the group during these years included what attitude the Cabinet should have toward cheating on exams, how to better include African American students in the organization, as well as how to bolster morale during the United States' involvement in World War II. A few of the many activities sponsored by the group included tea in the Union for the international students on campus, a refugee student fund, a race relations conference, and the organization of a religious program for military trainees during the summer of 1942. Another interesting event that is mentioned in a meeting note from 1942 was in regards to a Dr. Hill who spoke at a Convocation and Colloquy hosted by the Cabinet. According to one member of the Cabinet, he was the first African American man to ever address a large gathering at an Indiana University event. </p><p> A bound set of minutes covers 1940 to 1948. While the attendance sheets only span October 1941 through the summer of 1943, around forty students are listed on each roster. One topic of interest among these minutes include whether or not Japanese-American students should be admitted to the university in the fall semester of 1942. Herman B Wells was reportedly concerned with their safety, if allowed to enroll. Also of interest is the inclusion of a pamphlet listing the war time activities of the University Committee on Religion and the Student Religious Cabinet, which was created at the request of the Indiana University War History Project. Twenty-two activities are listed in this pamphlet. From writing letters to mothers of IU students who had joined the war to conducting classes on the topics of <emph render="doublequote">The Issues of War and Peace,</emph> the Cabinet was actively involved in attempting to inspire morale among university students during the war. </p><p> Other materials of note include Student Religious Cabinet publications and programs. <title render="underline">The Voice of Religion on Indiana University Campus</title> spans from September 1941 to January 1947 and includes two basic sections: a list of upcoming events and a weekly schedule of colloquies, church services, prayer groups, etc. Additionally, other publications such as <title render="underline">The Campus Home Front</title> and <title render="underline">Communique</title> centered around the war effort seeking to build morale among students and announce opportunities for students to take part in study groups, workshops and events. Noteworthy programs represented in the collection include <emph render="italic">A War-time Victory for Brotherhood</emph> which consisted of events over a month-long period <emph render="doublequote">aimed to promote understanding</emph> of the war and its effects. These lectures, colloquies, films and prayer meetings are categorized as being either <emph render="doublequote">inter-racial,</emph> <emph render="doublequote">inter-national,</emph> or <emph render="doublequote">inter-religious.</emph></p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_530c53bafdbd00afd6c4345f1237b594">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>See also the Frank O. and Daisy Beck papers, <archref xlink:href="http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/findingaids/archives/InU-Ar-VAC0980">Collection C168</archref>.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_14aeb931965f843038ecd6ddf8470963">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession Information: 0886</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_55eb061aa004533d6a617f62918027a4">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c1efb93e7338e29b6bcf4ebd403cf687">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana University Student Religious Cabinet records, Collection C430, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <custodhist id="aspace_51f1e5301b4c2242f1cb959832aa258c">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>These records were pulled from the Frank O. and Daisy Beck Papers collection (C168).</p>  </custodhist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_49a2eff4db7af4bca6f969bfb1ac0626">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Shannon K. Larson.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2011">2011</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">College students --Religious life --Indiana --Bloomington.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Universities and colleges --Religion.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Voice of religion on Indiana University campus.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Campus front.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Student Religious Cabinet --Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Student Religious Cabinet --Periodicals.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Student Religious Cabinet --History --Sources.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Student Religious Cabinet --Records and correspondence.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University --Religion.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAC1061-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1938/1951" type="inclusive">1938-1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_a7dea039eb6789bb5814efefdac315bd" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="underline">The Campus Front</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_1cff023a57f32bba8b967845e30e029c">No. 1-6</physdesc><container id="aspace_a0965adc6a2982d1f25215ae56c41d48" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="underline">Communique: Stressing Wartime Activities of Religious Groups</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1943" type="inclusive">1943</unitdate><physdesc id="aspace_f5dc41388249a2cf6774db14b1bdc10c">No. 1, 3</physdesc><container id="aspace_3ef57756a516bfcdd5b32915984fc4cb" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00041" level="file"><did><unittitle>Constitution</unittitle><unitdate normal="1949/1949" type="inclusive">1949</unitdate><container id="aspace_79f70bddb251381dd212f3e2a6e600f4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Enlist for Peace</emph> program</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1945" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_68d73f84a564e26c06ad428ac9806ad0" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00005" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Meeting Notes</unittitle><container id="aspace_5c07e3291f181606d50ef4f94b62842f" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00006" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle>Drafts</unittitle><container id="aspace_3cfd312c289c9f3c9f4666e19a8e0239" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC1061-00007" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1938/1940" type="inclusive">1938-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_5ba9ab09458907624f40a75ce34f82ee" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC1061-00008" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c258db4b8b982140a979c2f1bbe2b12" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC1061-00009" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">1943-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_600440ca511fa050d9be17c8c10f4343" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC1061-00010" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1945/1947" type="inclusive">1945-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_bfafca31284aecee3c2061950f89646b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC1061-00011" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1948/1951" type="inclusive">1948-1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf6ff3beb76bab58143e890c8102ca13" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00012" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bound Minute Book</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1948" type="inclusive">1940-1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b78c22940eae2ae463fb50dc6b21240" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00013" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">Off-the Campus Conference</emph> programs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1944" type="inclusive">1943-1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_33c29fd808e872a697bc40225ce9745d" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00014" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="underline">A Plan for World Peace</title> 1942</unittitle><container id="aspace_732f740176cd0844d438419623aff6c6" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00015" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="underline">Religion at Indiana University</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1947" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa6aace9caf9dd2280da156ebd006e1e" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00016" level="file"><did><unittitle>Religious Colloquy flyers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1947" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9f3ca272b5a211e92057bc0f1e548dc" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00017" level="file"><did><unittitle>Report of the World Future Study Group</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1945" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6953ee71312a1c917c9ed75408ef3b4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00018" level="file"><did><unittitle>Statements, after</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_706945f9ed31e842ea462719d041cd77" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00019" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="underline">Ten Times Tolerance</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_4feaeb2c7c848a4919a0a347e41053c5" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00020" level="otherlevel"><did><unittitle><title render="underline">The Voice of Religion on Indiana University Campus</title>, Student Religious Cabinet and Univ. Committee on Religion</unittitle><container id="aspace_f27439c79259ab71c6b24793592477cb" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00021" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. I no. 1, 13-15</unittitle><unitdate normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_acef6948b810a0b9be275d4f109e35a0" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00022" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. II no. 1-13</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1940" type="inclusive">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_0bb725edcb849204d2f148f5a622ed4f" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00023" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. III no. 1-14</unittitle><unitdate normal="1940/1941" type="inclusive">1940-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d407087e912a9980d14dc69e20cc8c4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00024" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. IV no. 1-16</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1941" type="inclusive">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_845ce74259f2edb144d31036649a8681" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00025" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. V no. 1-17</unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_3486baf106392d5a00d021bbecd093eb" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00026" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. VI no. 1-2, 4-14</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1942" type="inclusive">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0afc3d542e97902bf299f5c71dba44c" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00027" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. VII no. 1-3</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1942" type="inclusive">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a6a3f26df2a62cb3919cb92176b7ac4" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00028" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. VIII no. 1-2, 4-13</unittitle><unitdate normal="1942/1942" type="inclusive">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b8fc6cfd809b93d741a511e17918814" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00029" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. IX no. 1, 3, 5-7, 12-16</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1943" type="inclusive">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a7a93f515cab3f3e9acf4125c6de5ce" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00030" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. X no. 1-3, 6-10</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1943" type="inclusive">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e1197f514605eb574f111f8c374eb2f" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00031" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. XI no. 1-7, 9-12</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1943" type="inclusive">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_a590f0a58efcd44b65df91344ccbc054" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00032" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. XII no. 1-10, 12-13</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1944" type="inclusive">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_099d866d688f725b04df1250fea995ef" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00033" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. XIII no. 1-3, 6-13</unittitle><unitdate normal="1944/1944" type="inclusive">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_b295a381861831aea2e66ee56e898328" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00034" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. XIV no. 1-13</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1945" type="inclusive">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_77ef4aa64318bd8058748944c81f7fad" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00035" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. XV no. 1-9, 11-14</unittitle><unitdate normal="1945/1945" type="inclusive">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c3fa92d7ee0fdf7cec531bce1986b31" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00036" level="file"><did><unittitle>XVI no. 1-16</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1946" type="inclusive">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_7869cf0bc15a9cfde5fb44ece4e372fa" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00037" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. XVII no. 1-6, 8-13</unittitle><unitdate normal="1946/1947" type="inclusive">1946-1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b41fc67ac04984cdfad27f1327326c6" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC1061-00038" level="file"><did><unittitle>Vol. XVIII no. 2-11</unittitle><unitdate normal="1947/1947" type="inclusive">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_febadb293738a147a05efce3a488cc28" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00039" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="underline">War-time Activities</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1941/1946" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_99bf1cd42903d7e5607d13590bad291b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC1061-00040" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="italic">War-time Victory for Brotherhood</emph> programs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1943/1945" type="inclusive">1943-1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_e5eef6fe593ae5061a9cd20ec79ef6c6" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
