<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA2763</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>German assignment papers, <date normal="1947/1951">1947-1951</date><date type="bulk" normal="1947/1948">1947-1948</date> <num>C230</num></titleproper><subtitle>A guide to the collection at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Elia Van Lith</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date> 2017</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2018"> 2018</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:03:53 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>May 01, 2018</date><item>Original xml file lost (not on network drive or in Xubmit). Re-encoded by MRM.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>German assignment papers</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Wells, Herman B</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C230</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.8 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1947/1951" type="inclusive">1947-1951</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9f82f2a4040331bb908b8f445c8d0a7b"><emph render="bold">This collection has been incorporated into the Herman B Wells papers, Collection C75. Please visit the <extref xlink:href="http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/findingaids/archives/InU-Ar-VAB8162">C75 finding aid</extref>, "German Assignment" series to review and request access to these materials.</emph>Herman B Wells was an Indiana University alumnus, president, and chancellor. Late in 1947, in the midst of his presidency, Wells took a six month leave of absence to serve as Director of the Education and Cultural Relations Division of the Office of Military Government for German, U.S. (OMGUS). During this time he also served as General Lucius D. Clay's cultural affairs advisor. The collection includes correspondence, writings and reports, a diary, and subject files but consists primarily of correspondence with Indiana University, fellow OMGUS personnel, and individuals seeking help immigrating or locating displaced persons.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a29175e27af37a086b3e0387629241d2">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_560e20a3beb922cfd0e25da0b2537451">
    <head>Access to this Collection</head>
<p>This collection has been incorporated into the Herman B Wells papers, Collection C75. Please visit the C75 finding aid for a full inventory of these materials.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0991d42ed24033b33c3f201a2f4ef9ab">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>In early 1947, Indiana University President Herman B Wells was approached by a representative of the Unites States Military Government in Germany (OMGUS) to head the new Education and Cultural Affairs Division of the Occupation in Germany as well as serve as General Clay's cultural affairs advisor. At the time Indiana University was in the midst of coping with post-war problems, such as a yearly increase in the influx of students, and neither the Board of Trustees nor the Governor of Indiana were favorably disposed to Wells taking the year-long leave requested by the Government. In the end, the prestige of the post, both for Wells and the University, and Wells' suitability to the mission convinced the trustees and the governor to grant him a six month leave of absence.</p><p> President Wells arrived in Berlin on November 21, 1947 to a city still in ruins. He immediately began questioning the existing staff about the problems that needed to be solved. From that questioning, and the wishes of General Clay, four primary challenges and objectives emerged: 1. To assemble cultural activities in a single division under a unified policy and administration; 2. To create an agency in the U.S. to serve as a liaison between the American people and the Education and Cultural Relations Division (ECRD); 3. To stimulate military-government divisions to enter reorientation work; and 4. To recruit qualified personnel for the ECRD in Germany and in stateside organizations.</p><p> During his six month stay, Wells worked closely with both German and American education experts to restructure the German education system along more democratic lines while respecting German traditions. Here, as with everything he did, Wells used his abilities as a communicator to facilitate communication between the Americans and the Germans, and the educators and the military. Among Wells' many accomplishments during his six months in Germany were the rapid improvement and expansion of the exchange program and the establishment of the Free University of Berlin.</p>  </bioghist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_25ac8125918a04795e1f31e598856141">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>This collection was originally processed by Elia Van Lith in <date normal="2003">2003</date>. In <date normal="2009">2009</date>, the collection was transfered to the Herman B Wells papers, Collection C75, as the "German Assignment" series.</p>  </processinfo>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
