<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAD4397</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Effa Funk Muhse papers, <date normal="1895/1915">1895-1915</date> <num>C593</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to her Papers at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Amanda Ferrara</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2015</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2015">© 2015</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rightsreserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 05:09:47 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Effa Funk Muhse papers</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Muhse, Effa Funk, 1877-1968.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C593</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.2 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 small dc; 1 oversized</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1895/1915" type="inclusive">1895-1915</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1904/1915" type="bulk">1904-1915</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_8980fc3ba3d0f92622a60d55683cc697">Effa Funk Muhse was Indiana University's first woman to earn a Ph.D. at Indiana University, bestowed upon her in 1908 (Zoology). Prominent scientists Carl Eigenmann and Charles Zeleny advised Muhse's doctoral dissertation, "The Cutaneous Glands of the Common Toad," which was published in the American Journal of Anatomy in 1909. After obtaining her Ph.D., Muhse entered the lecture circuit speaking on topics from the Mendelian laws of heredity to rural sanitation to eugenics, before settling in Washington, D.C. Muhse's laboratory notes and drawings are included in this collection, as well as copies of the papers she published and laboratory slides.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_02533bbf49cd0361a877ddd49bc0f12b">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_8bd1241e4d8f1545b0b9250f6d225845">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_9c0bd4c7f4166682d451f79e485d8c53">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p><persname>Effa Funk</persname> was born on <date normal="1877-06-19">June 19, 1877</date> in <geogname>Blachleyville, Ohio</geogname>. She moved with her family and parents, Laban and Eliza (Bair) Funk, to <geogname>Hebron, Indiana</geogname> where she graduated from Hebron High School in <date normal="1894">1894.</date> She attended the <corpname>Northern Indiana Normal College</corpname> (now Valparaiso University) until <date normal="1896">1896</date> when she began teaching in the public schools of Indiana. On <date normal="1899-08-12">August 12, 1899,</date> Funk married <persname>Albert Charles Muhse,</persname> and soon thereafter enrolled at <corpname>Indiana University</corpname> in <date normal="1900-09">September 1900.</date> </p><p> During the summer of <date normal="1902">1902</date> she was named a fellow at the IU Biological Field Station on Winona Lake in <geogname>Warsaw, IN</geogname>. There she taught embryology, histology and histogenesis. She went on to receive all of her degrees in zoology from IU, receiving her A.B. in <date normal="1903">1903;</date> A.M. in <date normal="1906">1906;</date> and Ph.D. in <date normal="1908">1908.</date> </p><p> Conferral of Muhse's <date normal="1908">1908</date> zoology degree gave her the distinction of being the first woman at IU to receive a Ph.D. The title of her dissertation was <title render="underline">The Cutaneous Glands of the Common Toad,</title> published in the <date normal="1909-05">May 1909</date> issue of the <title render="italic">American Journal of Anatomy.</title> Muhse's dissertation refuted others research that said common toads had several different types of glands. She showed that the glands were all of the same type – just in different stages of development. She began her research on this paper at <corpname>Cornell University</corpname> where her husband had been given a fellowship. She returned to IU during the <date normal="1907/1908" type="inclusive">1907-1908</date> school year to accept a fellowship and to teach while finishing her dissertation under the direction and advisement of Professors <persname>Carl Eigenmann</persname> and <persname>Charles Zeleny.</persname> </p><p> After obtaining her Ph.D., Muhse was interested in teaching, but found it difficult to find a position that accepted married women. Instead, she worked the lecture circuit, giving her attention "…more especially to questions of public health and to general biological questions." She decided to settle in Washington, D.C., and gave public lectures at clubs near her home, around the country, and as far as China. Hoping to return to the state of Indiana to teach, Muhse contacted IU President <persname>William Lowe Bryan</persname> in <date normal="1911-10">October 1911</date> with a list of topics to which she could speak. Lectures offered for <date normal="1912">1912</date> included "Heredity and Problems in Eugenics," "Insects as Agents in Plant Fertilization," "Non-contagious Diseases: Deafness, Adenoids and Nervous Troubles," "The Food of Schoolchildren," and "The School as a Center of Sanitary and Health Work in the Community." During these years she became a pioneer lecturer on the Mendelian Laws of Heredity, on rural sanitation, and eugenics.</p><p> While in <geogname>Washington, D.C.,</geogname> Muhse became involved in women's suffrage, becoming a member of the <corpname>National Woman's Party</corpname> (NWP), founded by <persname>Alice Paul</persname>. In <date normal="1917">1917,</date> Muhse was sent to Idaho, Pennsylvania and Chicago to help organize the NWP. In 1963, she gave an interview to the <title>Indiana Alumni Magazine</title> in which she said she still urged "…women to 'continue the struggle for equal rights.' She believed that the greatest change in the role of the woman…came with the right to vote. At the same time, she felt that rearing families is still the most important work of today's women, putting 'minor office jobs' a poor second."</p><p> Between <date normal="1921">1921</date> and <date normal="1917">1927,</date> Muhse began teaching at several institutions, two of which were the <corpname>National Park Seminary</corpname> and the <corpname>Colonial School for Girls.</corpname> In the fall of <date normal="1927">1927,</date> she became the head of the Biology Department at <corpname>Chevy Chase Junior College</corpname> in <geogname>Washington, D.C.</geogname> and continued to teach there for 21 years, substantially increasing the enrollment of young women in biology classes, as well as throughout the field.</p><p> During her lifetime she was a member of the <corpname>Eugenics Education Society of London</corpname>; <corpname> American Association for the Advancement of Science</corpname>; <corpname>Phi Beta Kappa</corpname>; <corpname>Sigma Xi</corpname>; <corpname>the National Woman's Party</corpname>; and the T<corpname>wentieth Century Club of Washington, D.C.</corpname> Her favorite hobbies were drafting house plans and carpentry. Muhse died on <date normal="1968-02-27">February 27, 1968.</date></p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_33221ef536ffcf53ed454bcd090e7f60">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized into two series, Writings and Slides</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_bc499c69298ca85f742dc2bcacb74be4">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Effa Funk Muhse papers, (1904-1915, undated), consists of two series: Writings (1904-1915, undated) and Slides, (1895-1904, undated). The Writings series includes copies of Muhse's publications, laboratory notes, various drawings as well as a reprint of her dissertation. The Slides series consists numerous laboratory slides. Many of these glass slides were created by Muhse and bear her signature and/or initials; others have labels from places such as Mount Holyoke College (MA), or bear the name of the specimen.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_1c9457a406c512dfee011ba44d530c9c">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Related photographs may be available in the <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">University Archives Photographs Database</extref>.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_5144ac588158c19239f5ed0b2105c45e">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession: 9167</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0dc04ca9d72054ad67edbf65f0e04dea">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_1af3b407ba95a1d2f0f74143f36ce5b6">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Effa Funk Muhse papers, Collection C593, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <custodhist id="aspace_90c8d3790b5c0420d5af16eb68e35fca">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Transferred by Mr. and Mrs. Don. R. Cummins of Columbus, Indiana.</p>  </custodhist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_870f2faaf5c6b23ddf33131ea6fad694">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Amanda Ferrara.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2015">2015</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Zoology--Study and teaching (Higher)--Indiana--Bloomington--History--Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Zoologists--Indiana--Bloomington--History--Sources.</subject>
    <persname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Muhse, Effa Funk, 1877-1968--Archives.</persname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University--Students--History--20th century--Sources.</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD4397-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Writings</unittitle><unitdate normal="1904/1915" type="inclusive">1904-1915</unitdate><unitdate normal="1895/1915" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3f337654f4c905841ccbf4ba3f770003" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_VAD4397-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>Biology Laboratory Notes and Drawings: Zoology</unittitle><unitdate normal="1895/1915" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca0a78fa34ccaed8147f491091da6298" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD4397-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>Drawings of Cells</unittitle><unitdate normal="1895/1915" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_3208505a43ac4374398d6a2e8216ae3c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD4397-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Muhse, Effa Funk</unittitle><container id="aspace_73292fe90be3528da6a3092bd1cfd67b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAD4397-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Cutaneous Glands of the Common Toads</title> Reprint from <title render="underline">The American Journal of Anatomy</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1909/1909">1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ba5c390a1f892b3c06f851e09c8f4dd" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAD4397-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Eyes of Blind Vertebrates of North America</title> Reprint from <title render="underline">Biological Bulletin</title>c. 1</unittitle><unitdate normal="1903/1903">1903</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ee0be969c101ee39d9c6851dc60b9b1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAD4397-00007" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">The Eyes of Blind Vertebrates of North America</title> Reprint from <title render="underline">Biological Bulletin</title>c. 2</unittitle><unitdate normal="1903/1903">1903</unitdate><container id="aspace_5466cca3ed32c782e993f38666ea1b0f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAD4397-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Heredity and Problems in Eugenics</title> Reprint from <title render="underline">The Women's Medical Journal</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1912/1912">1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_38306a0b9944637aee1faf4b984f4c35" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAD4397-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Heredity and Problems in Eugenics</title> Reprint from <title render="underline">The Women's Medical Journal</title></unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1915">1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_8fe8eb4466d789f4d12bb367da9f48b3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAD4397-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="doublequote">Photographs and Data of Sectioned and Stained Material of American Toads</title> Cornell University</unittitle><unitdate normal="1904/1904">1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_ddf2b179d730a8c462d40f8f41771cb9" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD4397-00011" level="series"><did><unittitle>Slides</unittitle><unitdate normal="1895/1904" type="inclusive">1895-1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4cb8e214d19b1665d0dcf44b7e39dd5" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
