<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAD4345</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana University Folklore Institute Hungarian-American Project records, <date normal="1915/1987">1915-1987</date> <num>C585</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Chad Edward Buterbaugh</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2015</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.libraries.iub.edu/archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2015">© 2015</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-02-04 04:49:02 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana University Folklore Institute Hungarian-American Project records</unittitle>
    <origination audience="internal" label="Creator">
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Institute.</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C585</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">6 boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">1915-1987</unitdate>
    <unitdate normal="1982/1984" type="bulk">1982-1984</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b5c605c6355c5bf7d613f83c762dc116">The Hungarian-American project was an international undertaking of the Indiana University Folklore Institute between 1981 and 1984. Headed by IU folklorists Linda Dégh and Inta Carpenter, scholars from the United States and Hungary conducted ethnographic fieldwork to identify the uses of ethnicity among Hungarians in Hungary, Hungarian-Americans in the Calumet region of Indiana, and Hungarian-Americans in Chicago. The project led to the conference "Culture, Tradition, Ethnicity," hosted at Indiana University from March 26-28, 1984 and inspired a 1987 conference in Budapest. A special double issue of the <title render="italic">Journal of Folklore Research</title> printed many materials from the conference and was published later the same year. Collection consists of records relating to project personnel, fieldwork, and conferences.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_6ab61098eb920e4a220afa316b37ae9b">Most materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>; some are in <language langcode="hun">Hungarian</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_c687233843067fc12406c1cf4f88b3e3">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5491805508699befdc9bbf1b6e88fdab">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The Hungarian-American project was an international undertaking of the Indiana University Folklore Institute between <date normal="1981/1984" type="inclusive">1981 and 1984</date>. Headed by IU folklorists <persname>Linda Dégh</persname> and <persname>Inta Carpenter</persname>, scholars from the United States and Hungary conducted ethnographic fieldwork to identify the uses of ethnicity among Hungarians in Hungary, Hungarian-Americans in the Calumet region of Indiana, and Hungarian-Americans in Chicago. The project led to the conference "Culture, Tradition, Ethnicity," hosted at Indiana University from <date normal="1984-03-26/1984-03-28" type="inclusive">March 26-28, 1984</date> and inspired a <date normal="1987">1987</date> conference in Budapest. A special double issue of the <title render="italic">Journal of Folklore Research</title> printed many materials from the conference and was published later the same year.</p><p> <persname>Linda Dégh</persname> was a prominent folklorist who spent most of her professional life at the Folklore Institute. Born in Hungary, she came to Bloomington with the aid of <persname>Richard Dorson</persname>, founder of the Institute. According to her obituary on the American Folklore Society's website, her research specialty was "personal and communal identity projections of traditional rural and modern urban communities in Europe and North America. Through personal observation of creative processes in communicating folklore, traditional prose narratives in particular, taking into account historical and situational contexts of performance, she focused not on the text prototype, but on the unique, personal formulations of individuals generated by unpredictable given conditions."</p><p> Her work on the Hungarian-American project was mainly administrative. Bringing together professional contacts from both the United States and Europe, she laid the groundwork for this ambitious, multi-year project. With the help of Inta Carpenter, who at the time was the Folklore Institute's research associate, this project produced a number of notable presentations and publications. Of particular importance is the article <title>"The Seven Strands of Tradition"</title> by folklorist <persname>Dan Ben-Amos</persname>, a seminal monograph appearing in the <date normal="1984">1984</date> issue of the <title render="italic">Journal of Folklore Research</title> that grew from this project.</p><p> At issue in the project were senses of communal character among Hungarians and Hungarian-Americans. Applying the notion of ethnicity as differential identity, researchers worked with informants to uncover the everyday folkloric forms that were imported from Hungary and framed in the U.S. as specialized articulations of cultural inheritance. This activity produced rich fieldwork materials, many of which are included in this collection, as well as a series of broader discussions in the field of folklore studies, such as the publication by Ben-Amos, mentioned above, and others.</p><p> The research interest in these materials lies in the recounting of Hungarian-American ethnic identity in the latter decades of the twentieth century, especially as this is articulated by members of that group. A number of ethnographic ephemera, including church yearbooks and pamphlets, are very useful in this regard. These materials recount the successes and trials of Hungarian-Americans--often pertaining to their social life, as it was framed by shared religious practice--in their own words. Some of these materials, such as the death of a beloved minister, communal concerns about the dwindling importance of ethnic heritage among generations descended from immigrants, or the efforts of a church group to beautify its worship space--are less likely to be found in broader historical surveys. Yet they add to (or perhaps center) such broader works by providing clear articulations of the memories, activities, and aspirations of the small group.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_34a2d3b1b046720d6cd53a6fce3ee07d">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is organized into four series: Project personnel, Project proposal and correspondence, Conferences and publications, and Fieldwork materials.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_26f793016c22e7628dba7ca980aac54d">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection is organized into four series: Project personnel, Project proposal and correspondence, Conferences and publications, and Fieldwork materials. A number of the materials in this collection pre-date the research period. These are publications collected by ethnographers during the research phase of the project.</p><p> Arranged alphabetically by surname, the Project personnel files span <date normal="1980/1986" type="inclusive">1980-1986</date> and document the scholars who worked on the Hungarian-American project. The Project proposal and correspondence files, spanning <date normal="1980/1986" type="inclusive">1980-1986</date>, trace the scholars' efforts in crafting an ultimately-successful proposal to undertake the research. Research design, budgets, workflows, and the proposal itself detail this process. These files are arranged to reflect the process of proposal formation, from brainstorming to final submission. The Conferences and publications series, <date normal="1982/1987" type="inclusive">1982-1987</date>, include programs, budgets, and a number of conference papers and abstracts. They also contain consent to publish forms for the issue of the <title render="italic">Journal of Folklore Research</title> that resulted from the conference. These are arranged to reflect conference and publication planning processes. The Fieldwork materials files, which were published between <date normal="1915/1984" type="inclusive">1915 and 1984</date> but most likely all collected during the period of fieldwork for this project--roughly <date normal="1982/1984" type="inclusive">1982-1984</date>--contain some of the data collected by the ethnographers. This includes approximately 703 annotated photos pasted to index cards, film negatives logs of visual and audio materials, biographical notes on informants, and a variety of print ephemera produced by Hungarian-American groups. These files are arranged in alphabetical order by first letter of the folder title. Most files are in English; some are in Hungarian.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_8c60c1badf78ff467c6220b438e7b0f5">
    <head>Photographs Pulled</head>
<p>Approximately 703 fieldwork photos pasted on index cards and annotated with contextual information and photographer's name; 17 strips of film negatives encased in three 8.5" x 11" plastic sheets (folder "Film negatives"); all located in Box 6</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_e76c36fe529a6a0a2942674c09599e9d">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the <extref xlink:href="http://institutionalmemory.iu.edu/aim/">Archives of Institutional Memory</extref>.</p><p> Related photographs may be available in the <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">University Archives Photographs Database</extref>.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_48fcb42e9318bc275b07d2eaa59d3a4c">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession 2003/055, 2010/065</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_966fac7ec288002e45a2519dc1d29564">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_89abee277b09ec5fceadb5b3da94f3b3">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana University Folklore Institute Hungarian-American Project records, Collection C585, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <custodhist id="aspace_e44a45a396f1c80b5bf983d4f84732a9">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Transferred from the Indiana University Folklore Institute, May 8, 2003 and July 12, 2010.</p>  </custodhist>
  <appraisal id="aspace_29e746d6a16dc0222ede8fba1e7e801d">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>A number files have been recycled. These were either duplicate materials, listed travel arrangements, or described minor expenses incurred during the project. They did not include any information about the methods, content, or results of the research project.</p>  </appraisal>
  <processinfo id="aspace_a30d70544dc9e781a2c0eaf7e514dc12">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Chad Edward Buterbaugh.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2015">2015</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Ethnicity--Study and teaching (Higher)--Indiana--Bloomington--History--Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hungarian Americans--Ethnic identity.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hungarian--Ethnic identity.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hungarian Americans--Indiana--History--20th century--Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hungarian Americans--Illinois--Chicago--History--20th century--Sources.</subject>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Institute--Archives.</corpname>
    <corpname audience="internal" source="lcnaf">Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Institute--Resords and Correspondence..</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_5a444d497594b14bc8cafa01f49a3819" level="series"><did><unittitle>Project personnel</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1987" type="inclusive">1980-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_24080a4aa1adf1248dad6637fdc7bfd2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_43ee0340458dd5178719643dadf9b904" level="file"><did><unittitle>Erdely, Steven</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1986" type="inclusive">1983-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_58ac3ab8919cd31755431ca3bd7d11f8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_69b76fa9f60a0d93c1a7c1d0b0304600" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fejos, Zoltan</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1987" type="inclusive">1984-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_dc1cfc0fca025985a155d391ae67f101" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_07f318e39a83536d99faf866d26d28c4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hoppal, Mihaly</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_d8bd42c07b4accd513a2496de4699b62" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fd934a256aba58ec3b65a880b483e6ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>Huseby, Eva</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1985" type="inclusive">1983-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_a488b7a9b6d87d8623fadd9cc2019e9d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cb7202f4b46be82437ada4b8161a48c1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Niedermuller, Peter</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1986" type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_b547bb02ee0010e5b8131728d84cf071" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_213ecb5a470797fc169e2d52740677ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sozan, Michael</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1986" type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_faf71960e131356fc3751ac2a95d7af0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ede4690c557b76144d7a8f0410351a25" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fieldworkers' vita, etc.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1982" type="inclusive">1980-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_d7d609113cb14ae0d4404cfe827235c5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_40c74d6a51a089d12427276da45c2cd2" level="series"><did><unittitle>Project proposal and correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1983" type="inclusive">1981-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_49f2f6da6595e5ccbf8c7ee41792600f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_15bf03d4813b001599cc230e3c2009dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference - 1981</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3f703774bb20eedbbe242c3f7b845c8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c1e9f25c02697b47176928d411d0bea6" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hungary Trip ('81)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_f78f33c9bfb6623ddd55337f06b2c64a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f0010055c8f5a95f65bb23fcd6ae4bad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ethnographic Museum</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_0d5efbc574c71faf59d9343e1d3c27b8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8a48a74ff1e0ff64242eced6951e6d87" level="file"><did><unittitle>Skaggs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_3688c97ed031e3707360c3cd08013d3e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c62ba658ab2db19ed904fd6d8d2303f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Project rewrite</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1983" type="inclusive">1981-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_77dc7d12f7ad4f1422550a565b90eb65" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dd2f898526271b20b1c8f1d9fa21c9fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal</unittitle><container id="aspace_edaa08941e555792cd549729209c9bcc" label="box" type="box">2</container></did><c03 id="aspace_61375cba87d59944859e74e94e9e67fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>Workplans</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1986" type="inclusive">1982-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e63796821c28618ab8eaaa5062d1809" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_f31832f9b1ed3a5f2988029f41c6741a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rough drafts</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1986" type="inclusive">1980-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_a0f621f46e0479c5568b755b5591dd5c" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_76c6c1e92a4d18e7a709ce3be25f2707" level="file"><did><unittitle>Final draft - 6/4/82</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7ac9c452a817a69a3c98f86e71a23e3" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_95f1f96b5d28de0d16db45e3199233d2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hungarian-American proposal notes</unittitle><unitdate normal="1980/1982" type="inclusive">1980-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_746346dd56b0c48210c80267c5a4ccd0" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d6604196206d6cbfdeab047246ef7923" level="file"><did><unittitle>Meeting</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984-05-21/1984-05-21">May 21, 1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_f390c328280095ed5d1a8f307fe0a2a0" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c478c104eb7ca416886a50f6b288d0ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>NEH proposal</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f1a8753e6392e00caef290919f10753" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_522746e8843c6027709fcd97fc63da7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal correspondence</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1983" type="inclusive">1981-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e3e5724d0a4d7a12c08ed5cf383678a" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2b3eb3a0b5518d0bd6f206760199970b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hungarian-American revision - Feb. 1, 1983</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1983" type="inclusive">1981-1983</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3d555c1d4b703543bdc64eb5e53f83e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4c71d2b59289db2ab9721c9f153e08c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Protocol</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_271313bf428e6ef2989537561c6a6876" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0106bf1ce52d657cb4c49ddcd88f5b87" level="file"><did><unittitle>Project agreement copies</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_93d28752b1117121d4b95a956537dd6d" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e7830a09d289cb5e792aed99a646eeec" level="file"><did><unittitle>Misc. papers</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1986" type="inclusive">1981-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_c93d699e0c93d2f6fef1bce7c21279e0" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fd71fb3ecb5190f6cd0a1644fd5613f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Round Robin</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1985" type="inclusive">1984-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0d889e95ddf63f5844ae55d3cbab721" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d4aa817376f905f0d496eb82ef42ec23" level="file"><did><unittitle>Progress reports 5.21.84</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_3a4c5e4c3bbd556f9b8b07ba434ea9fd" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6ccf0d0db3850d8a825b2ebd3e9f10fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal for Continuation</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_a496c31ee63f87536c2c077fb2c3d3c8" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0f0b7e260d743820fb509f0e8f2c3f17" level="file"><did><unittitle>1983 Commission Meeting at Princeton</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f776750e4b35a95b6fffb6ba392b9b3" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5d0ac106cf794e58dcdf99083b4d6565" level="file"><did><unittitle>American Conference of Learned Societies/Hungarian Academy of Sciences Meeting - Princeton, NJ</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_77b4e8322c04934803b13a18fd4520c3" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_eb4588ca0a02ce0a2ffffbae57c8e16d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Related articles</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_77971cd33d1851462df25e2b6762eb01" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2543464aa58d489ab03372f95c064671" level="file"><did><unittitle>Proposal - Degh - "Kakasd Revisited"</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb1a7efebee72fc00de243a1f1b0c8e4" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7cb70f81b3fb458a5bf01757e18ce454" level="file"><did><unittitle>Hungary paper/trip</unittitle><unitdate normal="1981/1983" type="inclusive">1981-1983</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_dff6774b3dcf415fb7a47dd441de253c" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_13384c3237e1274cbea8bf9a05810fa3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Institute for Culture (Budapest) Newsletter</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8d5b7616c2159724c73f830e15c6e1d" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_08317b7c48763f129ddf8dd8ff1b8f68" level="series"><did><unittitle>Conferences and publications</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1987" type="inclusive">1983-1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_45ee3794d1964adba79f2dac52cde115" label="box" type="box">3</container></did><c02 id="aspace_9e73885a29be205d086a2ac0bd238315" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference participants, 3/25 - 3/28</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_409fa29e9883780612eea6cae82e2c7d" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e8309dac2447416df3219d6dab08c166" level="file"><did><unittitle>Conference Bureau Banquet Lists</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_8644498e542ce7f51bd4c9c4e1f30d81" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_82e8892a94924a71576ccedf786ef84f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Luncheons, 3/26, 3/27</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f76fc90bd4cdef15a0ad71ca9cf2e04" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_589d950dc4859cfc24f675b15fc1ac4a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tomas Hofer</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1986" type="inclusive">1984-1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_75ad5382f9ab57dc35db6dc49923ebab" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a151909cf715f1c39c3758ada1727ae3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Carol Silverman</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae1056612cd1216ccdaaaf8cd5453dfb" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_38f8f1c7d486ee46be3e315f79ddf88a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Mihaly Sarkony</unittitle><unitdate normal="1983/1984" type="inclusive">1983-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_a607fa6e68080682b3577a6ce663ed07" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e48706347f867d5f1182243d5f81d7f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>Domotor</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1332b977a9eaf2dc55d79085c8be345" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d166b99e9c5f025ae3649b561bc71a27" level="file"><did><unittitle>Voight (PAP)</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_80e69cdcdbbfe209b3c82a869633d0ef" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8f5c3557b0a6f3e82bba7c5e16933daf" level="file"><did><unittitle>Tape Transcript of Conference</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe2aaed4d4926b60b6b5e8a369bbeb97" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c867e15a0943cc5bf36a7a0ba4464c2c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Richard Vidutis - photo logs, slide logs</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1dbcb1aebc386febe5a1c706baa9e0f" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_82e4ed71d597f8242491e6b124aed63a" level="file"><did><unittitle>JFR, consent to publish forms</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1985" type="inclusive">1982-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0c6ddcd6fd406b36d73ad7d54a478ce" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_819a258988e73eba157263abc533cf53" level="file"><did><unittitle>Budapest conference 1987</unittitle><unitdate normal="1986/1987" type="inclusive">1986-1987</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_298a17782961a9947fa76cabc0ba28e5" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_677f56ee15b5cf4b85e302ff2d6efce6" level="series"><did><unittitle>Fieldwork materials</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1984" type="inclusive">1915-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7c3b75d7ba375d0a65e807c67f5fbe6" label="box" type="box">3</container></did><c02 id="aspace_ff751fb2db4b3b0a1d371d2951abc427" level="file"><did><unittitle>Autobiography Of Jozsef Plajer, S. Bend, IN</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_95974900bf8a6b1b0dcdffb56223f9e1" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c8955ad1cb1e61dfc59ff6e638734204" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chicago Church Anniv. Bks.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1934/1982" type="inclusive">1934-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_bb1e355612d28b2491a2f744373ad72f" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_41469a8c141dccad39c2da31e94d6b3c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Dr. Magyar Jozsef - A Chicagoi Szent Istvan Templam Elefebol</unittitle><unitdate normal="1930/1982" type="inclusive">1930-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_5317326878eaca2936448898f5b7114d" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_da28e2e1ee288207e0f7fe77ab658d1b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fieldworkers' inventory</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_9635566ec7f6e22745f9964b1ab7623c" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_aec03671cce17b8827ebbf33e15094a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Film negatives</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_d475d9b0d0b9ad79e45ca6425ca313b5" label="box" type="box">4</container></did><odd id="aspace_aa51b3e7e0ecfd89c6011beeaeb3f552"><head>General</head><p><emph render="bold">(Housed in Box 6)</emph></p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_33de18f750a3b825988444fee9434412" level="file"><did><unittitle>ITT-OTT (Here and There; Hungarian Communion of Friends)</unittitle><container id="aspace_4578c8ab72bd96b10301fcc59685761d" label="box" type="box">4</container></did><c03 id="aspace_2671b72c456e626ecbea05553987c996" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1967/1973" type="inclusive">1967-1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_f797cfb3db724e6097ecd9ae36fc2a9b" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_e6a68e689a5628ab43e651f96196c5d3" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1967/1977" type="inclusive">1967-1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d458d9b9c2bf171642f2f06572497a3" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_85106b859491ba43a80fa9ada18ad15f" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1978/1979" type="inclusive">1978-1979</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_e054b068a3b0bf108e213353c1e5f881" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_a62732cb7fc933935d2418a9262073e5" level="file"><did><unitdate normal="1982/1983" type="inclusive">1982-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_b91862302ddb74548b3a0ad59ed084f9" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_e938ed1d3de488d9653d6084d3a2332a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Misc. files</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_cc47debfbfcf812e1d5ca3a3adace5e9" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_53bf67b7321ab9996779b92b35ede186" level="file"><did><unittitle>More church, anniversary publications</unittitle><unitdate normal="1968/1982" type="inclusive">1968-1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5de7de399004e755db605bc16f4d988" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_209329949d6d9142de00961ea344f971" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photo logs - Z Fejos; slide logs - Zoltan Fejos</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_fc73353649cb881c70a4fb411a400186" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9f61dc2e99bc22181fba651376550631" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rerfy Geya, uj Magyar Ferfikarak Zsebkonyve</unittitle><unitdate normal="1915/1915">1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_617d6497dd57eccba2924f8ffd971b06" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dc200e26a18fa6a15631cd00a11be792" level="file"><did><unittitle>South Bend - Ethnic Heritage Studies Program</unittitle><unitdate normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><unitdate normal="1915/1987" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_ded4390ddc87095edcf30137b1d6b2bf" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9b70d2df13afcfb7328d49acacb145a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>William Penn Association, other anniv. bks.</unittitle><unitdate normal="1961/1984" type="inclusive">1961-1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_d7bd3f3c0a856a82319fc32b2ddf8d3b" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ab6d3a108c579a32276df8612f5d7c64" level="file"><did><unittitle>Zoltan Fejos</unittitle><container id="aspace_6d806715026ff111f90abf9782efe828" label="box" type="box">5</container></did><c03 id="aspace_42230b73cedcdfdb5cd4e535676978ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>cassette log + ATL Sheets</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_f61dc29ce30a8931b741938ffae4bb95" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1c70c22c5a4bbf24291ac15e67a81643" level="file"><did><unittitle>key contributor sheets</unittitle><unitdate normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_05f0dc644e8a4827a1842b4579f065aa" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_9651d6a424ae9c543cb7c54f359b898e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs - Folklore Institute Special Projects '84 Hungarian-American Project</unittitle><container id="aspace_fc752c7ddb90ce3bff6162324becf9a7" label="box" type="box">6</container></did><c03 id="aspace_a7885c1e41978fc0e8bceb9f80e42071" level="file"><did><unittitle>SPHA-84-006</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1983" type="inclusive">1982-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ea9a5b0a1466ab3b99b20417f4a508c" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_b9b3e5e88fda2577a5feb906647859f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>SPHA-84-007</unittitle><unitdate normal="1982/1983" type="inclusive">1982-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_93b2c0148aa26ec49b8d35bb4f0a056c" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c03></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
